[
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "N E X T\nL E V E L\nM O",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "I T Y\nBMW GROUP REPORT 2022\nOn the path to electric and digitalised mobility in a sustainable circular economy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW GROUP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Report on the economic performance of the BMW Group and its environmental\nand social contribution.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "↗ Link to the online report\n2 BMW Group Report 2022",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Other Information\nB M W G R O U P R E P O R T 2 0 2 2\nThe BMW Group firmly asserted itself in a highly volatile environment in the 2022 reporting year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022 reporting year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The continued strong performance figures show\nthat we are on track in the transformation – despite the many challenges.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Flexibility and resilience are the foundation of our business.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The ramp-up of\nelectromobility is gaining momentum.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We just recently proved our digital expertise with the presentation of the BMW i Vision Dee.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "And the goal of a\ncircular economy in the BMW Group is taking shape.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "As a technology platform, the NEUE KLASSE will deepen these focus areas and set new standards\nfor electromobility, digitalisation and sustainability.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NEUE",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "You can find more information in the following report.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "KEY PERFORMANCE INDICATORS\nGROUP PROFIT/LOSS EBIT MARGIN IN THE AUTOMOTIVE EBIT MARGIN IN THE MOTORCYCLES RoE IN THE FINANCIAL SERVICES\nBEFORE TAX in € million SEGMENT in % SEGMENT in % SEGMENT in %\n23,509 8.6 8.1 17.9\nSignificant increase over previous year 🡩",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "million",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "23,509",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "17.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "previous year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Within the corridor of 8 to 10 % Within the corridor of 8 to 10 %",
    "entities": [
      [
        "8 to 10 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "8 to 10 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Within the corridor of 17 to 20 %\nGROUP DELIVERIES IN THE AUTOMOTIVE DELIVERIES IN THE MOTORCYCLES SHARE OF ELECTRIFIED VEHICLES\nWORKFORCE at year-end SEGMENT in units SEGMENT in units IN DELIVERIES in %\n149,475 2,399,632 202,895 18.1\nSignificant increase over previous year 🡩 Slight decrease from previous year 🡮",
    "entities": [
      [
        "17 to 20 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "year-end",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "149,475",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,399,632",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "previous year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "🡩 Slight",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "previous year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Slight increase over previous year 🡭 Significant increase over previous year 🡩",
    "entities": [
      [
        "previous year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "🡭",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "previous year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "🡩",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This is a simplified presentation of the data.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Detailed information on the performance figures LINK TO CHAPTER\nas well as the identification of the depth of the audit can be found in the respective chapters.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "BMW Group in Figures\n3 BMW Group Report 2022",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Other Information\nT H E B M W G R O U P ’ S ST R AT E G",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ST",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "A LS\nFINANCIAL GOALS\nGroup EBT margin EBIT margin in the Return on capital employed\nAutomotive segment of Automotive segment\n> 10 % 8 – 10 % ≥ 18 %\nTARGETS FOR THE PERIOD UP TO 2025\nShare of electrified cars Share of women\nin total deliveries in management positions\n> 30 % 22 %\n🡩 🡩\nTARGETS FOR THE PERIOD UP TO 2030\nShare of all-electric vehicles in Reduction in carbon emissions Reduction in carbon emissions Reduction in carbon emissions\ntotal deliveries per vehicle in production during a vehicle’s use phase in the supply chain\n> 50 % 80 % > 50 % > 20 %\n🡩 🡫 🡫 🡫\nThis is a simplified presentation of the data.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EBT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "10 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "10 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "18 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "THE PERIOD UP TO 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "30 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "22 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "🡩 🡩",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "THE PERIOD UP TO",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "50 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "80 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "50 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "20 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "🡩",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Detailed information on the performance figures LINK TO CHAPTER\nas well as the identification of the depth of the audit can be found in the respective chapters.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "BMW Group Integrated Strategy\n4 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\nContents\n2 — COMBINED MANAGEMENT REPORT 3 — GROUP FINANCIAL STATEMENTS\n5 About This Report* 37 Overview of the BMW Group 153 Income Statement for Group and Segments\n41 BMW Group Integrated Strategy 154 Statement of Comprehensive Income for Group\n51 Financial Performance 155 Balance Sheet for Group and Segments at 31 December 2022\n1 — TO OUR STAKEHOLDERS 79",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW Group Integrated Strategy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "41",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "51",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "155",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "31",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "79",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "EU Taxonomy 157 Cash Flow Statement for Group and Segments\n90 Products 159 Statement of Changes in Equity for Group\n9 BMW Group in Figures\n103 Production and Supplier Network 161 Notes to the Group Financial Statements\n12 Report of the Supervisory Board\n114 Employees and Society\n20 Statement of the Chairman of the Board of Management\n123 Outlook\n26",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "157",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "90",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "103",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "114",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Society\n20 Statement",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management\n123 Outlook",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "26",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management\n6 — OTHER INFORMATION\n127 Appropriateness and Effectiveness of the Internal\n27 Composition of the Board of Management and\nControl System and Risk Management System\nSupervisory Board 311 Further GRI Information\n128 Risks and Opportunities\n31 Dialogue with Stakeholders 322 SASB Index\n143 Compliance and Human Rights\n34 BMW Group and Capital Markets 325 TCFD Index\n147 Internal Control System\n329 NFS Index\n148 Disclosures Relevant for Takeovers and Explanatory Comments\n330 Consumption and Carbon Disclosures\n333 BMW Group Ten-year Comparison\n4 — RESPONSIBILITY STATEMENT AND\n335 Glossary and Explanation of Key Figures*\nAUDITOR’S REPORT 5 — REMUNERATION REPORT\n341 Financial Calendar\n247 Responsibility Statement by the Company’s 260 Remuneration Report 342 Contacts\nLegal Representatives\n260 Review of the Past Financial Year from a Remuneration\n248 Independent Auditor’s Report P erspective\n*",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "127",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "27",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Control System and Risk Management System\nSupervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "311",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "128",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "31",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "322",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "143",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "34",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Capital Markets",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "325",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "TCFD",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "147",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Internal Control System",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "329",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "NFS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "148",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "330",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "333",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Ten-year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "335",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "AUDITOR",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "341",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "247",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Responsibility Statement",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Company",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "260",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "342",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "260",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Past Financial Year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "248",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Part of the Combined Management Report\n256 Independent Practitioner’s Report 262 Remuneration of the Members of the Board of Management\n300 Remuneration of the Members of the Supervisory Board\n304",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Combined Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "256",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "262",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "300",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "304",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Comparison of Change in Remuneration and Earnings pursuant\nto § 162 (1) Sentence 2 No. 2 of the German Stock Corporation\nAct (AktG)\n308 Other Considerations\nC O N T E N T S\n308 Outlook for the 2023 Financial Year\n309 A uditor’s Report\n5 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\nAbout This Report\nA B",
    "entities": [
      [
        "162",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the German Stock Corporation\nAct",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "308",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "308",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "309",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "This Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "I S R E P O R T *\nREPORTING CONCEPT The report is divided into the following sections: FRAMEWORKS APPLIED\n1 —",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To Our Stakeholders\nIntegrated reporting and corporate strategy 2 — Combined Management Report The BMW Group Report is based on the following reporting and\nThe BMW Group regards its balance of economic, ecological and 3 — Group Financial Statements accounting standards.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "social interests as the basis for its commercial success.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This 4 — Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report\nreport is intended to provide qualified insight into the BMW Group 5 — Remuneration Report Combined Management Report\nand explain our activities in a transparent, comprehensible and 6 — Other Information The Combined Management Report is based on the following\nmeasurable manner.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are keen to demonstrate to our stake- legal frameworks:\nholders how economic, ecological and social issues complement\none another and are often mutually dependent, and to identify Changes in reporting and outlook for reporting — German Commercial Code (HGB) (among other relevant\nthe general external conditions that influence the Company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "German Commercial Code",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "requirements legislation)",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "For these reasons, we explain ↗ the BMW Group’s integrated strategy In light of recent and prospective changes in non-financial dis-\nas well as the latest developments and the way in which the closure requirements, in particular the standards of the ISSB and — Content of the Management Report in accordance with\nbusiness is managed on the basis of key financial and non- CSRD at the EU level, the pace of change within the reporting §§ 289 and 315 HGB\nfinancial targets.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "315",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "↗ Dashboard environment will continue to gather momentum and increase the\nextent to which non-financial and financial disclosures need to — Combined Non-Financial Statement (NFS) at Group and\nOn 7 March 2023, the Financial Statements of BMW AG were be presented on an integrated basis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ Dashboard",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Combined Non-Financial Statement",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NFS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "7 March 2023",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "BMW AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The BMW Group is prepar- Company level in accordance with § 289 b and § 315 b\nprepared and the Group Financial Statements were approved for ing itself for these new trends by continually developing its Inter- HGB (↗ NFS Index)\npublication by the Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "315",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Inter- HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NFS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The BMW Group Report nal Control System to ensure that select non-financial performance\n(hereinafter also “the Report”) combines the management indicators are monitored to the same degree as financial perfor- — German Accounting Standards (GAS 20) underpinning\nr eports of Bayerische Motoren Werke Aktiengesellschaft mance indicators.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Control System",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "German Accounting Standards",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "20",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Bayerische Motoren Werke Aktiengesellschaft",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "With this BMW Group Report, we also fulfil the HGB requirements\n(BMW AG) and the BMW Group in a Combined Management disclosure requirements set out by the ↗ E U Taxonomy.\nReport.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "this BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Combined Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the ↗ E U Taxonomy",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "↗ GRI Index: 2-4 — German Stock Corporation Act (AktG)\n— Taxonomy Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2020 /852 of the\nEuropean Council and of the European Parliament on the\nEstablishment of a Framework to Facilitate Sustainable\nInvestment, and amending Regulation (EU) 2019 /2088)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ GRI",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Taxonomy Regulation (Regulation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the\nEuropean Council",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the European Parliament",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "* Part of the Combined Management Report\n6 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\nAbout This Report\nThe Combined Management Report is also based on: ADDITIONAL INFORMATION are not part of the audit.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Combined Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "This Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "The Combined Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The ↗ Remuneration Report 2022 was pre-\npared in accordance with the requirements of § 162 of the German\n— Guidelines on Alternative Performance Measures issued by ON THE REPORT Stock Corporation Act (AktG) and its content audited by PwC.\nthe European Securities and Markets Authority (ESMA)\nPwC has audited the Group Financial Statements and the Com-\n—",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The ↗ Remuneration Report 2022",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "162",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Guidelines on Alternative Performance Measures",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ON THE REPORT Stock Corporation Act",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the European Securities and Markets Authority",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "PwC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "German Corporate Governance Code (GCGC) Publication and scope bined Management Report for the year under report and issued\nThe BMW Group Report is published annually to coincide with an unqualified audit opinion thereupon.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "The BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "annually",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Further information is\nFurthermore, the Combined Management Report makes reference the BMW Group Annual Conference – most recently held on provided in the ↗ Independent Auditor’s Report and the ↗ Independent\nto the following reporting standards and transparency 15 March 2022 – and is subsequently available in both German Practitioner’s Report on Non-financial Disclosures.\nrequirements: and English on the BMW Group website.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Combined Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the ↗ Independent Auditor’s Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the ↗ Independent",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "15 March 2022",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "English",
        "LANGUAGE"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The ↗ GRI Index is also\navailable on the website as a separate document.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The ↗ GRI Index",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The reporting The contents of the NFS, in accordance with § 289 b and § 315 b\n— GRI Standards 2021 of the Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) period covers the financial year from 1 January to 31 December HGB, were subjected to an audit to obtain limited assurance and\n(↗ GRI Index) 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NFS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "315",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the financial year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1 January to 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "December",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The statements made in the report relate to the BMW Group are denoted with the symbol ... .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The section ↗ Dialogue with\nreporting entity.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ Dialogue",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Any deviations are marked accordingly.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Stakeholders and the additional information provided in the section\n— SASB Standards according to the Sustainable Accounting structure of the BMW Group changed significantly on 11 February ↗ Further GRI Information were also subjected to a limited assurance\nStandards Board (↗ SASB Index) 2022 due to the BMW Group’s increased stake in the former joint engagement.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainable Accounting",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "GRI Information",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Standards Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Certain individual parts of the ↗ NFS as well as the\nventure BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd. (BMW Brilliance) and remainder of the Combined Management Report were subjected\n— Recommendations of the Task Force on Climate-related Fi- its subsequent inclusion in the BMW Group reporting entity.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the ↗ NFS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Combined Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Task Force",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "to a reasonable assurance engagement.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Information provided in\nnancial Disclosures (TCFD) (↗ TCFD Index) Further information on the first-time consolidation is available the ↗ SASB Index is subjected to a limited assurance review on a\nin ↗n ote 3 to the Group Financial Statements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ TCFD Index",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "↗n ote 3",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The BMW Group voluntary basis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The ↗ TCFD Index indicates the sections in which\n— UN Global Compact Progress Report: see references in GRI Report 2023 will be published on 20 March 2024.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "UN Global Compact Progress Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "20 March 2024",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "the depth of the audit is identified.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "requirements (↗ GRI Index) ↗ GRI Index: 2-2, 2-3, 2-4\nGroup Financial Statements External audit\nThe Group Financial Statements of",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2-2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2-3",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Bayerische Motoren Werke The entire report of BMW AG, comprising the Combined Man-\nAktiengesellschaft for the year ended 31 December 2022 have agement Report, the Group Financial Statements and the further\nbeen prepared in accordance with International Financial GRI Information, is subjected to an annual independent audit by\nReporting Standards (IFRS) as endorsed by the European Union PricewaterhouseCoopers GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft\n(EU) and the supplementary requirements of § 315 e HGB.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Bayerische Motoren Werke",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Aktiengesellschaft",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the year ended 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "International Financial GRI Information",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Reporting Standards (IFRS",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "the European Union PricewaterhouseCoopers GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "315",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "(“PwC” or “Auditor”).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "PwC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Auditor",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Unaudited sections are marked according-\nly.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The external audit serves to underpin the reliability and trust-\nworthiness of the information contained therein for the public.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The external audit supports the Supervisory Board of BMW AG\nin fulfilling its auditing duties.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board of",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Any links and disclosures that refer\nto information outside the BMW Group Report and the GRI Index\n7 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\nAbout This Report\nMateriality analysis Sustainable Development Goals The BMW Group Report uses the simplified term “carbon” or\nThe BMW Group carried out a materiality analysis in 2022 in ac-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "This Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "The BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "With its business operations, the BMW Group is in a position to the abbreviation CO2 instead of CO2e; see the glossary under\ncordance with § 289 c and § 315 c HGB.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This three-step process contribute directly to the achievement of Sustainable Develop-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainable Develop-",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "↗ CO2e/CO2 equivalents.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Summarised disclosures of fuel consump-\ninvolved the preparation of a long list of topics that are internally ment Goals (SDGs), in particular ↗ SDG 3, 8, 9, 12 and 13.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ SDG 3,",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "9",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Icons will tion, carbon emissions and electricity consumption are provided\nand externally relevant for the BMW Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Icons",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "These topics were be used at the start of each section to provide a visual reference in the section ↗ Consumption and Carbon Disclosures.\nthen prioritised in consultation with external stakeholders and in to these SDGs.\nconsideration of competition analyses and rating requirements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ Consumption and Carbon Disclosures",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The topics that were ultimately categorised as material were Forward-looking statements\nthose where the actions of the BMW Group may have a significant This report contains various forward-looking statements con-\nsustainability impact on the environment and society (inside-out) cerning future developments that are based on the current status\nand which may be of high business relevance to the BMW Group of the BMW Group’s assumptions and forecasts.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "These state-\n(outside-in).",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The findings were subsequently validated in an in- ments are therefore subject to a variety of predictable and un-\nternal management workshop.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "As a result, our focus is on alter- predictable risks, uncertainties and other factors, which means\nnative drive systems ↗ Electromobility, Decarbonisation along the that the actual outcome, including that of the BMW Group’s\nvalue chain ↗ Carbon emissions, responsible sourcing ↗ Purchasing net assets, financial position and results of operations, its\nand Supplier Network, resource management in line with the prin- development or performance, could differ considerably from\nciple of the ↗ circular economy as well as compliance ↗ and Compli- those statements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ Electromobility",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗ Carbon",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗ Purchasing",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supplier Network",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Compli-",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "ance and Human Rights.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Employee diversity and equal opportunity\n↗ Diversity, Equal Opportunity and Inclusion as well as an attractive Statement on Corporate Governance\nworkplace ↗ Employer Attractiveness and Employee Development are The Board of Management and the Supervisory Board of\nalso given high priority within the BMW Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ Diversity",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗ Employer Attractiveness and Employee Development",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In accordance BMW AG prepare a yearly combined Statement on Corporate\nwith the Corporate Sustainability Reporting Directive (CSRD),",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Corporate Sustainability Reporting Directive",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Governance in accordance with § 289 f and § 315 d HGB to re-\nwhich must be applied from financial year 2024, topics are port on corporate governance within the Company and the\nmaterial when they (may) have a significant sustainability impact BMW Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Statement on Corporate Governance is pub-\nor be of high business relevance.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The additional topics in this lished on BMW AG’s website at ↗ www.bmwgroup.com/ezu.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW AG’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗ www.bmwgroup.com/ezu",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It also\ncontext are responsible digitalisation ↗ Innovation, Digitalisation includes the Declaration of Compliance pursuant to § 161 AktG.\nand Customer Orientation, Product and Road Safety, ↗ Product Q uality\nand Safety, ↗ Health and Performance, and Sustainable Governance Editorial comments\n↗ Performance Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Digitalisation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Declaration of Compliance",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "§ 161 AktG.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Customer Orientation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Safety, ↗ Health and Performance",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗ Performance Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "GRI reporting refers to topics that The key figures included in the BMW Group Report have been\nare relevant pursuant to the CSRD.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "rounded in accordance with standard commercial practice.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In\nindividual cases, this may mean that figures do not add up ex-\nConnection to figures in the Group Financial Statements actly to the stated total and that percentages cannot be derived\nFor each topic, an assessment was carried out to identify figures from the values shown.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "reported in the financial statements that enable a better under-\nstanding of the NFS, and which therefore need to be disclosed\nand explained.\n8 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\n9 BMW Group in Figures\n12 Report of the Supervisory Board\n20 Statement of the Chairman of the Board of Management\n26",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NFS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "20",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "26",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management\n27 Composition of the Board of Management and Supervisory\nBoard\n31 Dialogue with Stakeholders\n34 BMW Group and Capital Markets\n1 —",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "27",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management and Supervisory\nBoard",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "31",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "34",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Capital Markets",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "O L D E R S\n9 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\nBMW Group in Figures\nB M W G R",
    "entities": [
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "I G U R E S\nKEY PERFORMANCE INDICATORS\nChange\n2018 1 2019 2020 2021 2022 in %\nGROUP\nProfit/loss before tax in € million 9,627 7,118 5,222 16,060 23,509 46.4\nEmployees at year-end 2 134,682 126,016 120,726 118,909 149,475 25.7\nShare of women in management positions in the BMW Group (in %) 3 17.2 17.2 17.8 18.8 20.2 7.4\nAUTOMOTIVE SEGMENT\nEBIT margin in % 7.2 4.9 2.7 10.3 8.6 –16.5\nRoCE in % 4 49.8 29.0 12.7 24.0 18.1 –24.6\nDeliveries 5 2,486,149 2,537,504 2,325,179 2,521,514 2,399,632 –4.8\nShare of electrified vehicles in deliveries (in %) 5.7 5.8 8.3 13.0 18.1 39.2\nCO2 emissions of the EU new vehicle fleet (in g/km) 6, 7, 8 127.5 127.0 99.1 (135.0) 9 115.9 105.0 –9.4\nCO2 emissions per vehicle produced (in tonnes) 10, 11, 12 0.40 0.40 0.35 0.33 0.32 –3.0\nMOTORCYCLES SEGMENT\nEBIT margin in % 8.1 8.2 4.5 8.3 8.1 –2.4\nRoCE in %",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2018 1 2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "million",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "7,118",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "16,060",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "46.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "year-end",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "126,016",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "25.7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "17.2 17.2",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "16.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "24.6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,537,504 2,325,179",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "4.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5.7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "18.1 39.2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "7",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "8 127.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "99.1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "135.0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "9.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "12 0.40 0.40 0.35 0.33 0.32",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "3.0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "13 28.4 29.4 15.0 21.9 24.9 13.7\nDeliveries to customers 165,566 175,162 169,272 194,261 202,895 4.4\nFINANCIAL SERVICES SEGMENT\nRoE in % 14.8 15.0 11.2 22.6 17.9 –20.8\n1 The figures for 2018 were adjusted due to the change in accounting policy in conjunction with the adoption of IFRS 16 (↗ Annual Report 2019,",
    "entities": [
      [
        "29.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "24.9 13.7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "165,566",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "169,272",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "194,261",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "202,895",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "RoE",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "14.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "20.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "IFRS 16 (",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Note [6] to the Group Financial Statements).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The term “employee” has been redefined with effect from the reporting year 2020 (for definition, see ↗ Glossary).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the reporting year 2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "↗ Glossary",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The figure for 2019 was restated accordingly for comparison purposes (2019 before adjustment: 133,778 employees).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "133,778",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "For the period 2018 and earlier, the share of employees that are no longer reflected in\nreporting is between 7.5 % and 8.0 %.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the period 2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "between 7.5 % and 8.0 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The new definition of the term “employee” (see footnote 1) also has an impact on disclosures relating to the percentage of female employees.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The 2019 figure was adjusted accordingly for comparison purposes (2019 before adjustment: 17.5 %).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2019",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "17.5 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "4 The term “RoCE” has been redefined with effect from the reporting year 2022 (for definition, see ↗ Glossary).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the reporting year 2022",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "↗ Glossary",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The 2021 figure was adjusted accordingly for comparison purposes (2021 before adjustment: 59.9 %).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "59.9 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "5 Deliveries including BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd., also for the period prior to full consolidation in the Group Financial Statements of the BMW Group (2018: 455,581 units, 2019: 538,612 units, 2020: 602,247 units, 2021: 651,236 units, 1 January to 10 February 2022: 96,133 units).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "455,581",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "538,612",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "602,247",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "651,236",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1 January to 10",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "96,133",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "6 EU-27 countries including Norway and Iceland; with effect from 2021, values are calculated on a converted basis in line with WLTP (Worldwide Harmonised Light Vehicles Test Procedure).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6 EU-27",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Norway",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Iceland",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "WLTP",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Values for 2018 to 2020 were calculated based on the New European Driving Cycle (NEDC).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the New European Driving Cycle",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NEDC",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This is a preliminary internal calculation with a potential variation of +/– 0.5 g CO2/km, as official registration figures from the authorities are not available for all EU states.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "0.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Figures officially published by the EU Commission are not expected to be available until November of the following year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the EU Commission",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "November of the following year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "8 Including an allowance for eco-innovations (amounts of clearly minor significance).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "9 To improve comparability, the 2020 NEDC figures were converted to WLTP after adjusting for permissible flexibilities – specifically from 99 g CO2/km according to NEDC (including 5 g CO2/km phase-in, 7.5 g CO2/km supercredits and 2.4 g CO2/km eco-innovations) to 135 g CO2/km according to WLTP (excluding flexibilities).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "NEDC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "WLTP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "99",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "NEDC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "135",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "WLTP",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In 2020, a phase-in regulation was accepted, as was the recognition of supercredits, which ceased in 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "10 Efficiency ratio calculated on the basis of Scope 1 and Scope 2 carbon emissions (i.e. a market-based method according to GHG Protocol Scope 2 guidance; mainly based on the use of emissions factors for electricity, district heating and fuels of the VDA (each in the most current valid version: 12/2022) and occasionally\nusing local emissions factors; excluding climate-changing gases other than carbon dioxide from vehicle production (BMW Group manufacturing sites including the BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd. joint venture and Motorrad, but excluding partner plants and contract manufacturers), as well as BMW Group\nnon-manufacturing sites (e.g. research centres, sales centres, office buildings) divided by the number of vehicles produced (BMW Group manufacturing sites including the BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd. joint venture and partner plants, but excluding contract manufacturers).\n11 From 2019, this indicator includes the carbon emissions of all other BMW Group locations in addition to the carbon emissions generated by production.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Scope 1",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "GHG Protocol Scope 2",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "VDA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "12/2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Motorrad",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The figure for 2018 cannot be compared directly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "12 The 2018 figure was audited on the basis of a limited assurance engagement.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "13 The term “RoCE” has been redefined with effect from the reporting year 2022 (for definition, see ↗ Glossary).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the reporting year 2022",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "↗ Glossary",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The 2021 figure was adjusted accordingly for comparison purposes (2021 before adjustment: 35.9 %).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "35.9 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "10 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\nBMW Group in Figures\nOTHER FINANCIAL PERFORMANCE FIGURES\nChange\nin € million 2018 2019 2020 2021 2022 in %\nTotal capital expenditure 1 8,013 7,784 6,222 7,518 10,610 41.1\nDepreciation and amortisation 5,113 6,017 6,143 6,495 8,566 31.9\nFree cash flow Automotive segment 2,713 2,567 3,395 6,354 11,071 74.2\nGroup revenues 2 96,855 104,210 98,990 111,239 142,610 28.2\nAutomotive 85,846 91,682 80,853 95,476 123,602 29.5\nMotorcycles 2,173 2,368 2,284 2,748 3,176 15.6\nFinancial Services 2 27,705 29,598 30,044 32,867 35,122 6.9\nOther Entities 6 5 3 5 8 60.0\nEliminations 2 – 18,875 – 19,443 – 14,194 – 19,857 – 19,298 – 2.8\nGroup profit/loss before financial result (EBIT) 2 8,933 7,411 4,830 13,400 13,999 4.5\nAutomotive 6,182 4,499 2,162 9,870 10,635 7.8\nMotorcycles 175 194 103 227 257 13.2\nFinancial Services 2 2,172 2,312 1,721 3,701 3,163 – 14.5\nOther Entities – 27 29 36 – 8 – 203 –\nEliminations 2 431 377 808 – 390 147 –\nGroup profit/loss before tax (EBT) 2 9,627 7,118 5,222 16,060 23,509 46.4\nAutomotive 6,977",
    "entities": [
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "€ million",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "1 8,013",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6,222",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "10,610",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5,113",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "8,566",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "31.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,713",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,395",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "11,071",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "74.2\nGroup",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "104,210",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "142,610",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "28.2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "85,846",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "123,602",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,173",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,748",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "15.6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "60.0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "18,875",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "19,443",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14,194",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "19,857",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "19,298",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4,830",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "13,999",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6,182",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "10,635 7.8",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "175",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "103",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2,172",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1,721",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,701",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,163",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "27 29 36",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "203",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2 431 377 808",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "390 147",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EBT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2 9,627",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7,118",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "16,060",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "46.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6,977",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "4,467 2,722 11,805 18,918 60.3\nMotorcycles 169 187 100 228 269 18.0\nFinancial Services 2 2,143 2,272 1,725 3,753 3,205 – 14.6\nOther Entities – 45 – 96 – 235 531 995 87.4\nEliminations 2 383 288 910 – 257 122 –\nGroup income taxes 2 – 2,530 – 2,140 – 1,365 – 3,597 – 4,927 37.0\nProfit/loss from continuing operations 2 7,097 4,978 3,857 12,463 18,582 49.1\nProfit/ loss from discontinued operations – 33 44 – – – –\nGroup net profit/loss 2 7,064 5,022 3,857 12,463 18,582 49.1\nEarnings in € per share of common stock/preferred stock 2 10.60/10.62 7.47/7.49 5.73/5.75 18.77/18.79 27.31/27.33 45.5/45.5\nPre-tax return on sales 2, 3 in % 9.9 6.8 5.3 14.4 16.5 14.6\n1 Expenditure for capitalised development costs, other intangible assets and property, plant and equipment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2,722",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "11,805",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "18,918",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "60.3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "169",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "228",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,272",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,753",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14.6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "45",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "96",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "235",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "531 995 87.4",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "2 383",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "257 122",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,530",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,140",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1,365",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,597",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4,927",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "37.0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2 7,097",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "4,978",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "12,463",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "18,582",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "49.1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "33 44",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2 7,064 5,022",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "12,463",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "18,582",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "49.1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "€",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2 10.60/10.62",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "9.9 6.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14.4 16.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14.6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The figures for 2018 were adjusted due to the change in accounting policy in conjunction with the adoption of IFRS 16 (↗ Annual Report 2019, Note",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "IFRS 16 (",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "[6] to the Group Financial Statements).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "3 Group profit/loss before tax as a percentage of Group revenues.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3 Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "11 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\nBMW Group in Figures\nOTHER NON-FINANCIAL PERFORMANCE FIGURES\nChange\n2018 2019 2020 2021 2022 in %\nGROUP\nSpending on employee training and development (in € million) 1 373 370 279 389 416 6.9\nAUTOMOTIVE SEGMENT\nDeliveries by brand\nBMW 2 2,117,854 2,184,939 2,028,841 2,213,790 2,100,689 – 5.1\nMINI 364,101 347,465 292,582 302,138 292,922 – 3.1\nRolls-Royce 4,194 5,100 3,756 5,586 6,021 7.8\nTotal 2 2,486,149 2,537,504 2,325,179 2,521,514 2,399,632 – 4.8\nProduction by brand\nBMW 3 2,168,496 2,205,841 1,980,740 2,166,644 2,089,801 – 3.5\nMINI 368,685 352,729 271,121 288,713 286,265 – 0.8\nRolls-Royce 4,353 5,455 3,776 5,912 6,239 5.5\nTotal 3 2,541,534 2,564,025 2,255,637 2,461,269 2,382,305 – 3.2\nEnergy consumption per vehicle produced (in MWh) 4, 5 2.12 2.04 2.12 2.10 2.13 1.4\nMOTORCYCLES SEGMENT\nProduction\nBMW 162,687 187,116 168,104 187,500 215,932 15.2\nFINANCIAL SERVICES SEGMENT\nNew contracts with retail customers 1,908,640 2,003,782 1,845,271 1,956,514 1,545,490 – 21.0\n1 Training for BMW Group employees and temporary staff at consolidated companies worldwide.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2018 2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "GROUP\nSpending",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "million",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "1 373",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "389",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2,117,854",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,184,939",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,028,841 2,213,790",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "5.1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "364,101",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "292,582",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "292,922",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3.1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6,021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2 2,486,149",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "4.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2,166,644 2,089,801",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "0.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5,912",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6,239",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3 2,541,534",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,255,637",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3.2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "MWh",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "162,687",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "168,104",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "15.2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,003,782",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1,956,514 1,545,490",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "21.0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Data is collated on the basis of direct input by participants and, to a small extent, by extrapolation.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Data also includes e-learning formats.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "2 Deliveries including BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd. also for the period prior to full consolidation in the Group Financial Statements of the BMW Group (2018: 455,581 units, 2019: 538,612 units, 2020: 602,247 units, 2021: 651,236 units, 1 January to 10 February 2022: 96,133 units).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "455,581",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "538,612",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "602,247",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "651,236",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1 January to 10",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "96,133",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "3 Production including BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd. also for the period prior to full consolidation in the Group Financial Statements of the BMW Group (2018: 491,872 units, 2019: 536,509 units, 2020: 602,935 units, 2021: 700,777 units, 1 January to 10 February 2022: 58,507 units).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "491,872",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "536,509",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "602,935",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "700,777",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1 January to 10",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "58,507",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "4 Efficiency indicator calculated from the absolute energy consumption (adjusted for CHP losses) of automobile production (BMW Group plants including BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd., excluding partner plants and contract manufacturing) divided by the number of units produced\n(BMW Group plants including BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd. and partner plants, excluding contract manufacturing).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "CHP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The figure for 2018 has been audited with limited assurance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "12 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nR E P O R T",
    "entities": [
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "A R D\nDEAR SHAREHOLDERS,\nThe year 2022 was a challenging, but nonetheless successful one for the BMW Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The ongoing war in Ukraine is a human tragedy that moves us all deeply.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ukraine",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In economic\nterms, too, the conflict has had a massive impact, with severe repercussions for vital supply\nchains.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The general situation was also exacerbated by repeated lockdowns in China and\nnumerous bottlenecks affecting semiconductor availability.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "However, despite these adverse\ngeo political and macroeconomic circumstances, the BMW Group performed well in 2022\nwithin the competitive environment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "With around 2.4 million vehicles sold and the production\nof all-electric vehicles making good progress, the BMW Group has clearly demonstrated\nthat a strong product portfolio is the best response to a challenging environment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "around 2.4 million",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We got off to a flying start in 2023 with the unveiling of the BMW i Vision Dee at the Con-\nsumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Las Vegas",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "“Dee” stands for Digital Emotional Experience, a\nnew form of interaction between people and their cars in which genuine driving pleasure\nand the virtual world merge seamlessly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Dee",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Digital Emotional Experience",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "With this vehicle, BMW has already arrived in the\nfuture in terms of digitalisation!",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Norbert Reithofer\nChairman of the Supervisory Board",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Norbert Reithofer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board\n",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "For 2023, we intend to maintain our firm course of profitable growth and press ahead with\nthe ramping up of electric mobility.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are convinced that the future of the BMW Group is\nelectric, digital and circular – and it has already begun!",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "13 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nFocus of Supervisory Board activities during the past financial year and risk management measures on a regular basis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board\nFocus of Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the past financial year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The latest developments in the semi-\nThe Supervisory Board performed the duties incumbent upon it with the utmost diligence conductor supply situation were also discussed at each meeting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "throughout the financial year 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the financial year 2022",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The monitoring of corporate strategy also remained high on the Supervisory Board’s",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Based on in-depth reports presented by the Board of Management, in our capacity as a agenda.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management provided an in-depth account of its strategies, focus-\nsupervisory body we assiduously monitored the governance of the BMW Group and advised ing on the automotive sector’s transformation in the fields of electrification, digitalisation\nthe Board of Management on matters relating to the management and strategic develop- and the circular economy and emphasising the importance of the NEUE KLASSE as a huge\nment of the Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NEUE",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We focused in particular on the progressive electrification of the Group’s leap in terms of product features.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The latest purchasing strategies in place were also\nproduct portfolio and on implementing the corporate strategies adopted in the fields of explained to us in great depth.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Growing challenges in relation to supply chain management\ndigitalisation and sustainability.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "At each of the five plenary sessions of the Supervisory and the ongoing trend towards technology clusters were both discussed at considerable\nBoard (including two two-day meetings), we held detailed discussions with the Board length.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "two-day",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Particular attention was paid to the Catena-X platform, a cross-company network\nof Management regarding the Group’s situation, addressing a variety of topics, including designed to improve supply security and carbon emissions management throughout\nthe risks associated with the ongoing global uncertainty and risk management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Catena",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The the supply chain using standardised data exchange systems.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The overall market situation\nBoard of Management also kept the Supervisory Board well informed of any matters of as well as the outlook for automated driving were also subjects of the Board of Manage-\nsignificance outside the framework of formal meetings.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Manage-",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "I also discussed key current ment’s reports.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In conjunction with the information provided on the topic of sustainability,\nmatters personally with the Chairman of the Board of Management between meetings on the Board of Management reaffirmed the BMW Group’s ambitious decarbonisation targets\na regular basis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition to scheduled meetings, the Chairman of the Audit Committee for the year 2030.\nwas also in direct contact with the Board of Management member responsible for Finance\nas well as with the external auditor’s representatives.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the year 2030",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, we regularly dealt At each meeting, the Board of Management updated us on the current status of its strategy-\nwith personnel-related matters as well as internal Supervisory Board issues without the and project-related work as well as the progress being made in implementing its declared\npresence of the Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "strategy of environmental sustainability.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "These updates also included current events such\nas the opening of the Lydia plant in China, which is fully geared to e-mobility production,\nWithin the Supervisory Board and its committees, dialogues were always conducted in an the start of production of fuel cell systems at the BMW Group’s in-house competence centre\nopen and constructive spirit, both internally and together with members of the Board of for hydrogen in Munich, the market launch of the all-electric BMW iX1 as well as the found-\nManagement.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Lydia",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of for hydrogen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "iX1",
        "PRODUCT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Detailed documents distributed in a timely manner prior to meetings enabled ing of the “Circular Republic” initiative in collaboration with UnternehmerTUM GmbH on all\nmembers to prepare appropriately for the topics up for discussion.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the “Circular Republic",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "UnternehmerTUM GmbH",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition, separate aspects of the circular economy.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "preliminary meetings of the shareholder and employee representatives were held on a\nregular basis prior to Supervisory Board meetings.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Moreover, the Board of Management reported to us on other current topics, such as the\nhighly successful presentation of the new BMW 7 Series in Palm Springs, USA, the activi-\nIn its reports on the BMW Group’s position, the Board of Management kept us well ties surrounding the 100th anniversary of the BMW plant and the 50th anniversary of\ninformed at each meeting regarding current developments and the Group’s overall perfor- the BMW Group’s “Vierzylinder” tower in Munich, the unveiling of the Spectre, the first\nmance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Palm Springs",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "USA",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "100th",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "50th",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Vierzylinder",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Spectre",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "A regular topic of discussion was the development of current sales trends based all-electric Rolls-Royce, and the eight IQS Quality Awards received for five of our vehicle\non figures analysed by brand, segment and market region for both the BMW Group and its models as well as three of the BMW Group’s plants.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Rolls-Royce",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "eight",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "IQS Quality Awards",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "competitors, with a keen focus on electrified vehicles.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "An overview of key financial indica-\ntors and the liquidity situation of the BMW Group was also an integral part of these reports.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "On several occasions we deliberated on major changes affecting the legal framework\nIn view of the far-reaching consequences of the war in Ukraine, including the impact on and/or regulatory projects that are of significance to the BMW Group, in particular the\nbusiness in Russia and the recurrent coronavirus -related lockdowns in China, we were pro- EU’s regulations regarding fleet carbon emissions in conjunction with the EU’s “Fit for 55”\nvided with up-to-date information on current developments, risks to business performance package and the Euro 7 emissions standards.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ukraine",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Fit",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "55",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Euro 7",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "14 BMW Group Report 2022 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Responsibility Statement and Auditor’s Report Remuneration Report Other Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nFurthermore, the Supervisory Board closely monitored developments relating to major The fundamental structures of the BMW Group’s risk management system as well as the\nstrategic cooperations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board\nFurthermore",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In 2022, the focus was particularly on the Chinese market, with key elements of its risk strategy were clearly set out for us in the detailed Risk Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Risk Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In\nrespect to both the BMW Brilliance Automotive joint venture, in which the BMW Group was addition, various scenarios and risk mitigation measures were discussed regarding a range\nable to increase its share to 75 % with effect from 11 February 2022, and the cooperation of topics of current relevance for the key areas Development, Purchasing, Production and\nwith Great Wall Motors for the local production of an all-electric MINI.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Brilliance Automotive",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "75 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Development, Purchasing, Production",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Great Wall Motors",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Board of Manage- Sales.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Manage- Sales",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management also reported to us on the strategy, performance, sector-\nment updated us on the current status of these projects at each meeting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In light of the specific risk profile and current projects of the Financial Services line of business.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Key\nsale of SHARE NOW, we were also kept informed of strategic developments at YOUR",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "NOW topics relating to the Group’s financing system were also discussed at length.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "as well as the strengthening of the BMW Group’s luxury segment product range through\nthe acquisition of the ALPINA brand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "During the year under report, we reviewed the strategies pursued by Human Resources,\nincluding maintaining the attractiveness of the BMW Group as an employer.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Human Resources",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Board of\nThe development of the BMW Group’s equity and considerations undertaken by the Management also brought us up to date on the current status of the diversity concepts\nBoard of Management regarding the possible implementation of a share buyback pro- developed by the Group and the extent to which targets have been achieved regarding the\ngramme were further key items on our agenda.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of\nThe development of",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
