[
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "T H E F U T U R E I S\nE L E C T R I C ,",
    "entities": [
      [
        "F U",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A L A N D\nBMW GROUP REPORT 2021\nC",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "U L A R\nOn the way to an electric and digitalised mobility\nin a sustainable and circular economy.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Report\non the BMW Group’s economic performance and\nits ecological and social contributions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "↗ Link to the Online-Report\n2 BMW Group Report 2021",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Online-Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Other I nformation\nB M W G R O U P R E P O R T 2 0 2 1\nIn 2021, the BMW Group demonstrated how profitability and transformation can go hand in glove, des­\npite tough market conditions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Electric mobility is gathering pace, with delivery figures on a steep up­\nward trajectory.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At the same time, the BMW Group is working on digital solutions that make life more\nconvenient for customers and provide access to a broad range of services.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The BMW Group’s vision of\na circular economy is gradually taking shape, the ultimate goal being fully sustainable mobility.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Further information is provided in the following report.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "KEY PERFORMANCE INDICATORS\nPROFIT / LOSS BEFORE TAX in € million EBIT MARGIN AUTOMOTIVE SEGMENT in % EBIT MARGIN MOTORCYCLES SEGMENT in % RoE FINANCIAL SERVICES SEGMENT in %\n16,060 10.3 8.3 22.6\nSignificant increase compared to 🡩 Significant increase to prior year 🡩 Significant increase to prior year 🡩 Significant increase to prior year 🡩\nprior year\nSHARE OF ELECTRIFIED\nGROUP EMPLOYEES end of year DELIVERIES AUTOMOTIVE SEGMENT in units DELIVERIES MOTORCYCLES SEGMENT in units VEHICLES IN DELIVERIES in %\n118,909 2,521,514 194,261 13.0\nSlight decrease to prior year 🡮",
    "entities": [
      [
        "million",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "RoE FINANCIAL SERVICES SEGMENT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "16,060",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "22.6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "🡩",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "🡩",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "🡩",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "🡩",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "prior year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "GROUP EMPLOYEES end of year",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "118,909",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "13.0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Solid increase to prior year 🡭 Significant increase to prior year 🡩 Significant increase to prior year 🡩\nThe diagram provides a simplified overview.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "prior year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "🡩",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "🡩",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Detailed explanations of the KPIs as well as an indication of the scope of the audit can be found in the respective TO THE CHAPTER\nchapters of the report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "CHAPTER",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "BMW Group in figures\n3 BMW Group Report 2021",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "O F T H E B M W G R O U P\nFINANCIAL TARGETS\nEBT margin Group EBIT margin Automotive segment Return on capital employed\nAutomotive segment\n> 10% 8 – 10% ≥ 18%\nTARGET ACHIEVEMENT BY 2025\nShare of electrified cars in total Share of women in management\ndeliveries positions\n> 30% 22%\n🡩 🡩\nTARGET ACHIEVEMENT BY 2030\nShare of fully electrified cars in Reduction of CO emissions per Reduction of CO emissions in the Reduction of CO emissions in the\n2 2 2\ntotal deliveries vehicle produced use phase of the vehicle supply chain\n> 50% 80% > 50% > 20%\n🡩 🡫 🡫 🡫\nThe diagram provides a simplified overview of the key performance indicators (KPIs) disclosed in the report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EBT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "10%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "10%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "18%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "30%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "22%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Reduction of CO emissions per Reduction of CO emissions",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Reduction of CO emissions",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "50%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "80%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "50%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "20%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "🡩",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Detailed explanations of the KPIs as well as an TO THE CHAPTER\nindication of the scope of the audit can be found in the respective chapters of the report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "CHAPTER",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "BMW Group Integrated Strategy\n4 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nContents\nCO N T E N TS\n1 2 3\n2 COMBINED MANAGEMENT REPORT 3 GROUP FINANCIAL",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW Group Integrated Strategy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Contents\nCO N",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "STATEMENTS\n5 About this Report (Part of the Combined Management Report) 34 Overview of the BMW Group 149 Income Statement for Group and Segments\n38 BMW Group Integrated Strategy 150 Statement of Comprehensive Income for Group\n51 Products and Mobility Solutions 151 Balance Sheet for Group and Segments at 31 December 2021\n1 TO OUR STAKEHOLDERS\n67 Production, Purchasing and Supplier Network 153 Cash Flow Statement for Group and Segments\n9 BMW Group in Figures 80 Employees and Society 155 Statement of Changes in Equity for Group\n12 Report of the Supervisory Board 91 Financial Performance 157 Notes to the Group Financial Statements\n21 Statement of the Chairman of the Board of Management 121 EU Taxonomy\n27 The Board of Management 124 Outlook, Risk and Opportunity Management\n28",
    "entities": [
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Combined Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "34",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "38",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "51",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "151",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "31",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "67",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "80",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Society 155 Statement of Changes in",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "91",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "21",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "121",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "27",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Board of Management 124 Outlook",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Opportunity Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "28",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Dialogue with Stakeholders 143 Internal Control System\n31 BMW Group and Capital Markets 144 Disclosures Relevant for Takeovers and Explanatory Comments\n4 5 6\n4 CORPORATE GOVERNANCE 5 REMUNERATION REPORT 6 OTHER INFORMATION\n248 Fundamental Aspects of Corporate Governance 271 Remuneration Report 321 Further G RI",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Stakeholders 143 Internal Control System",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "31",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Capital Markets 144",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "248 Fundamental Aspects of Corporate",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "271",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "321",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "o f t he C ombined M anagement R eport)\n332 SASB­Index\n337 TCFD­Index\n341 NFS­Index\n258 Responsibility Statement by the Company’s Legal\n342 Consumption and Carbon Disclosures\nR epresentatives\n344 BMW Group Ten­year Comparison\n259 Independent Auditor’s Report\n346 Glossary and Explanation of Key Figures\n267 Independent Practitioner’s Report\n351 Financial Calendar\n352 Contacts\n5 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nAbout This Report\nA B",
    "entities": [
      [
        "332",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "337",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "341",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "258",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Responsibility Statement",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "342 Consumption and Carbon Disclosures",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "344",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "259",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "346",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "267",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "351",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "352",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "This Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "I S R E P O R T\n( PA R T O F T",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A G E M E N T R E P O R T )\nREPORTING CONCEPT The BMW Group is keen to demonstrate to its shareholders\nhow economic, ecological and social issues complement\none another and are often mutually dependent, and which\nIntegrated reporting and corporate strategy general external conditions influence the company and de-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In the BMW Group’s view, a key prerequisite for a company’s fine our potential to boost sustainability.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For these reasons,\nprofitability is that its activities are compatible with external we explain the BMW Group’s ↗ corporate strategy as well as the\neconomic, ecological and social interests.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Conversely, profit- latest developments and the way in which the business is\nability is the prerequisite for a company’s ability to develop managed on the basis of key financial and non-financial tar-\nsustainable and innovative technologies, ensure job secu rity, gets.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "↗ KPI Dashboard\nand cooperate with all its business partners along a value\nchain that is striving to become increasingly sustainable.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ KPI Dashboard",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "On 8 March 2022, the Financial Statements of BMW AG\nwere authorised for issue by the Board of Management and\nFor this reason, since the financial year 2020, the BMW Group the Group Financial Statements approved for publication.\nhas kept stakeholders informed of its business performance The BMW Group Report combines the management reports\nby reporting on an integrated basis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "8 March 2022",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "BMW AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the financial year 2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With the Integrated of Bayerische Motoren Werke Aktiengesellschaft (BMW AG)\nGroup Report 2021, we aim to provide a clear and compre- and the BMW Group in a Combined Management Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Integrated of Bayerische Motoren Werke Aktiengesellschaft",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "hensive insight into the BMW Group and explain our activities\nin a transparent, comprehensible and measurable manner.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We are well aware that integrated reporting is among the\nsubjects of an ongoing discussion currently taking place be-\ntween stakeholders, regulators and reporting entities.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The\nstatus achieved to date is therefore still subject to constant\nreview and continuous improvement.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "6 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nAbout This Report\nChanges in reporting and outlook for reporting — German Accounting Standards (GASs) underpinning ADDITIONAL INFORMATION\nrequirements HGB requirements\nIn light of recent and prospective changes in non-financial ON THE REPORT\ndisclosure requirements, including the revision of the Non-Fi- — German Stock Corporation Act (AktG)\nnancial Reporting Directive at EU level (Corporate Sustain-\nability Reporting Directive), the related development of EU — Taxonomy Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2020 / 852 of the Publication and scope\nreporting standards and the establishment of the Inter- European Council and of the European Parliament on the The BMW Group Report is published annually to coincide\nnational Sustainability Standards Board (ISSB) under the Establishment of a Framework to Facilitate Sustainable with the BMW Group Annual Conference – most recently\numbrella of the ↗ IFRS Foundation, the pace of change within the Investment, and amending Regulation (EU) 2019 / 2088) held on 17 March 2021 – and is subsequently available in\nreporting environment will continue to gather momentum both German and English on the BMW Group website.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "This Report\nChanges",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "German Accounting Standards",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "852",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Publication",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Inter- European Council",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the European Parliament",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the The BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "annually",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "national Sustainability Standards Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Establishment of a Framework to Facilitate Sustainable",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the ↗ IFRS Foundation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2019 / 2088",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "17 March 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "English",
        "LANGUAGE"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The\nand increase the extent to which non-financial and financial The Combined Management Report is also based on: ↗ GRI Content Index is also available on the website as a sepa-\ndisclosures need to be presented on an integrated basis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Combined Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The reporting period covers the financial\nThe BMW Group is preparing itself for these new trends by — Guidelines on Alternative Performance Measures issued year from 1 January to 31 December 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Guidelines on Alternative Performance Measures",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1 January to 31",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The statements\ndeveloping its internal control system to ensure that non-fi- by the European Securities and Markets Authority (ESMA) made in the report relate to the BMW Group reporting entity.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the European Securities and Markets Authority",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "nancial performance indicators are monitored to the same Any deviations are marked accordingly.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Nothing significant\ndegree as financial performance indicators.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In the year under — German Corporate Governance Code has changed in the reporting period with regard to the or-\nreport, we also complied with the disclosure requirements of ganisational structure of the BMW Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The BMW Group\nthe (↗ EU Taxonomy) Regulation and expanded our reporting in Furthermore, the following reporting standards and trans- Report 2022 will be published on 15 March 2023.\nline with the requirements of the Sustainability Accounting parency requirements have, for the most part, been integrat-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "15 March 2023",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Accounting",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "102­45, 102­48, GRI­Index 102­52\nStandards Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "102­45",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102­48",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102­52",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Standards Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "↗ SASB­Index ed in the Combined Management Report:\n↗ GRI 102­48, 102­49 External audit\n— Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) (↗ GRI­Index), option The entire report of BMW AG, comprising the Combined\n“ comprehensive” Management Report, the Group Financial Statements, the\nFRAMEWORKS APPLIED disclosures on corporate governance and the additional GRI\n— Sustainability Accounting Standards Board (SASB) information, has been subject to an annual independent au-\n(↗ SASB­Index) dit by PricewaterhouseCoopers GmbH",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Combined Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗ GRI 102­48",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "102­49",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Accounting Standards Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "PricewaterhouseCoopers GmbH",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Wirtschaftsprüfungs-\nThe BMW Group Report 2021 is based on the following re- gesellschaft (“PwC” or “Auditor”).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "PwC",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "Auditor",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The external audit serves\nporting and accounting standards: — Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclosures to underpin the reliability and trustworthiness of the infor-\n(TCFD) (↗ TCFD­Index) mation contained therein for external users.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Task Force",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Disclosures",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "TCFD",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The external au-\nCombined Management Report dit supports the Supervisory Board of BMW AG in fulfilling its\nThe Combined Management Report is based on the follow- — UN Global Compact Progress Report: see references in auditing duties.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board of BMW AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Combined Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "UN Global Compact Progress Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Any links and / or disclosures that refer to\ning legal frameworks: GRI Content Index (↗ GRI­Index) additional information outside the BMW Group Report and\nthe GRI Content Index are not part of the audit.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI Content",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The ↗ Remuner­\n— German Commercial Code (HGB) (among other relevant Group Financial Statements ation Report 2021 was prepared in accordance with the require-\nlegislation)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The ↗ Remuner­\n—",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group Financial Statements ation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Group Financial Statements of Bayerische Motoren ments of § 162 of the German Stock Corporation Act (AktG)\nWerke Aktiengesellschaft for the year ended 31 December and its content audited by PricewaterhouseCoopers GmbH\n— Combined Non-Financial Statement (NFS) at Group 2021 have been prepared in accordance with International Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft.\nand Company level in accordance with § 289 b and Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) as endorsed by the\n§ 315 b HGB.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Bayerische Motoren",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "162",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the German Stock Corporation Act",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Werke Aktiengesellschaft",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the year ended 31 December",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "PricewaterhouseCoopers GmbH",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Combined Non-Financial Statement",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NFS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group 2021",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "International Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Reporting Standards",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "315",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "European Union (EU) and the supplementary requirements\nof § 315 e HGB.\n7 BMW Group Report 2021",
    "entities": [
      [
        "European Union",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "315",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nAbout This Report\nPwC has audited the Group Financial Statements and the was given to the BMW Group’s own business operations, that of the BMW Group’s net assets, financial position and re-\nCombined Management Report for the year ended 31 De- products and services on the one hand and its business re- sults of operations, its development or performance, could\ncember 2021 and issued an unqualified audit opinion there- lationships (for example in the supply chain) on the other.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "This Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "PwC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the year ended 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "cember 2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In differ considerably to those statements.\nupon.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Further information is provided in the ↗ Independent Audi­ accordance with statutory materiality requirements, infor-\ntor’s Report and the ↗ Independent Practitioner’s Report on mation has been aggregated in each case with a view to pro-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the ↗ Independent Audi­",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the ↗ Independent Practitioner’s Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Editorial comments\nNon-financial Disclosures.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "viding an understanding of the BMW Group’s course of busi-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The key figures presented in this report have been rounded\nness, results of operations and financial position, while also in accordance with standard commercial practise.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In certain\nThe contents of the NFS, in accordance with § 289 b and showing the impact of its activities on the non-financial as- cases, this may mean that figures do not add up exactly to\n§ 315 b HGB, were subjected to an audit to obtain limited pects specified in the legislation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NFS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "315",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A stakeholder survey con- the stated total",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "and that percentages cannot be derived from\nassurance and is denoted with the symbol … .",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The chapter ducted during the period under report with selected repre-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "↗ Dialogue with stakeholders and the additional information pro- sentatives from capital markets and academia confirmed our\nvided in the section ↗ Additional GRI Information were also sub- selection of ↗ material topics.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ Dialogue",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗ Additional GRI Information",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The BMW Group Report uses also the simplified term “car-\njected to a limited assurance engagement.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Certain individual ↗ GRI 102­46, 102­49 bon” or the abbreviation CO instead of CO e. Since not only\n2 2\nparts of the NFS as well as the remainder of the Combined carbon dioxide, but also other gases such as methane (CH )\n4\nManagement Report were subjected to a reasonable assur- Connection to figures in the Group Financial Statements and nitrous oxide (N O) contribute to climate warming to a\n2\nance engagement.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗ GRI 102­46",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "102­49 bon",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "2 2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "NFS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Information provided in the ↗ SASB­Index is For each topic, an assessment was carried out to identify varying extent, the impact is converted into so-called CO\n2\nsubjected to a limited assurance review on a voluntary basis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "↗",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "figures reported in the financial statements that enable a equivalents (CO e).",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "2\nThe ↗ TCFD­Index refers to the corresponding chapter, in which better understanding of the NFS, and which therefore need\nthe respective test levels are denoted.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "↗",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NFS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "to be disclosed and explained.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Summarised disclosures of fuel consumption, carbon emis-\nsions and electricity consumption are provided in the section\nMaterial topics addressed in the NFS Forward-looking statements ↗ Consumption and carbon emissions data.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NFS Forward",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "↗ Consumption",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The material topics addressed in the NFS to ensure compli- The BMW Group Report 2021 contains various forward-look-\nance with § 289 c and § 315 c HGB were determined partly ing statements concerning future developments that are\non the basis of the results of the materiality analysis updated based on the current status of the BMW Group’s assumptions\nin 2018, in line with the requirements of the Global Reporting and forecasts.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NFS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The BMW Group Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "289",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Global Reporting",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "These statements are therefore subject to a va-\nInitiative (GRI), and partly on the basis of the BMW Group’s riety of predictable and unpredictable risks, uncertainties and\nown long-term targets.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For these purposes, consideration other factors, which means that the actual outcome, including\nNICHT LÖSCHEN!!!!!\n1",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To Our Stakeholders\n8 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\n9 BMW Group in Figures\n12 Report of the Supervisory Board\n21 Statement of the Chairman of the Board of Management\n27",
    "entities": [
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board\n",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "21",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "27",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management\n28 Dialogue with Stakeholders\n31 BMW Group and Capital Markets\n1\nT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "28",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "31",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Capital Markets",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A K E H O L D E R S\n9 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nBMW Group in",
    "entities": [
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Figures\nB M W G R O U P I",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "I G U R E S\nKEY PERFORMANCE INDICATORS\n2017 20181 2019 2020 2021",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2017 20181",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Change in %\nGROUP\nProfit / loss before tax in € million 10,675 9,627 7,118 5,222 16,060 –\nWorkforce at year­end 2 129,932 134,682 126,016 120,726 118,909 – 1.5\nShare of women in management positions in the BMW Group 3 16.0 17.2 17.2 17.8 18.8 5.6\nAUTOMOTIVE SEGMENT\nEBIT margin in % 9.2 7.2 4.9 2.7 10.3 –\nRoCE in % 77.7 49.8 29.0 12.7 59.9 –\nDeliveries 4, 5 2,465,021 2,486,149 2,537,504 2,325,179 2,521,514 8.4\nShare of electrified vehicles in deliveries (in %) 4.2 5.7 5.8 8.3 13.0 56.6\nCO emissions EU new vehicle fleet (in g / km) 6, 7 128.0 127.5 127.0 99.1 (135.0)8 115.99 – 14.1\n2\nCO emissions per vehicle produced (in tons) 10, 11, 12 0.41 0.40 0.40 0.35 0.33 – 5.7\n2\nMOTORCYCLES SEGMENT\nEBIT margin in % 9.1 8.1 8.2 4.5 8.3 84.4\nRoCE in % 34.0 28.4 29.4 15.0 35.9 –\nDeliveries 164,153 165,566 175,162 169,272 194,261 14.8\nFINANCIAL SERVICES SEGMENT\nRoE in % 18.1 14.8 15.0 11.2 22.6 –\n1 The 2018 figures were adjusted due to the change in accounting policy in conjunction with the adoption of IFRS 16 (↗ Annual Report 2019, Note 6 to the Group Financial Statements).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "7,118",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "16,060",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2 129,932",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "126,016",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "120,726 118,909",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "16.0 17.2",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "18.8 5.6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "59.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4.2 5.7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "56.6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "127.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "127.0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "99.1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "135.0)8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "115.99",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14.1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "12 0.41 0.40 0.40 0.35 0.33",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "5.7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "8.3 84.4\nRoCE",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "34.0 28.4 29.4",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "35.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "164,153",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "165,566",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "169,272",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "194,261",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "RoE",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "18.1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "IFRS 16 (",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "2 T he term “employee” has been redefined with effect from the reporting year 2020 (for definition, see ↗ Glossary and explanation of key figures).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the reporting year 2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "↗ Glossary",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The figure for 2019 was restated accordingly for comparison purposes (2019 before adjustment: 133,778 employees).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "133,778",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For the period 2018 and earlier, the percentage of employees no\nlonger covered by the new definition is between 7.5 and 8.0 %.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the period 2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "between 7.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "8.0 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The new definition of the term “employee” (see footnote 1) also has an impact on disclosures relating to the percentage of female employees.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The 2019 figure was adjusted accordingly for comparison purposes (2019 before adjustment: 17.5 %).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2019",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "17.5 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "4 Deliveries including the joint venture BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd., Shenyang (2017: 385,705 units, 2018: 455,581 units, 2019: 538,612 units, 2020: 602,247 units, 2021: 651,236 units).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "4 Deliveries",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Shenyang",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2017",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "385,705",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "455,581",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "538,612",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "602,247",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "651,236",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "5 Retail vehicle delivery data for 2020 and 2021 are not directly comparable to the data presented for previous years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "previous years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "See Retail vehicle delivery data in the section ↗ Comparison of Forecasts with Actual Outcomes for further information.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "6 EU-27 countries including Norway and Iceland; with effect from 2021, values are calculated on a converted basis in line with WLTP (Worldwide Harmonised Light Vehicles Test Procedure).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6 EU-27",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Norway",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Iceland",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "WLTP",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Values from 2017 to 2020 according to New European Driving Cycle (NEDC).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2017",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "New European Driving Cycle",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NEDC",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This is a preliminary internal calculation with a potential variation of +/– 0.5 g CO2 / km, as official registration figures from the authorities are not available from all EU states.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "0.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The EU Commission is not expected to publish official figures until November the following year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The EU Commission",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "November the following year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "8 To improve year-on- year comparability, the 2020 NEDC figures were converted to WLTP after adjusting for permissible flexibilities – specifically from 99 g CO2 / km according to NEDC (including 5 g CO2 / km phase-in, 7.5 g CO2 / km supercredits and 2.4 g CO2 / km eco-innovations) to 135 g CO2 / km according to WLTP\n(excluding flexibilities).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "year-on- year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "NEDC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "WLTP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "99",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "NEDC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "135",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "WLTP",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In 2020, a phase-in regulation was accepted, as was the recognition of supercredits.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "As of 2021, these two simplifications no longer apply for the BMW Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "9 Flexibilities as defined in the regulatory requirements for 2021 are as follows: eco-innovation with 1.7 g CO2 / km (WLTP).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1.7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "CO2 / km",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "WLTP",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "10 Efficiency ratio calculated on the basis of Scope 1 and Scope 2 CO2 emissions (i.e. a market-based method according to GHG Protocol Scope 2 guidance; mainly the use of the VDA emissions factors as well as isolated use of local emissions factors; but excluding climate-changing gases other than carbon dioxide) from vehicle pro-\nduction (BMW Group manufacturing sites incl.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Scope 1",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "GHG Protocol Scope 2",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "VDA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "joint venture BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd. and motorcycles, excluding contract manufacturers), as well as BMW Group non-manufacturing sites (e.g. research centre, sales centre, offices) divided by the number of vehicles (excluding motorcycles) produced (BMW Group manufacturing\nsites incl.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "joint venture BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd., excluding contract manufacturers).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "11 From 2021, this indicator will include the carbon emissions of all other BMW Group locations in addition to the carbon emissions generated by production.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The figures for 2019 (base year) and 2020 have been adjusted accordingly for comparison purposes (2019 before adjustment: 0.30 tons, 2020 before adjustment: 0.23 tons).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "0.30 tons",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "0.23 tons",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "12 Figures from 2017 and 2018 are audited with limited assurance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2017",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "10 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nBMW Group in Figures\nFURTHER FINANCIAL PERFORMANCE FIGURES\nin € million 2017 2018 2019 2020 2021 Change in %\nTotal capital expenditure 1 7,112 8,013 7,784 6,222 7,518 20.8\nDepreciation and amortisation 4,822 5,113 6,017 6,143 6,495 5.7\nFree cash flow Automotive segment 4,459 2,713 2,567 3,395 6,354 87.2\nGroup revenues 2 98,282 96,855 104,210 98,990 111,239 12.4\nAutomotive 85,742 85,846 91,682 80,853 95,476 18.1\nMotorcycles 2,272 2,173 2,368 2,284 2,748 20.3\nFinancial Services 2 27,567 27,705 29,598 30,044 32,867 9.4\nOther Entities 7 6 5 3 5 66.7\nEliminations 2 – 17,306 – 18,875 – 19,443 – 14,194 – 19,857 39.9\nGroup profit / loss before financial result (EBIT) 2 9,899 8,933 7,411 4,830 13,400 –\nAutomotive 7,888 6,182 4,499 2,162 9,870 –\nMotorcycles 207 175 194 103 227 –\nFinancial Services 2 2,194 2,172 2,312 1,721 3,701 –\nOther Entities 14 – 27 29 36 –8 –\nEliminations 2 – 404 431 377 808 – 390 –\nGroup profit / loss before tax (EBT) 2 10,675 9,627 7,118 5,222 16,060 –\nAutomotive 8,717 6,977 4,467 2,722 11,805 –\nMotorcycles 205 169 187 100 228 –\nFinancial Services 2 2,207 2,143 2,272 1,725 3,753 –\nOther Entities 80 – 45 – 96 – 235 531 –\nEliminations 2 – 534 383 288 910 – 257 –\nGroup income taxes 2 – 2,000 – 2,530 – 2,140 – 1,365 – 3,597 –\nProfit / loss from continuing operations 2 8,675 7,097 4,978 3,857 12,463 –\nProfit / loss from discontinued operations – – 33 44 – – –\nGroup net profit / loss 2 8,675 7,064 5,022 3,857 12,463 –\nEarnings in € per share of common stock / preferred stock 2 13.07 / 13.09 10.60 / 10.62 7.47 / 7.49 5.73 / 5.75 18.77/18.79 –\nPre-tax return on sales 2, 3 in % 10.9 9.9 6.8 5.3 14.4 –\n1 Expenditure for capitalised development costs, other intangible assets and property, plant and equipment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "€ million 2017",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "1 7,112",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "8,013",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6,222",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7,518",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "20.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4,822",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5.7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4,459",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,567",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,395",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "87.2\nGroup",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "96,855",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "104,210",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "12.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "85,742",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "95,476",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "18.1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,272",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,284",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,748",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "66.7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "17,306",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "18,875",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "19,443",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14,194",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "19,857",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "39.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EBIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "8,933 7,411",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "13,400",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7,888",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,162 9,870",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "194",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "103",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "227",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,172",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1,721",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,701",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "27 29 36",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "404 431 377 808",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "390",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EBT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7,118",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "16,060",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "8,717",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6,977",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,722",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "205",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "228",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2 2,207",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,272",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,753",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "80",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "45",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "96",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "235",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "531",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "534 383",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "257",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,530",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,140",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1,365",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,597",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2 8,675",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4,978",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "12,463",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "33 44",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5,022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "12,463",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "€",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2 13.07",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "13.09 10.60",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "10.62 7.47",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7.49 5.73",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The figures for 2018 were adjusted due to the change in accounting policy in conjunction with the adoption of IFRS 16 (↗ Annual Report 2019, Note 6 to the Group Financial Statements).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "IFRS 16 (",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "3 Group profit/loss before tax as a percentage of Group revenues.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3 Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "11 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nBMW Group in Figures\nOTHER NON-FINANCIAL PERFORMANCE FIGURES\n2017 2018 2019 2020 2021 Change in %\nGROUP\nSpending on employee training and development (in million €) 1 349 373 370 279 389 39.4\nAUTOMOTIVE SEGMENT\nDeliveries by brand 2\nBMW 3 2,089,854 2,117,854 2,184,939 2,028,841 2,213,790 9.1\nMINI 371,729 364,101 347,465 292,582 302,138 3.3\nRolls­Royce 3,438 4,194 5,100 3,756 5,586 48.7\nTotal 3 2,465,021 2,486,149 2,537,504 2,325,179 2,521,514 8.4\nProduction by brand\nBMW 4 2,123,947 2,168,496 2,205,841 1,980,740 2,166,644 9.4\nMINI 378,486 368,685 352,729 271,121 288,713 6.5\nRolls­Royce 3,308 4,353 5,455 3,776 5,912 56.6\nTotal 4 2,505,741 2,541,534 2,564,025 2,255,637 2,461,269 9.1\nEnergy consumption per vehicle produced (in MWh) 5, 6 2.17 2.12 2.04 2.12 2.10 – 0.9\nMOTORCYCLES SEGMENT\nProduction volume\nBMW",
    "entities": [
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2017 2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "GROUP\nSpending",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1 349",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "373 370",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "389",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "39.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,089,854",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,117,854",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,184,939",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "371,729",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "364,101",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3.3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,438",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5,100",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "48.7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2,123,947",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,168,496",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,166,644 9.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "288,713",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,308",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3,776",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5,912",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "56.6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,541,534",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,564,025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,255,637",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "MWh",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "0.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "185,682 162,687 187,116 168,104 187,500 11.5\nFINANCIAL SERVICES SEGMENT\nNew contracts with retail customer 1,828,604 1,908,640 2,003,782 1,845,271 1,956,514 6.0\n1 Training for BMW Group employees and temporary staff at consolidated companies worldwide.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "162,687",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "168,104",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1,828,604",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,003,782",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1,956,514",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6.0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Data are collated on the basis of direct inputs of participants and, to a small extent, by extrapolation.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Data also include e-learning formats.\n2 Delivery figures presented for 2020 and 2021 are not directly comparable to those of previous years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "previous years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "See sales figures for deliveries in the section ↗ Comparison of Forecasts with Actual Outcomes for further information.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "3 Deliveries including the joint venture BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd., Shenyang (2017: 385,705 units, 2018: 455,581 units, 2019: 538,612 units, 2020: 602,247 units, 2021: 651,236 units).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Shenyang",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2017",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "385,705",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "455,581",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "538,612",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "602,247",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "651,236",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "4 Production volume including the joint venture BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd., Shenyang (2017: 396,749 units, 2018: 491,872 units, 2019: 536,509 units, 2020: 602,935 units, 2021: 700,777 units).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Shenyang",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2017",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "396,749",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "491,872",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "536,509",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "602,935",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "700,777",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "5 Efficiency ratio calculated on the basis of energy consumption, adjusted for CHP losses, of vehicle production (BMW Group manufacturing sites incl.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "CHP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "joint venture BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd., excluding motorcycles and contract manufacturers) divided by the total number of vehicles produced (BMW Group\nmanufacturing sites incl.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "joint venture BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd., excluding motorcycles and contract manufacturing).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW Brilliance Automotive Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "6 Figures from 2017 and 2018 are audited with limited assurance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2017",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "12 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nR E P O R T",
    "entities": [
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A R D\nDEAR SHAREHOLDERS,\nThe year 2021 was a particularly challenging one for the BMW Group, with semicon-\nductor supply issues and the ongoing coronavirus pandemic making the business\nenvironment more volatile and calling for even greater flexibility from company and\nworkforce alike.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "However, the prudent leadership of the Board of Management and\nthe tremendous hard work of our employees helped make 2021 a highly successful\nNorbert Reithofer\nfinancial year for the BMW Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Norbert Reithofer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "financial year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With a new record of over 2.5 million BMW brand\nChairman of the\nvehicles delivered, we are now the leading manufacturer in the premium segment Supervisory Board\nworldwide.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "over 2.5 million",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With great resolve, the Board of Management continued to develop the\nkey strategies that will shape the future of the BMW Group and create the ideal\nconditions for an attractive product portfolio precisely tailored to meet the needs\nof our customers as we move forward.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The fact that we are on the right track with\nour strategy was amply borne out by the enthusiastic media response to the BMW i\nVision Circular at the IAA Mobility in Munich and the presentation of the BMW iX and\nBMW i4 models.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Vision Circular",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Even in these uncertain times we therefore look to 2022 with confi-\ndence and will remain firmly focused on our mission of moving people with products\nthat evoke emotions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "13 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nFocus of Supervisory Board activities during the past financial year The monitoring of corporate strategy remained high on the Supervisory Board’s\nThe Supervisory Board performed the duties incumbent upon it with the utmost dili- agenda.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board\nFocus of Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the past financial year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management provided a comprehensive account of its\ngence in the financial year 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the financial year 2021",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "strategy with a particular focus on sustainability, including detailed key objectives,\nregionally differentiated approaches and specific strategies for each of the Group’s\nBased on in-depth reports presented by the Board of Management, we continuously divisions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It also briefed us on the state of progress in terms of electrification, digital-\nand diligently monitored the quality of management in the BMW Group and advised isation, sustainability and circularity and explained the customer-centric, future-ori-\nthe Board of Management on matters relating to the strategic development and ented strategy adopted for the BMW brand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Against the backdrop of stricter carbon\nleadership of the BMW Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We focused in particular on the technological trans- emissions regulations across all major markets, the Board of Management provided\nformation of the BMW Group’s drive system technology.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At each of its five meetings us with details of the BMW Group’s ambitious decarbonisation targets up to the\n(including two two-day meetings), the Supervisory Board held detailed discussions year 2030.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "two-day",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "year 2030",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The latest aspects of vehicle digitalisation, ranging from digital operating\nwith the Board of Management on the BMW Group’s current position.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Board of systems and driver assistance technologies to personalised digital experiences, were\nManagement also kept the Supervisory Board informed of any matters of significance also thoroughly explained to us in a presentation, which also focused on differing\noutside the framework of formal meetings whenever necessary.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of systems",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "I also discussed key customer expectations in various markets as well as the importance of digital fea-\ncurrent matters personally with the Chairman of the Board of Management between tures as a key purchasing criterion, particularly in the strategically important market\nmeetings on an ongoing basis, as did the Chairman of the Audit Committee with the of China.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We also held a detailed discussion on the technological challenges posed\nBoard of Management member responsible for Finance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Finance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "for vehicle, environment and drivers when developing automated driving beyond Lev-\nel 3.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A Supervisory Board member with in-depth expertise in this field provided us\nWithin the Supervisory Board and its committees, dialogues were always conduct- with additional insight into the future of automated driving as well as the importance\ned in an open and constructive spirit, both internally and together with members of of agile software integration in BMW Group vehicles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At each meeting, the Board of\nthe Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of\nthe Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Members of the Supervisory Board and its committees Management reported on its strategy-related work as well as on the current status of\nhad adequate opportunity to prepare in advance for the topics to be discussed at implementation.\nmeetings with the aid of well-documented information provided to them.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Moreover,\nshareholder representatives and employee representatives generally prepared for It also kept us well informed about current topics of significance, including the\nmeetings in separate preliminary discussions.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "establishing of QUATAC, a consortium promoting the use of quantum computing in\nindustrial settings, the successful presentation of the BMW Group at the IAA Mobility\nIn its regular reports on the BMW Group’s position, the Board of Management kept in Munich, the highly encouraging results of the employee survey, the BMW Group’s\nus well informed regarding current developments and performance, including an participation in the start-up company Solid Power, which specialises in solid-state\nin-depth presentation of current sales trends based on figures analysed by market, battery cells, and the expansion of the IONITY network for premium charging sta-\nmodel and drive system for both the BMW Group and its competitors, with a sharp fo- tions using 100 % green power.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "QUATAC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Munich",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Solid Power",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "IONITY",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "100 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "cus on electrified models and developments on the Chinese market.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The reports also\ncontained regular updates on the performance and risk profile of the Financial Ser-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "On the basis of a thorough examination, we considered the impact of changes in\nvices segment as well as the development of key performance indicators and liquidity legislation and regulations on the BMW Group, in particular the Act on Corporate\nfor the BMW Group as a whole, highlighting deviations from the original forecast and Due Diligence in Supply Chains, the Act on Strengthening Financial Market Integrity\npresenting a range of scenarios for future potential developments.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Act",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chains",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Act",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Updates on the (FISG) and the new European exhaust emissions standard (Euro 7).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "FISG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "European",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "current status of semiconductor supply issues were also provided at every meeting.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "14 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nWe also spent considerable time deliberating on the antitrust proceedings instigated The Board of Management reported on the current status of the diversity concepts\nby the EU Commission in connection with the former working groups of several Ger- developed by the Group and the extent to which targets have been achieved regard-\nman automobile manufacturers.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the EU Commission",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In this context, we consulted with external attorneys ing the proportion of women employed at various levels.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "and an antitrust advisor engaged directly by the Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We were kept\nwell informed about the latest status of the proceedings at all times.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In May 2021, af- We also addressed the topic of compliance within the BMW Group in depth, including\nter the EU Commission significantly scaled down its charges in terms of content and the current status and ongoing developments.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "May 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the EU Commission",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Chief Compliance Officer pre-\ntiming, the BMW Group was able to reverse approximately € 1 billion of the € 1.4 bil- sented the annual report on compliance, including compliance targets and a number\nlion provision recognised in 2019.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "approximately € 1 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "1.4",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "After the proceedings were concluded in July 2021 of other selected topics, focusing in particular on measures and processes aimed at\nwith the payment of a fine amounting to around € 373 million, the Supervisory Board improving the Group’s compliance management system on a continuous basis.\ncarefully considered the question of potential personal responsibility on the part\nof former Board of Management members and any duty of the Supervisory Board In light of the coronavirus pandemic and the accompanying restrictions on events\nto act.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "July 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "around € 373 million",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board also obtained advice on this issue from an attorney, involving large numbers of people, in March 2021 we agreed on a plan to hold the\nwhose written findings were also explained to us personally at the relevant meeting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "March 2021",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Annual General Meeting 2021 on a virtual basis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For the same reason, in December\nBased on this report and taking into account the supplementary explanations pro- 2021, we approved the plan to hold the Annual General Meeting 2022 again in a\nvided by the antitrust advisor, also regarding the legal particularities of the antitrust virtual format.\nproceedings, the Supervisory Board decided – after thorough discussion and on the\nrecommendation of the Audit Committee – not to assert any claims against former Strategic cooperations were again a key topic at Supervisory Board meetings in 2021,\nmembers of the Board of Management of BMW AG in this context.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "December",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management of BMW AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "including in particular the positioning of the BMW Group in the vital Chinese market\ngoing forward and the future structure of the BMW Brilliance Automotive joint ven-\nThe Supervisory Board also deliberated at length on key issues arising within the ture.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "BMW",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Brilliance Automotive",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We also deliberated on the intended acquisition of shares in Brilliance Automo-\nBoard of Management’s various key areas of responsibility.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Brilliance Automo-\nBoard of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We were given an insight tive Manufacturing.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management updated us regularly on the strategic\ninto working methods and working environments at the BMW Group currently being positioning and status at the various YOUR NOW companies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "developed in conjunction with the “Connected Works” project.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the “Connected Works",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The new remuneration system resolved by the Supervisory Board for the members\nThe Board of Management familiarised us with the NEUE KLASSE, which will herald of the Board of Management during the previous financial year came into effect on\nthe third phase of the BMW Group’s transformation to electric mobility from 2025 1 January 2021 and was approved by shareholders at the Annual General Meeting\nonwards and set new standards in terms of digitalisation, electrification and sus- 2021 with a majority of 91.6 % of valid votes.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NEUE",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the previous financial year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "third",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025 1 January 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "91.6 %",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board reviewed both\ntainability in vehicles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We took a detailed look at the key features of the New Cluster the targeted and the expected level of Board of Management remuneration for the\nVehicle Architecture (NCVA), which is specifically geared towards all-electric vehicles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the New Cluster",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NCVA",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "financial year 2021 in light of the BMW Group’s business performance and also the\nFurthermore, the Board of Management elucidated potential applications of artificial multi-year remuneration trend of its senior executives and employees in Germany.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the BMW Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "intelligence (AI) in production planning processes.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Financial Services segment Based on a comparative study conducted by an external remuneration consultant\nwas also included in our deliberations, particularly in light of positive developments in and subsequent oral advice, we concluded that the remuneration of Board of Man-\nterms of its risk profile and the pre-owned vehicle market.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Key topics relating to the agement members is appropriate.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In December 2021, following thorough preparation\nGroup’s corporate finance system were also discussed.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "December 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Regarding sales markets we by the Personnel Committee, we adopted the variable remuneration component tar-\nfocused in particular on Asia as a whole.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Personnel Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Asia",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "gets applicable to Board of Management members for the financial year 2022, taking\ninto account the budget for the financial year 2022, the long-term business plan and\n15 BMW Group Report 2021 To Our Stakeholders Combined Management Report Group Financial Statements Corporate Governance Remuneration R eport Other I nformation\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nthe corporate strategy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the financial year 2022",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the financial year 2022",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "15",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Detailed information on Board of Management remuneration In December, the Board of Management and the Supervisory Board issued their Dec-\nis provided in the ↗ Remuneration Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "December",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the ↗ Remuneration Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "laration of Compliance with the German Corporate Governance Code.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Compliance",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the German",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We will comply\nwith the recommendations of the Code as amended on 16 December 2019, again\nThe new remuneration system, which gives the Supervisory Board greater influence without exception.\non corporate strategy implementation was also the focus of one-on-one discussions\nwith investor representatives ahead of the Annual General Meeting 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "16 December 2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "BMW",
    "year": 2021,
