[
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nThe Mercedes-Benz Group\ncan look back on a tradition that goes back to the inventors of the automobile – Gottlieb Daimler and Carl Benz –\nand features pioneering achievements in automotive engineering.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Gottlieb Daimler",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Carl Benz",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Group is one of the most successful auto-\nmobile companies in the world and is one of the largest providers of high-end cars and premium vans.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Financing,\nleasing, vehicle subscriptions and rental, fleet management, digital services for charging and payment, insurance\nbrokerage and innovative mobility services round off the range of services.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "2.389 million €145.6 billion €13.6 billion €9.2 billion 175,264\nUnit sales Revenue EBIT Free cash flow of the Employees worldwide\nindustrial business as of 31 Dec. 2024\nTO OUR\nSHAREHOLDERS\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 5\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nTO OUR SHAREHOLDERS\n6 Letter from the CEO\n8",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2.389 million €145.6 billion €13.6 billion €9.2 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "175,264",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Revenue EBIT Free",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "31",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Dec. 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management\n9 Report of the Supervisory Board\n19 The Supervisory Board\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 6\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nLetter from the CEO\nLetter from the CEO\nDear Shareholders,\nFor the automotive industry, 2024 was characterized Looking ahead, what topics are on our agenda?\nby a challenging geopolitical situation, a slower\nramp-up of electromobility and a subdued consumer Mercedes-Benz is about to embark on the biggest\nclimate in Asia.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "19",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Supervisory Board\nAnnual",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Dear Shareholders",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Asia",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Generally speaking, we have managed product launch programme in its history.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "We want to\nto steer Mercedes-Benz well through these difficult offer the most desirable products in all segments we\nwaters.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "At the same time, we have continued to press serve.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "With a total of four new models, we will redefine\nahead with the implementation of our strategy, and the entry into the world of Mercedes-Benz from 2025.\nthus set an important course for the future.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "This year we are starting with our new CLA.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "This year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "CLA",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In the\nimportant core segment, we will expand our electric\nWe owe this to the tireless commitment of our portfolio and take the product substance of our models\nemployees.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Their skill, dedication and flexibility were to the next level.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In the Top-End segment, our custom-\nthe key to these solid results.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The entire Board of ers can look forward to a range of new products from\nManagement would like to thank all of our colleagues Mercedes-AMG in the next few years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-AMG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the next few years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The S-Class\nfor this.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "will continue to strengthen its undisputed leading\nposition in its segment.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, we are continuing\nwith the further development of our vans product\nportfolio.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Ola Källenius\nChairman of the Board of Management\nof Mercedes-Benz Group AG\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 7\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nLetter from the CEO\nWith our product campaign",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ola Källenius",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": ", we are establishing a new The environment is likely to remain extremely These are all good prerequisites for driving forward the\ndesign idiom.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In the future, our vehicles will embody challenging in 2025.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "We are therefore working flat out successful future of Mercedes-Benz.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "We would be\neven more strongly what has characterized Mercedes to further improve the resilience of our business.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "We delighted if you were to accompany us on this journey.\nfor decades: confident ease and timeless style.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "decades",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "For the have set up a comprehensive programme for this\nfuture, we are focusing on coherence across the entire purpose.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "We want to create a standardized and, above Sincerely yours,\nportfolio.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Customers will primarily decide on a model – all, exceptional customer experience.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Based on our\nand then on their preferred type of drive.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "We are in a strong product portfolio, we want to take better advan-\nposition to fulfil all customer requirements well into tage of the global markets and increase the quality of\nthe 2030s – from electrified high-tech combustion our sales.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2030s",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "We will sustainably reduce our costs over the\nengines to all-electric vehicles.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Our guiding principle next few years and further streamline our structures\nis that there is a perfect Mercedes-Benz for every and processes.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "next few years",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "We are also launching an initiative to\ncustomer requirement.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Thanks to intelligent modulari- anchor the desire for top performance even more\nzation and maximum efficiency in production, we are firmly in the corporate culture of Mercedes-Benz.\nable to live up to this ambition.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Ola Källenius\nFor people all over the world, the Mercedes star is a\nThe wishes of our global customers also take centre symbol of the highest engineering skills, iconic designs\nstage in the development of new technologies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ola Källenius",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Our and the pursuit of social advancement and economic\nown operating system MB.OS celebrates its debut with success.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Our brand stands for maximum safety, excel-\nthe new CLA.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "CLA",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "This marks an important milestone for us lent quality, unique comfort and intelligent technol-\nin terms of software and digitalization.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The integration ogies.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Our team has been underpinning this reputation\nof artificial intelligence makes interaction with our cars for almost 140 years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "almost 140 years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In the future, this strong team\neven more natural, intuitive and personalized.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "We are and the Board of Management in particular will become\nalso making great progress in terms of safety and even more effective.\nautomated driving.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In Germany, our conditionally\nautomated driving system DRIVE PILOT, is authorized\nto travel at speeds of up to 95 km/h.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "up to",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "95 km",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In Beijing, we\nhave received authorization to test highly automated\ndriving systems.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Beijing",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "This underscores our pioneering role\nin this field.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Annual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 8\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nThe Board of Management\nThe Board of Management\nOla Källenius Dr Jörg Burzer Mathias Geisen Renata Jungo Brüngger Sabine Kohleisen\nChairman of the Board of Production, Quality & Supply (Member since February 2025)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Board of Management\nThe Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Jörg Burzer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Mathias Geisen",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Jungo",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Production, Quality & Supply",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "February 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Integrity, Governance & Human Relations & Labour\nManagement Chain Management Marketing & Sales Sustainability Director\nAppointed until May 2029 Appointed until November (since March 2025) Appointed until October 2025 Appointed until April 2025\n2029 Appointed until January 2028",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Governance & Human Relations & Labour\nManagement Chain Management Marketing & Sales Sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "May 2029 Appointed",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "November",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "March 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "October 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "April 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2029",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "January 2028",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Markus Schäfer Britta Seeger Oliver Thöne Hubertus Troska Harald Wilhelm\nChief Technology Officer, Marketing & Sales Greater China Greater China Finance & Controlling/\nDevelopment & Procurement (until February 2025) (since February 2025) (until January 2025)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Markus Schäfer Britta Seeger Oliver",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Hubertus",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Troska",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Harald Wilhelm",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Marketing & Sales",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Greater China Finance & Controlling/\nDevelopment & Procurement",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "February 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "February 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "January 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Mobility\nAppointed until May 2026 Human Relations & Labour Appointed until January 2028 “Business Model China” Appointed until March 2027\nDirector (since February 2025)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Mobility\n",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "May 2026",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "January 2028",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "March 2027",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "February 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Appointed until July 2025\nAppointed until December 2029\n🌐 Further information on the members of the Board of Management of Mercedes-Benz Group AG\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 9\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nDear Shareholders,\nThe global environment presented the business of It is therefore all the more important that the\nthe Mercedes-Benz Group with numerous challenges Mercedes-Benz Group positions itself optimally,\nin 2024: ongoing geopolitical conflicts, trade policy exploits efficiency potentials, and remains willing\nuncertainties and volatile markets characterized the to change and competitive while consistently going\nframework conditions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "July 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "December 2029",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management of Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board\nReport",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board\nDear Shareholders",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "forward with the transformation towards digitization\nand electrification.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, with the further\nWe successfully faced the challenges with development of the Board of Management we are\ndetermination and conviction in our own abilities as rejuvenating this body and providing new impulses\nwell as flexibility in our actions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In this demanding at crucial points.\nand intensely competitive environment, the\nMercedes-Benz Group asserted its position as one of The Mercedes-Benz Group is heading into the 2025\nthe leading suppliers of premium and luxury vehicles financial year resolutely and optimistically.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "financial year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In doing so,\nglobally.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "I would also therefore like to thank all we rely on our strengths: innovative technologies and\nemployees who gave their best in 2024.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "products, financial solidity and a clear focus on a\nprofitable, sustainable and resilient business model.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The economic, regulatory and political conditions will\nnot become any easier in the foreseeable future.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "As a\ncompany, we can only influence this to a limited\nextent.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Dr Martin Brudermüller\nChairman of the Supervisory Board\nof Mercedes-Benz Group AG\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 10\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nSupervisory and advisory activities of sales markets as well as the reaction to them in terms Working methods of the Supervisory Board\nthe Supervisory Board of business policy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Martin Brudermüller",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board\nSupervisory",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board of business policy",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In the 2024 financial year, the Supervisory Board held\nIn the 2024 financial year, the Supervisory Board of eight meetings.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the 2024 financial year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the 2024 financial year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "eight",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Seven meetings were held in person,\nMercedes-Benz Group AG again performed, in full, The Board of Management regularly informed the with the option of participation in virtual form or via\nthe duties incumbent upon it by law, the articles of Supervisory Board about all significant business telephone, and one meeting was held as a video\nassociation and the rules of procedure.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Seven",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "developments of the Group and the divisions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Meeting attendance by the members was\nthe reporting period, it kept the Supervisory Board at a very high level, as can be seen in the detailed",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In this context, the Supervisory Board continuously continuously informed about all fundamental issues overview at the end of this report.\nadvised and monitored the Board of Management in regarding corporate planning, including financial,\nthe management of the company and provided support investment, sales and personnel planning; current The work of the Supervisory Board was characterized\non strategically important issues for the further developments at Group companies; the development by open and intensive dialogue.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The members of the\ndevelopment of the company. of revenue; the situation of the company and the Supervisory Board regularly prepared for upcoming\ndivisions; the economic and political environment; and resolutions using documents provided in advance by\nThe Supervisory Board reviewed whether the individual the current status and assessment of significant legal the Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The employee and\ncompany and Consolidated Financial Statements, the proceedings.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Consolidated Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, the Board of Management shareholder representatives also regularly prepared\nCombined Management Report including the continuously reported to the Supervisory Board on the the meetings in separate discussions, which were also\nsustainability reporting and the other financial profitability and liquidity situation of the company, the attended by members of the Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "reporting complied with the applicable requirements.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "development of sales and procurement markets, the In addition, the Supervisory Board was supported in\noverall economic situation and developments on the depth by its committees.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "At the meetings of the\nFurthermore, after careful review and consultation, it capital markets and in the financial services sector.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Supervisory Board, its members discussed the\napproved numerous business transactions subject to Other topics included the further development of measures and transactions to be resolved in detail with\nits consent.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "This related in particular to the approval of the product portfolio, securing the long-term the Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Executive sessions were\nextensive investment in the further development of the competitiveness of the company and the further regularly scheduled for the meetings so that topics\nMercedes-Benz operating system MB.OS as well as the implementation of measures to ensure sustainable, could be discussed also in the absence of the Board of\ndrive and product portfolio.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "It also included financial future-oriented mobility.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board also Management.\nand investment planning, cooperation projects and the dealt in detail with the capital market and its\nconclusion of contracts of particular importance to the expectations",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board also Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": ", the share-price development and its The Supervisory Board was informed of special events\ncompany.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management informed the background, as well as the expected effects of the outside the regular meetings.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, some\nSupervisory Board about a large number of other strategic projects on the share-price development.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "members of the Supervisory Board and the Board of\nmeasures and business transactions and discussed Management held bilateral meetings to exchange\nthem intensively and in detail with the Supervisory views.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of\n",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management also informed the\nBoard; for example, the effects on the company of Supervisory Board of the key indicators of the business\npolitical developments and trade conflicts in the main\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 11\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\ndevelopment and of existing risks by means of written Topics of the Supervisory Board’ Work status of the fulfilment of the settlement concluded\nreports.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the\nBoard",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Annual Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board\ndevelopment",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Topics of the Supervisory Board’ Work",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "On 19 January 2024, at an extraordinary meeting, the with the US authorities in relation to diesel emissions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "19 January 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Supervisory Board was informed of the plans of the Furthermore, the body dealt with the Board of Manage-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Manage-",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The members of the Supervisory Board assume Board of Management to comprehensively review the ment’s remuneration on the basis of the remuneration\nresponsibility for their training and further education structures of the Group’s Own Retail operations in system approved by the General Meeting in 2023.\nmeasures in areas such as changes in the legal Germany and this was discussed intensively.\nframework and new, forward-looking technologies that At the meeting in March 2024, the Supervisory Board\nare required for the performance of their tasks and are In its meeting on 21 February 2024, the Supervisory discussed the Annual Financial Statements, the\nsupported in this by the company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board assume Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the General Meeting",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "March 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "21 February 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Annual Financial Statements",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In the reporting Board decided on the extension of Renata Jungo Consolidated Financial Statements and the Combined\nperiod, for example, the company held information Brüngger’s and Britta Seeger’s appointments.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Renata Jungo Consolidated Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Brüngger",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Britta Seeger’s",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In the Management Report, including the Non-Financial\nevents on ‘Digital Trust’ as part of the sustainable presence of representatives of the auditor, the Declaration for the 2023 financial year of Mercedes-\nbusiness strategy as well as on the Mercedes-Benz Supervisory Board then discussed the preliminary key Benz Group AG and the Group, each of which had been\noperating system MB.OS.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Digital Trust’",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2023 financial year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Both internal and external figures of the 2023 company and the Consolidated issued with an unqualified audit opinion by the auditor,\nexperts were involved in these events.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Consolidated",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, new Financial Statements, the outlook for 2024 as well as as well as the reports of the Audit Committee and the\nmembers of the Supervisory Board have the opportu- the preliminary proposal to the 2024 General Meeting Supervisory Board, the Declaration on Corporate\nnity to meet the members of the Board of Management for the appropriation of profits and noted them with Governance, the Remuneration report, and the\nand senior executives with specialist responsibility in a approval.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board determined that there proposal for the appropriation of profits.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The members\nspecifically designated onboarding programme for a were no objections to their publication.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The preliminary of the Supervisory Board were provided with extensive\nbilateral exchange on fundamental and current topics key figures for the 2023 financial year, the outlook for documentation for their preparation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2023 financial year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, the\nin respect of the relevant areas of the Board of Ma- 2024 and the preliminary proposal for the appropria- Supervisory Board passed its proposed resolutions on\nnagement, thus gaining an overview of the topics tion of profits were published at the annual press the agenda items for the 2024 Annual General Meeting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Ma- 2024",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the appropria- Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "relevant to the company and of the governance conference on 22 February 2024.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "22",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "At the same meeting In order to meet the expectations of investors to\nstructure.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "ESG (environmental, social and governance) the Supervisory Board approved the new general share improve shareholder participation, it was decided,\nand sustainability-related thematic blocks are also an buyback policy as well as another share buyback among other things, to again publish a shareholder\nintegral part of this programme.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, the programme to the value of up to €3 billion intended by letter before the Annual General Meeting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "up to €3 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "This includes\nmembers of the Supervisory Board are regularly the Board of Management as well as the general share comments on strategy, the share buyback programme,\ninformed about the regulatory environment relevant to buyback policy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, the Supervisory Board the proposed dividend, the Supervisory Board, the\ntheir work on the Supervisory Board and other legal discussed the results of the self-assessment carried Board of Management’s remuneration and legal issues.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "developments affecting them.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "out in the 2023 financial year, which confirmed very\ngood professional cooperation characterized by a high At its meeting on 24 April 2024, the Supervisory Board\ndegree of trust between members of the Supervisory was informed of current legal issues.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2023 financial year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "24 April 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "It welcomed the\nBoard and with the Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the\nBoard",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, decision by the U.S. Department of Justice to end the\nthe Board of Management provided information on the criminal investigations against the company in relation\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 12\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nto diesel emissions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the U.S. Department of Justice",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management then the Board of Management provided information on the as road safety), going into particular detail on the\nprovided information on the measures to mitigate expansion of the high-power charging network in the management of sustainability topics.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "cyber security risks, including in the area of production.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "United States as well as the opening of the new\nThe Supervisory Board also dealt with the refocusing competence centre for the development of innovative As part of the meeting held on 11 December 2024, the\nand operationalization of the sustainable business high-power battery cells and new manufacturing Supervisory Board dealt with and approved the busi-\nstrategy, going into detail in particular on the processes (eCampus) in the Stuttgart-Untertürkheim ness planning (Mercedes-Benz Business Planning)\npreliminary results of the double materiality assess- plant.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "United States",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "11 December 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Stuttgart",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Business Planning",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Finally, the Supervisory Board was informed of based on comprehensive documentation and discussed\nment carried out based on the European Sustainability current legal issues as well as the status of the existing opportunities and risks in this context.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the European Sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In\nReporting Standards (ESRS).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Reporting Standards",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "ESRS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, the fulfilment of the settlement concluded with the US addition, the Supervisory Board decided on changes to\nSupervisory Board decided on a series of measures authorities in relation to diesel emissions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "the Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Other items on the agenda\nthat required its approval. included the Board of Management’s report on the\nIn September 2024, the Supervisory Board convened in current financial status, volumes and prices of vehicle\nAt the virtual Annual General Meeting held on 8 May Beijing for a strategy meeting lasting several days.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "September 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "8 May",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Beijing",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "several days",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The clusters of current as well as future portfolios of\n2024, the candidate suggested by the Supervisory meeting focused on discussing the strategic challenges, Mercedes-Benz Cars and Mercedes-Benz Vans as well\nBoard, Dr Doris Höpke, was elected as successor to in particular the challenges of the Chinese market, as the Supervisory Board’s resolutions on several\nDr Bernd Pischetsrieder, who left the body at the end which is of particular relevance to the company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Cars",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Vans",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Doris Höpke",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Bernd Pischetsrieder",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "measures subject to its approval.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, the\nof the Annual General Meeting.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, I was re-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Involving the responsible managers from Germany and body dealt with the Board of Management’s report on\nelected early as a member of the Supervisory Board, China, the members of the Supervisory Board and the the development of current as well as concluded\neffective from the end of the 2025 Annual General Board of Management discussed in a constructive and acquisitions and cooperations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the end of the 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "General Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, the\nMeeting.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "At the Supervisory Board meeting that took open dialogue how Merecdes-Benz would position Supervisory Board was informed of the sustainability\nplace following the Annual General Meeting, I was itself to face existing and new challenges and which reporting, in particular on the important impacts, risks\nelected as successor to Dr Bernd Pischetsrieder as opportunities should be made use of.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Merecdes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Dr Bernd Pischetsrieder",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "An integral and opportunities (IROs) which were determined as\nchairman of the Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, elec- component of the discussions included sustainability part of the materiality assessment.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "tions were also held on committee appointments.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "aspects as well as the perspective of the capital\nmarket.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board also used the trip to Further topics in the meeting included remuneration,\nAt the end of July 2024, the Supervisory Board met for Beijing to meet important business partners as well as corporate governance issues and legal matters.\nanother meeting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the end of July 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Beijing",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Together with the Board of Manage- representatives of important Chinese companies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Manage-",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In the In particular, the Supervisory Board, together with its\nment, the Supervisory Board discussed the business context of the regular ESG reporting, the Board of legal experts, dealt in detail with the question of any\ndevelopment and the results for the first half of the Management also reported on the operationalization of potential liability of Members the Board of Manage-\nyear in detail.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the first half",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Manage-\n",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board went into detail the six focus areas of the sustainable business strategy ment regarding the diesel emissions issue.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Super-\non the product strategy as well as the Mercedes-Benz (decarbonization, resource utilization and circular visory Board agreed with the findings of its legal\noperating system MB.OS.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Super-",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, it approved economy, employees, human rights, digital trust as well experts and the recommended resolution from the\nproduct projects that required its approval.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Moreover, Legal Affairs Committee",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Legal Affairs Committee",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "and concluded that there are\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 13\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nno claims against any of the Members of the Board of which is to be submitted to the General Meeting for Furthermore, the committee received the reports from\nManagement who had been on the Board since 2005.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Annual Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the General Meeting for Furthermore",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2005",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "the units Corporate Audit, Compliance and Legal.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Corporate Audit",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The\nreports from Corporate Audit included reviews and\nFurthermore, the Supervisory Board received reports The Audit Committee held six meetings in the year findings related to ESG and the reports from Legal\non the status of anti-trust matters and the progress of 2024.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Corporate Audit",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Five meetings were held in person, with the covered the current status of important legal proceed-\nthe review of potential responsibilities in this context.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "option of participation in virtual form or via telephone, ings, including anti-trust proceedings as well as\nand one meeting was held as a video conference.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "proceedings in relation to diesel emissions.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition,\nWork in the Committees The Chairman of the Supervisory Board attended all the Audit Committee received regular reports on\nThe Supervisory Board has set up five committees.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "meetings as a permanent guest.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Other permanent possible violations of rules, which employees and\nThese are the Presidential Committee, the Audit participants, in compliance with the statutory external parties reported to the BPO (Business &\nCommittee, the Legal Affairs Committee, the Nomina- requirements, were the Chairman of the Board of People Protection Office) whistle-blowing system.\ntion Committee and the Mediation Committee.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Presidential Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Audit",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the BPO (Business &\nCommittee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Legal Affairs Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Nomina-",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of People Protection Office",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "tion Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Mediation Committee",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Management, the members of the Board of Manage-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Manage-",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Audit Committee dealt with issues of accounting,\nchairs of the various committees provided the ment responsible for Finance and Controlling and for financial reporting and non-financial reporting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Finance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In so\nSupervisory Board’s plenary meetings with detailed Integrity, Governance & Sustainability, and the doing, the draft version of the law on the implemen-\nreports on the work of the committees.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Integrity, Governance & Sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "You can find representatives of the auditor.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The heads of specialist tation of Directive (EU) 2022/2464 regarding corporate\ndetailed information on the tasks of the committees of departments such as Accounting, Corporate Audit, sustainability reporting, the status of the materiality\nthe Supervisory Board in the Declaration on Corporate Compliance and Legal also provided information on assessment and the resulting impacts, risks and\nGovernance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022/2464",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Corporate Audit",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "individual items on the agenda.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Regular executive opportunities (IROs) were dealt with.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Taking into\nsessions also took place with the auditor without the account audit quality indicators, the Audit Committee\nThe Presidential Committee held two meetings in the presence of the Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Presidential Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Audit reviewed the quality, qualification and the indepen-\npast financial year.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Both meetings were held in person, Committee audited and discussed the Annual Financial dence of the auditor.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Moreover, the committee\nwith the option to take part virtually or by telephone.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In Statements, the Consolidated Financial Statements and discussed the appropriateness, effectiveness and\nparticular, the Committee discussed personnel matters the Combined Management Report, including the Non- functionality of the risk management system, the\nand succession planning for appointments to the Board Financial Declaration of Mercedes-Benz Group AG and internal review system and the compliance manage-\nof Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Consolidated Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Combined Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board Financial Declaration",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, the Presidential Commit- the Group for the 2023 financial year, each of which ment system (including sustainability-related aspects).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Presidential Commit- the Group",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "2023 financial year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "tee discussed the acceptance by members of the had been issued with an unqualified audit opinion by It received, among other things, reports on the integra-\nBoard of Management of board positions at other the auditor, as well as the Remuneration report, the tion of sustainability topics into the existing risk\ncompanies and institutions, corporate governance Declaration on Corporate Governance, and the pro- management process (in particular ESG risks and\nissues, D&O insurance and the remuneration of the posal for the appropriation of profits.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board of Management of board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "D&O",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, in opportunities as well as the inside-out perspective),\nBoard of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The committee specifically the reporting period, the committee dealt in detail with the refocused sustainability business strategy, adjust-\naddressed the proposal for the further development of the interim financial reports for the first and third ments to ESG governance and the newly established\nthe remuneration system for the Board of Management, quarters of 2024 and the mid-year financial report Mercedes-Benz Sustainability Management Model.\n2024 as well as the results of the auditor’s review.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "third",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "mid-year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Sustainability Management Model",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "After the election of the auditor by the General\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 14\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nMeeting, the Audit Committee engaged the auditor to of any potential liability of Members of the Board of During the reporting period, there was no reason to\nconduct the annual audit and the auditor’s review of Management regarding the diesel emissions issue.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board\nMeeting",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of During the reporting period",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In convene the Mediation Committee.\nthe interim financial reports.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Mediation Committee",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, the Audit doing so, the Committee members, together with their\nCommittee agreed on the important audit issues and legal experts, analysed all circumstances from a factual Corporate governance and declaration of\nnegotiated the audit fees with the auditor.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Audit",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Committee",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Audit and legal perspective and agreed with the findings of compliance\nCommittee also engaged the auditor to conduct the the legal experts.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "compliance\nCommittee",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Committee concluded that there During the 2024 financial year, the Supervisory Board\naudit of the sustainability reporting as part of the are no claims against any of the Members of the Board continuously addressed the standards of good\nManagement Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024 financial year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, the committee dealt of Management, and submitted a corresponding corporate governance.\nwith the management of currency, energy and raw resolution recommendation to the Supervisory Board.\nmaterial risks and received the reports from the Head Following my election as chairman of the Supervisory\nof Taxes, the Data Protection Officer for the Group as As part of the settlement reached with the US Board in May 2024, as part of the ongoing investor\nwell as Human Rights Officer.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Head Following",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "Taxes",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Data Protection",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the US Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "May 2024",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "During the reporting authorities in connection with diesel emissions, the dialogue I conducted talks in September 2024 with\nperiod, the Audit Committee carried out a self-evalua- Committee was assigned specific tasks and decision- investors and proxy advisors on Supervisory Board-\ntion of its activities, on the basis of an extensive making competences with regard to the fulfilment of specific topics such as Board of Management\ncompany-specific questionnaire.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "September 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The positive results of the obligations assumed in the settlement.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The remuneration and the work and composition of the\nthis self-evaluation were presented and discussed in Committee also fulfilled these tasks in full and with Supervisory Board and its committees.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "the meeting on 19 February 2025.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "19 February 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "A basic need for great care.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, the Committee received\nchange was not evident.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Committee",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Individual ideas and reports on the status of anti-trust matters and the In July 2024, the Supervisory Board agreed on\nsuggestions were discussed.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "July 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "progress of the review of potential responsibilities in measures to make the work of the committee more\nthis context.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "effective and to create additional room for strategic\nThe Legal Affairs Committee held three meetings in discussions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Legal Affairs Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "At the same time, the members of the\nthe year 2024.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the year 2024",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Two meetings were held in person, with The Nomination Committee held two meetings in the Supervisory Board agreed that they wanted to be\nthe option of participation in virtual form or via 2024 financial year, both of them as video conferences.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Nomination Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024 financial year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "available to the Board of Management even more as\ntelephone, and one meeting was held as a video The Committee specifically considered the recommen- sparring partners and to discuss existing risks more\nconference.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Committee",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In those meetings, the Committee was dations for the proposals of the Supervisory Board to intensively.\ninformed in detail about legal matters relating to the General Meeting regarding the election of share-\nemissions and cartels and discussed these matters in holder representatives to the Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In this In December 2024, the Supervisory Board adopted\nthe presence of the legal advisers of the Supervisory context, it was guided by the interests of the company, the regular 2024 Declaration of Compliance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "December 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "2024 Declaration of Compliance",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "It discussed the continuing further development taking all circumstances of the individual case into exceptions explained there, all recommendations of\nof the technical compliance management system, also account, and striving to fulfil the overall profile of the Code have been and are being complied with.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In\nwith respect to future technologies.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Following the requirements, along with the diversity concept and addition, the Supervisory Board agreed on adjustments\ncompletion of the analysis initiated by the Supervisory competence profile for the entire Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "to the overall requirements profile for the composition\nBoard, the Committee dealt in detail with the question\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 15\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nof the Board of Management and the Supervisory discussed at the Audit Committee meeting on 19 elected, the proportion of women on the shareholder\nBoard.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Annual Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "15",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "19",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "side will remain at 40%.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "40%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The gender quota would\nremain fulfilled both on the shareholder side and for\nIn the interests of good corporate governance, the For supervisory boards of listed companies subject to the Supervisory Board as a whole.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "members of the Supervisory Board of Mercedes-Benz codetermination and equal representation of share-\nGroup AG are required to disclose to the Supervisory holders and employees on the supervisory board, such Corporate governance at Mercedes-Benz Group is\nBoard as a whole any conflicts of interest, in particular as that of Mercedes-Benz Group AG, the German Stock explained in detail in the Declaration on Corporate\nthose that could arise as a result of an advisory or Corporation Act (AktG) prescribes a mandatory gender Governance.\nboard function with customers, suppliers or lenders of quota of at least 30% women and 30% men.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board of",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "share-\nGroup AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the German Stock",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Declaration on Corporate",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "Corporation Act",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "at least 30%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "30%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The quota\nMercedes-Benz Group AG or other third parties.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "third",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "is to be met by the Supervisory Board as a whole.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Changes in the Supervisory Board and\nthe Board of Management\nThere were no indications of actual conflicts of interest As of 31 December 2024, women make up 40% of Several members of the Board of Management were\nduring the 2024 financial year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "31",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "40%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024 financial year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "the shareholder side of the Supervisory Board of reappointed in the course of the financial year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the financial year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The\nMercedes-Benz Group AG with Liz Centoni, Dame Polly reappointment periods are in line with the Supervisory\nThe Supervisory Board regularly assesses how Courtice, Dr Doris Höpke and Professor Dr Helene Board’s guidelines on the appointment and reappoint-\neffectively the Supervisory Board and its committees Svahn, while the remaining 60% are men.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Liz Centoni",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Courtice",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Doris Höpke",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Helene Board",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Svahn",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "60%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "On the ment of members of the Board of Management.\nperform their duties.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In 2023, a comprehensive self- employee side, Nadine Boguslawski, Gabriela Neher,\nassessment of the Supervisory Board and its commit- Pia Simon and Monika Tielsch make up 40% women At its meeting on 21 February 2024, the Supervisory\ntees on the basis of an extensive questionnaire and and the remaining 60% are men.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Nadine Boguslawski",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Gabriela Neher",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Pia Simon",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Monika Tielsch",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "40%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "21 February 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "60%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Thus, the Supervisory Board reappointed Renata Jungo Brüngger as a member\nadditional interviews took place with the involvement Board as a whole also currently fulfils the statutory of the Board of Management of Mercedes-Benz Group\nof an external consultant.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Renata Jungo Brüngger",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management of Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management’s quota.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "On 1 January 2025, Ms Barbara Resch was AG with effect from 1 January 2025 for a further one-\nperspective was also included in this assessment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1 January 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Ms Barbara Resch",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1 January 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The appointed by the court as successor to Roman year term, and Britta Seeger with effect from 1 January\nresults of the audit, which the Supervisory Board dealt Zitzelsberger, who left the Supervisory Board on 31 2025 for a further five-year term.\nwith extensively at its meeting on 21 February 2024, December 2024.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Roman year",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Britta Seeger",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1 January",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Zitzelsberger",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "31 2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "five-year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "21 February 2024, December 2024",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Since this point in time, 50% women\nconfirm that the members of the Supervisory Board and 50% men belong to the Supervisory Board on the At the virtual Annual General Meeting on 8 May 2024,\ncooperate very effectively and professionally with one employee side.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "50%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "50%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "8 May 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "the candidate proposed by the Supervisory Board,\nanother and with the Board of Management and do so Dr Doris Höpke, was elected to the Supervisory Board\non a basis of great trust.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Doris Höpke",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "At its meeting on 19 February 2025, on the recommen- as the successor to Dr Bernd Pischetsrieder, who left\ndation of the Nomination Committee, the Supervisory the body at the close of the Annual General Meeting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "19 February 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Dr Bernd Pischetsrieder",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Nomination Committee",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In\nThe Audit Committee also conducted a self-evaluation Board decided to propose to the 2025 General Meeting addition, I was re-elected early to the Supervisory\nof its activities on the basis of a comprehensive to re-elect Ben van Beurden, Liz Centoni, Timotheus Board, effective from the end of the 2025 Annual\ncompany-specific questionnaire in 2024.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Audit Committee",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "General Meeting",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Ben van Beurden",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Liz Centoni",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Timotheus Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the end of the 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The positive Höttges, Olaf Koch and Prof Dr Helene Svahn to the General Meeting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Höttges",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Olaf Koch",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Prof Dr",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Helene Svahn",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the General Meeting",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In the Supervisory Board meeting that\nresults of this self-assessment were presented and Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "If the proposed candidates are re- took place following the Annual General Meeting, I was\nAnnual Report 2024 | Mercedes-Benz Group 16\nTo Our Shareholders Combined Management Report Declaration on Corporate Governance Consolidated Financial Statements Further Information\nReport of the Supervisory Board\nelected as successor to Dr Bernd Pischetsrieder as responsibility for the ‘Integrity, Governance & and issued with an unqualified audit opinion.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Annual Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "16",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Dr Bernd Pischetsrieder",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the ‘Integrity, Governance &",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In\nchairman of the Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "In addition, Sustainability’ division from Renata Jungo Brüngger, addition, the sustainability reporting was subject to a\nelections were also held on committee appointments.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Renata Jungo Brüngger",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "who will be leaving the Board of Management on voluntary audit to obtain limited assurance, whereby\n31 October 2025.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "31 October 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board would like to individual disclosures were checked with reasonable\nAt the end of 31 May 2024, Roman Romanowski left the thank the very esteemed members of the Board of assurance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the end of 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Roman Romanowski",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of assurance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The audit was provided with a\nSupervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The court appointment of his Management Sabine Kohleisen, Renata Jungo Brüngger corresponding audit opinion.\nsuccessor, Sebastian Fay, was effective as of 1 June and Hubertus Troska, who are leaving the Board in the\n2024.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Management Sabine Kohleisen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Renata Jungo Brüngger",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Sebastian Fay",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1 June",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Hubertus Troska",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Pia Simon, the successor to Dr Frank Weber who course of the 2025 financial year, for their willingness In a meeting of the Supervisory Board on 19 February\nalso left the Supervisory Board at the end of 31 May to hand over their respective areas of responsibility to 2025, the preliminary key figures of the 2024 company\n2024, took up office as his elected replacement their successors before their own contracts end, thus and Consolidated Financial Statements, the Combined\nmember effective as of 1 June 2024.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Pia Simon",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dr Frank Weber",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "2025 financial year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "19 February",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the end of 31 May",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Consolidated Financial Statements",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1 June 2024",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "enabling the changes to the Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Management Report including the sustainability\nreporting 2024, as well as the preliminary proposal to\nAt the Supervisory Board Meeting on 11 December At the end of 31 December 2024, Roman Zitzelsberger the 2025 General Meeting for the appropriation of\n2024, the Supervisory Board decided on changes to left the Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board Meeting",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "11 December",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the end of 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Roman Zitzelsberger",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The court appointment of profits were discussed and noted with approval in the\nthe Board of Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board his successor Barbara Resch took place with effect presence of representatives of the auditor.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Barbara Resch",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The\nappointed Mathias Geisen as a member of the Board of from 1 January 2025.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mathias Geisen",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of from",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1 January 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "Supervisory Board determined that there were no\nManagement of Mercedes-Benz Group AG for a term of objections to their publication.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "The preliminary key\nthree years, effective as of 1 February 2025.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "three years",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1 February 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2024,
    "sentence": "At the Supervisory Board Meeting on 19 February 2025, figures for the 2024 financial year and the preliminary\nAs of 1 March 2025 he took over responsibility for the based on a corresponding recommendation from the proposal for the appropriation of profits were\n‘Marketing & Sales’ division from Britta Seeger.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board Meeting",
