[
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "aera egami muminim aera egami mumixam Flexible height of the images lower edge Sustainability Report 2021 Mercedes-Benz Group Sustainability Report 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "aera egami",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "muminim aera egami",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group FOREWORD MAGAZINE 6 We focus on our customers 13 We connect with science 22 We are changing our working environment 27",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group FOREWORD MAGAZINE",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "22",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "27",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Our strategy is set in place 36 Art and culture accompany our transformation 43",
    "entities": [
      [
        "36",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "43",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Our investors focus on ESG criteria 51 We learn from our stakeholders 61 We rethink mobility policy ESG REPORTING 72 Sustainable corporate governance 93 Integrity and compliance 109 Data responsibility 119 Partnerships 129 Climate protection 154 Air quality 162 Resource conservation 183 People 218",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "51",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "61",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "72",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "93",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "109",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "119",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "129",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "154",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "162",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "183",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "218",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Sustainable urban mobility 226 Traffic Safety 240 Human rights 259 Social commitment APPENDIX 269",
    "entities": [
      [
        "226",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Traffic Safety",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "240",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "259",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "APPENDIX 269",
        "LAW"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "About this report 274 Calculation and documentation of CO emissions\n\n275 KPMG auditor’s report 278 GRI Index 279 UN Global Compact 282 Glossary 289 Imprint\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "274",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "275",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "KPMG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "278",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "279",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "UN",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "282",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "289",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Foreword electro mobility, for example, we must also accelerate the expansion of green infrastructure - a very demanding task that governments, energy suppliers and car manufacturers can only solve by working together.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Foreword",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We’re also making our contribution: Mercedes me Charge, for example, is already one of the world’s largest charging networks with access to some 700,000 charging stations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Charge",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "some 700,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "By adding additional markets and charging station operators, this network is growing steadily.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Working with our partners, we are participating in its further expansion.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At the same time, we are increasingly using our own systems and buildings to Dealing with climate change is one of the greatest generate sustainable electricity from solar power.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "challenges in human history.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "That’s why it’s best, in this Much can be achieved when we pull together across transformation to increased sustainability, that we’re no company and industry boundaries.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "That is why we comlonger discussing the “if” but the “how.”",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In doing so, we ply with international agreements in everything we do shouldn’t first think of problems, bans or sacrifices, but and are clearly committed to initiatives such as the UN rather of the opportunity to keep our planet worthy of Global Compact.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "UN",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Global Compact",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "habiting and to promote social progress and prosperity.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It is part of our corporate responsibility to optimally poWith that in mind we are using our full strength to drive sition ourselves structurally for the future.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To do so we our transformation forward.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With “Ambition 2039,” we took a historic step forward last year:",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ambition 2039",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "last year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Out of the former set our course towards CO neutrality for our entire Daimler we formed two strong, independent companies\n\ncompany in 2019.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Daimler",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Last year we decided to once again in Daimler Truck and Mercedes-Benz.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Last year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Daimler Truck",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This enables us to significantly accelerate down the road to an emis- concentrate more fully on our respective customers and sion-free and software-driven future.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We will invest their technological requirements in the future and to some 60 billion euros in this effort by 2026.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "some 60 billion euros",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "2026",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "further accelerate our transformation to sustainability.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We want our products to be fully electric by the end Sincerely, of this decade wherever market conditions allow.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "this decade",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With our new EQA, EQB, EQE and EQS we introduced four all-electric models in 2021 alone.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EQB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "And our electric product offensive continues – across all our brands.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We are encouraged by the strong positive feedback from our customers, which is equally reflected in our strong sales Ola Källenius numbers: In 2021 we sold nearly twice as many electric Chairman of the Board of Management of Mercedes-Benz Group AG cars and vans as in the previous year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ola Källenius",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management of Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the previous year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "However, when it comes to promoting sustainability, it’s not solely about products.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It’s also about the big picture.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In order to further advance the spread of\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Foreword digital development and interdisciplinary cooperation that make us both faster and more efficient.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Foreword",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The holistic approach to Vision EQXX is also a symbol of our efforts to become climate-neutral along our entire value chain.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Vision EQXX",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Production in our own plants will be CO\n\nneutral as early as 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "as early as",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We have also made carbon dioxide emissions a key award criterion in our purchasing.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Suppliers, who account for around 90 percent of our annual purchasing volume, have already agreed to only supply us with CO neutral products in the future.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "around 90 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "What is the drivetrain of the future?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This question has Rarely have we set ourselves more ambitious goals at been on our minds – and not just since the historic Mercedes-Benz than we do today.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "today",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This is how we want realignment of our company, but since our founder to be a driving force for a good future.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "fathers invented the automobile 136 years ago.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "136 years ago",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At Mercedes-Benz we have a clear answer: Innovation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Sincerely, Today, this is particularly true when it comes to sustainability.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Today",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Innovation is the key to ensure that future generations can live well on our planet.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To this end, we are not only completely gearing our product range to electric driving – we are also changing the way we develop our vehicles.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Markus Schäfer Member of the Board of Management of Mercedes-Benz Group AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Markus Schäfer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management of Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Chief Technology Officer, Development & Procurement",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Development & Procurement",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We presented tangible evidence of this at the beginning of 2022 in our Vision EQXX.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Vision EQXX",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It’s an electric car pushing the boundaries and exploring options for future production vehicles.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It is designed down to the last detail for maximum range and efficiency.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With a comparatively small and light battery, our technology showcase will be capable of exceeding 1,000 kilometers on a single charge.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "exceeding 1,000 kilometers",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To accomplish this, we pursued a holistic approach, from the high-tech drivetrain to optimized aerodynamics and bionic lightweight structures.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We also set out to achieve as much as possible in terms of environmental compatibility.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "That’s why, for example, we use new materials obtained from cactus fibers and mushroom mycelium.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The important thing is that this car is not merely a show car.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It comes out of a technology program from which we learn to advance our series production.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This includes new forms of\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Foreword Specifically, that means we do not want to shift any problems to other parts of the world – such as in the extraction of raw materials for our electric vehicles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Foreword Specifically",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We only want to offer products that have been manufactured without human rights violations.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To this end, we are further developing our Human Rights Respect System, with which we can meet central regulatory requirements at an early stage.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Human Rights Respect System",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Our declaration of principles for social responsibility and human rights, which was adopted in the 2021 reporting year, also contributes to this end.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021 reporting year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With the high-reaching goals of our “Ambition 2039,” We employ governance instruments of this kind for we at Mercedes-Benz are clearly committed to climate- other sustainability issues.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ambition 2039",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The data compliance manneutral mobility.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "But we also aim to be a driving force agement system is becoming increasingly important to for a better future beyond our own value chain.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "our ambition to “Lead in Car Software.”",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Lead in Car Software",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "When using AI or automated driving, we also take ethical requirements In November 2021, for example, we were the only Ger- into account.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "November 2021",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "And we’ve done so with success: We were man car manufacturer to sign the “COP26 Declaration the first manufacturer in the world to receive an interon Zero-Emission Cars and Vans” at the world climate nationally valid system approval for highly automated conference in Glasgow.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Zero",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Glasgow",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We are convinced: Only through driving.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "collective action by governments, business and civil society can we achieve the goals of the Paris climate Our corporate principles and our code of conduct, agreement.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "which was awarded top marks1 in the reporting year, help us to do the right thing.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "marks1",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the reporting year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Sustainability and Integrity That is why we not only accelerated from “electric-first” are the central guidelines in the daily work of our more to “electric-only” in this past year, but also further than 170,000 employees.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "this past year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "170,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "They play the decisive role in intensified the exchange with our stakeholders.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In our the sustainable transformation of Mercedes-Benz - our Advisory Board for Integrity and Sustainability, in the “how” to master what is perhaps the greatest challenge Sustainability Dialogue and as part of our membership in human history.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz - our Advisory Board for Integrity and Sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Dialogue",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "in organizations such as the World Business Council for Sustainable Development, we use external feedback to Sincerely, position ourselves even more sustainably.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the World Business Council for Sustainable Development",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In terms of sustainable transformation, we aim to create added value for all stakeholders in the spirit of ESG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We have therefore aligned our sustainable business strategy with the Sustainable Development Goals of the Renata Jungo Brüngger UN.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Sustainable Development Goals of the Renata Jungo Brüngger UN",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For us, environmental, social and economic respon- Member of the Board of Management of Mercedes-Benz Group AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management of Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Integrity & Legal Affairs sibility are inextricably linked.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Integrity & Legal Affairs",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "During the reporting year, the trade magazine “Der Compliance Manager” took a close look at the codes of conduct of the DAX-40 companies and evaluated them in depth.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the reporting year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Our Integrity Code received top marks in this assessment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Integrity Code",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We focus on our customers Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We focus on our customers Our customers have the floor Our most important task in the transition to electric mobility is to inspire the change with convincing luxury products.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With Mercedes-EQ, we offer our customers more than just a unique electric driving experience.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-EQ",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We asked some of them how they’re experiencing this new Mercedes-Benz world, why they’ve switched to an EQ model and how important sustainable mobility is to them.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EQ",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For me as a customer… “ ...Mercedes-Benz is a perfect metaphor of society’s development and the representation of balancing force of the world to achieve a more sustainable life.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mobility is giving us a glimpse of eternity through which we should live the best sustainable life as possible.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Li Minguo\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Li Minguo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We focus on our customers At Mercedes I decide… “ ...how I allow my data to be used, and what I either do or don’t regulate electronically.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Andreas Fuss I experience electromobility… “ ...as the fire-new EQ model that has struck me with its splendid automotive electric luxury.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Andreas Fuss",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "EQ",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The longer it stays by your side, the better it gets to know you and your needs, like a boon companion that you have known for years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Gong Li\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Gong Li",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We focus on our customers To make progress and improvement to be the best… “ ...you continuously have to challenge yourself in every detail.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With its shift to electric mobility, Mercedes-Benz is making great effort on social responsibility and customer care.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For me as a customer, transparency means… “ ...being able to rely on verifiably fair and environmentally friendly journeys, all the way from production to recycling.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Jörg Bernicken\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Jörg Bernicken",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We focus on our customers I drive an EQC* because… “ ...a sustainable future begins in the present.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "4MATIC: NEDC: combined electrical consumption: 21.9 – 19.4 kWh/100 km; combined CO emissions: 0 g/km.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NEDC",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "21.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "19.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "0 g/km",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Electricity\n\nconsumption was determined on the basis of Commission Regulation (EC) No. 692/2008.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Commission Regulation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EC",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Dr Jana Michel\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Jana Michel",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We focus on our customers Wordless but straight to the point As the saying goes, a picture says more than a thousand words.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Wordless",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "more than a thousand",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In a somewhat offbeat interview, Bettina Fetzer, Chief Communications and Marketing Officer at Mercedes-Benz, shows there’s a grain of truth in this.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Bettina Fetzer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Without using any words, she shows clearly what we’ve already achieved on our path toward CO\n\nneutrality.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "What’s your facial expression when you’re going from 0 to 100 in 4.3 seconds in the EQS (EQS 580 4MATIC, WLTP combined electric energy consumption: 21.3 – 18.2 kWh/100 km; CO emissions: 0 g/km)1?\n\n2.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "0 to 100",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4.3 seconds",
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "WLTP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "21.3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "18.2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "kWh/100 km",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "km)1",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Production of the EQS is CO\n\nneutral as well.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "What’s the situation regarding recycling?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "How would you rate the recyclability of a Mercedes-Benz car on a scale of one to ten?2 1 Electrical consumption and range were determined on the basis of Regulation (EU) 2017/1151. 2",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "one to ten?2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2017/1151",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For details please see chapter Recycling- keeping the end in mind from the very start\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We focus on our customers 3.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "How can customers charge and pay in an uncomplicated way all across Europe?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "What material used in the EQS surprised you?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "You are one of the people responsible for the external image of the world’s most valuable luxury automotive brand.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Do you sometimes take a break in the EQS (EQS 450+, WLTP combined electric energy consumption: 19.8 – 15.7 kWh/100 km; CO emis sions: 0 g/km)1 within its range of up to 784 kilometres?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "450+",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "WLTP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "19.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "15.7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "kWh/100 km",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "km)1",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "up to 784 kilometres",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Bettina Fetzer has been Head of Marketing at Mercedes-Benz AG since November 2018.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Bettina Fetzer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "November 2018",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Effective as of 1 July 2021, Bettina Fetzer also became Head of Communications at Mercedes-Benz AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1 July 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Bettina Fetzer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Head of Communications",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This unit encompasses global corporate communications as well as global communications for cars and vans.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In this position, Fetzer generates momentum for the brand and is responsible for the global positioning of Mercedes-Benz and its products inside and outside the company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Fetzer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "She studied International Business Administration in Landshut and Cambridge and has been working in various positions within the company since 2004.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "International Business Administration",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Landshut",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Cambridge",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2004",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "1 Electrical consumption and range were determined on the basis of Regulation (EU) 2017/1151.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2017/1151",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We connect with science Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We connect with science Two perspectives on the path to climate neutrality In 2021, the publication of the first part of the Sixth IPCC Assessment Report has made it clear: the world must act now to limit the consequences of climate change.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sixth",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "IPCC Assessment Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At Mercedes-Benz, scientific findings and the dialogue with experts are the basis for the necessary technological progress.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This is the only way we can achieve our goal of CO neutrality by 2039.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2039",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Prof Dr Dr Felix Ekardt Jana Krägenbring-Noor Head of the Research Centre for Head of the Corporate Environmental Sustainability and Climate Policy Protection and Energy Management in Leipzig and Berlin department at Mercedes-Benz AG Facts only influence our We’ve achieved a lot more than behaviour to a limited extent was conceivable at the beginning Prof Dr Dr Felix Ekardt is Head of the Research Centre",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Prof Dr",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Felix Ekardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Jana Krägenbring-Noor Head",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Research Centre for Head",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Corporate Environmental Sustainability and Climate Policy Protection",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Energy Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Leipzig",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Berlin",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Felix Ekardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Research Centre",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The publication of the first part of the Sixth IPCC report in for Sustainability and Climate Policy in Leipzig and Berlin 2021 used hard facts on the status quo of climate change and Professor of Public Law and Philosophy of Law at the and possible subsequent scenarios to make it clear: University of Rostock.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sixth",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability and Climate Policy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Leipzig",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Berlin",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Professor of Public Law and Philosophy of Law",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "University of Rostock",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "He has been researching in matters Society, business and governments need to act!",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Society",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In this of law, ethics, politics, and transformation conditions of name contribution Jana Krägenbring-Noor, Head of Corposustainability for 25 years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Jana Krägenbring-Noor",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Corposustainability",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "25 years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Felix Ekardt is active in polit- rate Environmental Protection and Energy Management, ical consulting and is the author of numerous specialist reveals what is needed for the sustainable transformation articles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Felix Ekardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Environmental Protection and Energy Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In 2021, together with the lawyer Dr Franziska of an internationally operating company — and why there’s Hess, he also obtained the noted decision of the German no alternative to a sustainable business strategy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Dr Franziska",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Hess",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Federal Constitutional Court on climate policy1.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Federal Constitutional Court",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "policy1",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We asked him for his opinion on key issues in the climate debate.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "When I look into the sunset on vacation at the Baltic Sea and watch the seabirds along the horizon it not only A frequently used argument against intensified energises me, but makes me aware of how important climate protection is that it will place a dispro-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Baltic Sea",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "it is to keep nature and people in harmony.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With this portionate burden mainly on people with low goal in mind, I start my laptop in the morning and am incomes.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the morning",
        "TIME"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "What’s your opinion?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "happy that I can help to shape sustainable action at a This is all to do with the fact that the opportuni- company like Mercedes-Benz.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "About four years ago, my ties for freedom between the generations must be team and I were given an important task: to create an 1 1 BvR 2656/18, 1 BvR 288/20, 1 BvR 96/20, 1 BvR 78/20\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "About four years ago",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "288/20",
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "96/20",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "78/20",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We connect with science balanced more fairly.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Federal Constitutional even greater awareness within the company of how our Court confirmed this in its ruling.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Federal Constitutional",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Court",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The effect of cli- actions affect the environment.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Sustainability should be mate protection on the balance of social equality is at the centre of business, and it’s not just a matter of more good than bad, because climate change itself putting locally emission-free automobiles on the road.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "would cause a much more problematic distribution of social goods than even the most radical climate Sustainability must be the guiding protection policy.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "principle for every employee’s actions What does the term “climate justice” mean to you?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In your opinion, who has to create a balance in In fact, a sustainable business strategy means intewhose favour?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "grating sustainability into all processes along the value When it comes to climate protection, the freedom chain.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This is a huge task that can only be successful of those who produce and consume here and now if everyone participates.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "My team and I are working competes with the right to the elementary prerequisites intensely, as we always have, to keep things moving and of freedom: life, health and a subsistence income — serve as the driving force of the strategy and impleworldwide, and also for future generations.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The demo- mentation process.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In a way, asking the right questions cratic majority has some creative freedom in this area.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "has to become a part of the organisation’s DNA: how is Constitutional courts have the task of safeguarding cer- climate and environmental protection relevant for my tain limits as we weigh the alternatives.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Constitutional",
        "LAW"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This is precisely tasks, and what aspects do I have to keep in mind?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "How why Germany’s Federal Constitutional Court intervened, does this decision affect resource consumption and the because we are in the process of very quickly using up CO footprint?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Federal Constitutional Court",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Where can I also improve in ways that\n\nthe small remaining budget we still have for reaching are not measured by performance indicators?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We’ve the goal of limiting global warming to 1.5 °C.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1.5 °",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "already made big progress on these issues, and not just in vehicle development and production.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Following a complaint to the Federal Constitutional Court, the Federal Government must amend the German Climate Protection Act by the end of 2022 and define effective climate The EQS electric saloon is produced CO neutrally at Factory 56 in Sindelfingen.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Federal Constitutional Court",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Federal Government",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the German Climate Protection Act",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Factory 56",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Sindelfingen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "protection measures for the period after 2030.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2030",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "How would you categorise the results of the IPCC This highly dynamic process of change is increasingly with regard to climate justice and the automotive being influenced by investors who demand sustainindustry?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "One response to this was the first green Sustainability requires a lifestyle and an approach to bond in the amount of one billion euros, which the resource management that are viable in the long run Mercedes-Benz Group issued in September 2020.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "One",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "one billion euros",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "September 2020",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The and on a global scale.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In order to solve various environ- second green bond of the same amount followed in mental problems such as the climate crisis, loss of bio- March 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "second",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "March 2021",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The net proceeds from these issues are\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We connect with science diversity, distorted nitrogen and phosphorus cycles and used exclusively to fund green projects.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This enables the pollution of soil, air and waterways we have to leave investors to participate directly in the attainment of certain drivers of destruction behind us.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We need to the sustainability goals and at the same time ensures use zero fossil fuels and about 75 percent less livestock that we have the liquidity we need to make important farming and pesticides.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "zero",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "about 75 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "These problems would then be investments for the future.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The legally binding 1.5 °C limit set by the Paris Agreement implies that we must implement all of This is necessary because our efforts as a company are these requirements by the start of the 2030s all over embedded within a legal framework set by politics.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1.5 °",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Paris Agreement",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the start of the 2030s",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For the world and in all sectors, including the transportation example, the goals of the Paris Climate Agreement must sector.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Paris Climate Agreement",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Fossil fuel drive systems may no longer be used be implemented, so that targets and incentives are after that point.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Possible compensations for greenhouse set not only for individuals, but for society as a whole gas emissions such as bog or forest management don’t – because that’s the only way that the climate can be change that necessity.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This is because we need these effectively protected in the long term.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At the European compensations for residual emissions in areas such as level, car manufacturers for example are given fleet food production.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "European",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It should be noted that the goals of our Ambition 2039 go beyond these requirements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ambition 2039",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We want to become CO neutral by 2039 – the goal\n\nwe set ourselves in May 2019 with the aforementioned Ambition 2039 programme has since gained enormous momentum, both internally and externally.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2039",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "May 2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Ambition 2039",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "From my point of view we’ve made much more progress over the past two years than was originally thought possible.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the past two years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In my opinion, the decision of the Executive Board to set sustainability targets for all areas is the basis for this success.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Executive Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Environmental protection is being directly managed and put into practice in our daily work.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It summarises the most important findings on the current It makes me proud that we have in fact exceeded our state of climate change, causes and impacts.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "targets defined for 2021 in some areas.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For example, People always blame others we have succeeded in reducing the amount of cobalt in the cathodes of the EQS’ battery cells to less than Why do we find it so difficult to translate our ten percent – a significant improvement compared to knowledge about the harmful effects of fossil previous battery generations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ten percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Our procurement unit fuels and excessive meat consumption into also made great progress.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For example, Mercedes-Benz concrete actions? has agreed to purchase battery cells produced in a CO\n\nKnowledge of the facts and ethical values — in o ther neutral manner as part of its strategic partnerships with words, aspects of awareness — have only limited battery cell partners CATL, ACC and Farasis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "o",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "CATL",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ACC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Farasis",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Starting influence on our behaviour.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For members of the public, with the EQS, we will only procure CO neutral battery\n\npoliticians, managers and everyone else, other factors cells for our new all-electric passenger car models.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "are often more important — factors such as calculations This will save around 30 percent of the emissions from of self-interest, path dependencies, and the fact that battery production.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "around 30 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "the climate is a collective good that can’t be controlled by individuals.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Also important are people’s concepts of normality, which are often confused with ethical values.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It somehow seems “normal” to eat meat every day, fly to\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We connect with science Step 1: Taking stock of (life cycle) a holiday destination several times a year and become assessment more and more wealthy over time.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Perhaps emotional factors are the most important here: laziness, habit, mental avoidance, a tendency to make up excuses, But how can we know where the need for action is inability to imagine complexity — and especially the ten- particularly acute or where reduction measures are dency to scapegoat others.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Climate change is somehow especially effective?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To answer this question, our ultimately the fault of the Chinese or Donald Trump; as first step for all units is to take a close look at our for me, I’m completely blameless — even though here consumption.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Donald Trump",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "in Germany we have one of the world’s biggest climate footprints per capita.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In doing so, my team and I concentrate on how we can employ a holistic approach to improve the products’ environmental compatibility and reduce Is “green” consumption a legitimate way to make the environmental impact.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "If you want to permaa fair contribution to climate protection at the nently improve the life cycle assessment, you need individual level?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "permaa",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "to take a 360° view of the entire life cycle: What imSocial change takes place through the interaction of pact do the raw materials already have?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "imSocial",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "How much diverse players, all of whom are subject to the motivation energy is needed for production, how do the various factors I’ve just mentioned.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Politicians, members of the drivetrains influence the CO balance during the\n\npublic, lobbyists and journalists, who all depend on one use phase, and what effect does the use of reanother as if they were caught up in vicious circles, pop- cyclates have?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We can now evaluate all of this not ulate the political sphere.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In addition, the political sphere only manually, but also automatically, from the raw is interdependent with the sphere of production and material to practically the last screw, so to speak.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "consumption, which is ultimately populated by the same As a result, we know precisely what measures we people who in turn are interdependent on one another.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "have to take in order to improve climate neutrality, In other words, if we want to reset the framework for our enhance environmental compatibility and reduce consumption, success will depend on the interaction of resource consumption.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The life cycle assessment of many players.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "That’s because green consumption can the EQS, for example, shows that we are on the right mean a technological as well as a behavioural transfor- track from today’s perspective with our electric–only mation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "today",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Both will be necessary if we are to stay within the approach.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Calculated for the life cycle as a whole, 1.5°C limit.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1.5°",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In the interplay of change, we will need volun-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "the EQS’ CO balance is 80 percent better than that\n\ntary green consumption as well as political commitment of its combustion engine counterpart, given the EQS to a change of lifestyle and of economic activity.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "80 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "is charged with green electricity.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Compared to the conventional S-Class, the higher emissions from the production of the EQS are already offset after just 20,000 kilometres.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "just 20,000 kilometres",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A few years ago, we would have considered such figures to be merely visionary.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "A few years ago",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Keeping materials in circulation We also take a close look at the materials used in a vehicle.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Moreover, we take on responsibility for our supply chain even though we don’t pull all the strings here.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Our goal is to conserve valuable resources as well and to use as little of the primary raw materials An “unpacked” filling station in a supermarket – to slow down climate change, it is not enough to make production processes more efficient and environmentally friendly.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At Mercedes-Benz, we have therefore set Consumer behaviour must also change.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We connect with science Demanding and promoting ourselves the goal of increasing the use of recycled a different kind of politics materials to 40 percent by 2030.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "40 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With regard to plastics we’ve already made good progress: seat covers made of What exactly do you mean 100 percent recycled PET bottles, floor coverings made by a political commitment?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "100 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "PET",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "of processed fishing nets and fabric scraps instead of A different kind of politics is only going to be possible tufted velour.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Moreover, we are using cable ducts if we all demand it — so people should join political made of recycled household waste.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The EQS alone parties, join associations and join the demonstrations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "contains a total of 80 kilograms of resource-conserving Another prerequisite for a different kind of politics materials.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "80 kilograms",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "I was totally thrilled when I had the chance to is that as many people as possible show in their experience the Vision EQXX that we unveiled in January personal spheres how we can live and do business 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "January",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The vehicle’s interior, for example, contains many differently.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This kind of cooperative action is the materials that aren’t from animal origin.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "only way we can break through the various vicious circles in which all of the participants and spheres are In fact, 95 percent of a vehicle can be recycled today.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "95 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "today",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Referring to individual actors is pointless; However, as we progress towards a circular econthat would lead to the old question of which came omy, we have to bear in mind that the steel from first, the chicken or the egg.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "And it is by no means just recycled end-of-life vehicles today is generally not a matter of more factual knowledge and values.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "today",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "If we used to produce a new automobile, but rather for steel set the course within the political framework and in girders in a multi-storey building.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Although there is our personal activities for zero fossil fuels and less nothing wrong with this as such, it also means that the livestock farming and pesticides, these harmful fac- high-quality automotive alloys are tied up for another tors will disappear from the market either completely purpose.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "zero",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We want to get closer to the „closed loop“ or partially — through technological and behavioural in automobile production.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In the case of our high-volttransformations.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "age batteries, we attach great importance to recycling and reuse even before recycling.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For example, defective batteries are reprocessed for reuse in vehicles.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "What does the pathway toward this new normality look like to you?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "When a battery is no longer suitable for road use, it The central political toolbox has to start operating at is reused in a stationary energy storage unit in order the EU level.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Otherwise, problems would only be shifted to offset peaks in consumption in the electricity grid.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "If we establish an improved emis- Once this application likewise comes to an end, the sions trading system that covers all fossil fuels and also battery is recycled so that valuable raw materials can animal products and pesticides in a similar way, we be recovered.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "would make our reduction target more ambitious than it has been so far.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "If we close all the loopholes — and Minimising raw materials risks by if we do all this in 15 years at the most — we can still means of technological progress reach the binding global targets for the climate and the environment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "15 years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To round off this effort, the EU would have to work together with other countries that are moving Although recycling processes are already very along a similar pathway to introduce environmental tar- advanced, batteries contain valuable raw materials iffs against countries that are not participating in these that are sometimes critical.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "That’s why we want to measures.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "If that doesn’t happen, we would once again steadily reduce the amount of critical raw materials be shifting emissions to other countries.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Individuals will that are used per vehicle.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We design our vehicles then experience a temporary increase in the price of to be as resource-conserving and environmentally fossil fuels — effects that steer us toward technological friendly as possible over their entire life cycle.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "and behavioural transformation.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "If we target emissions In vehicle development we call this approach\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We connect with science trading with a goal of zero fossil fuels by around 2035, “Design for Environment”.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "zero",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2035",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Design for Environment",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This is why it’s all the fossil fuels will simply no longer be on the market at more important that the individual components are some point.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "analysed for their social and environmental risks before the first vehicle sketch is made.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The ESSENZ method that we developed in cooperation with the Less consumption and TU Berlin and other partners provides information climate-neutral products about the scope of the risks.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESSENZ",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "TU Berlin",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This method assesses, for example, how the raw material deposits are disOf course behavioural change also means that we tributed across the earth and whether their exploitahave to rethink our attitude toward consumption.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "disOf",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "tion could be associated with human rights risks.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "From a corporate perspective, would companies In the latter case, it supplements our Human Rights earn enough money from frugal consumers to Respect System.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Respect System",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The results help us to gain a clear secure jobs?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "picture of the potential environmental, economic Technological change creates growth and jobs.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "By and social risks that are associated with the use of contrast, less consumption may lead us into the post- a given raw material.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To date, the Mercedes-Benz growth society.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Companies, the job market and social Group has identified 24 such risk-related raw mainsurance will need new concepts to deal with this.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "24",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It terials, including cobalt and lithium, which we will makes sense for an individual company to orient itself only procure from certified sources in the future.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "toward emission-free services and products as soon as possible.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "However, our aspirations go far beyond industrywide standards.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In the medium-term, we want to reduce the amount of critical materials used by keeping second-use raw materials in the cycle for as long as possible.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "second",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At the same time, our engineers are working at full speed to increase the energy density of lithium-ion technology.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This enables us to reduce the proportion of critical raw materials used as well.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With success: The proportion of cobalt in the new generation of batteries has already been reduced to below ten percent.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ten percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Our goal is to completely change the material composition.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Whereas today’s battery cells contain comparable amounts of nickel, manganese and cobalt, most of the cobalt in The new EQXX convinces with a range of 1,000 kilometres and its 117 solar cells on the roof, which provide additional range, especially on sunny days.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "today",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "EQXX",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "1,000 kilometres",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "117",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "sunny days",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "the lithium-ion battery cells might soon be replaced by nickel.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In the future, we want to use post-lithiumFrom a climate-policy perspective, is it correct to ion technology to dispense with nickel and cobalt include transport in the national emissions trading completely in batteries.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "system – what do you think?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This is an initial step toward the expanded EU Achieving CO neutral production emissions trading system I’ve been describing.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EU Achieving CO neutral",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The\n\nwith green electricity biggest question for Germany’s new “traffic light” government is whether it will accept the EU’s proposals for intensified climate protection.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In order We have also taken a great leap forward in vehicle proto reach the 1.5°C target, the government would duction.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1.5°",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The use of sustainable energy increased further have to demand a further improvement of the EU in 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Since 2022, purchased electricity has come recommendations — for example, a more ambitious entirely from renewable sources, and production at the\n\nNachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We connect with science EU reduction goal and a more consistent closing of car and van plants of Mercedes-Benz is CO neutral\n\nloopholes in the emissions trading system.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "throughout the world.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "However, the availability of green electricity at all of our locations worldwide proved to be one of the key challenges.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "That’s because local condiFrom your perspective, what would a convincing tions often differ widely.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Green power wasn’t always narrative about the future look like?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "What role available or couldn’t easily be routed to the places could car manufacturers play in it?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We therefore sought dialogue with Car manufacturers will have to focus more strongly on the plants worldwide and drew up individual solutions leasing and sharing than on selling vehicles.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "They will for the green power supply.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In addition to the expanhave to become general providers of mobility servic- sion of photovoltaic systems, this was an essential key es.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In addition, all of their products and services must to achieving CO neutrality in production.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "However, we\n\nbe completely in the post-fossil-fuel category.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "can’t dispense with offsets completely yet.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In the future, we especially want to improve facilities that require a lot of process heat.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Prof Dr Dr Felix Ekardt is Head of the Research Unit Sustainability and Climate Policy in Leipzig and Berlin and Professor of Public Law and Law Philosophy at the What we can learn University of Rostock.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Prof Dr",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Felix Ekardt",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Research Unit Sustainability and Climate Policy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Leipzig",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Berlin",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Professor of Public Law and Law Philosophy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "University of Rostock",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "He has been researching law, ethics, politics and from ESG ratings transformation conditions of sustainability for 25 years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "25 years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In 2021, together with the lawyer Dr Franziska Heß, he obtained the decision of Germany’s Federal Constitutional Court on climate policy, which received worldwide Incidentally, whether our transformation is basically attention.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Dr Franziska Heß",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Federal Constitutional Court",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "on the right track is reflected in more than just our share price.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "ESG ratings are becoming increasingly important means of depicting our performance alongside the financial rankings and trend analyses of the capital market.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "These scores provide us with guidance because they let us know which topics are currently trending and where we have to make more rapid progress.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "That’s why investors consider ESG ratings to be an important indicator of whether our investments are sustainable.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "I’m very confident with regard to our company’s transformation.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This positive feeling greatly motivates me in my daily work.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For me, it’s very important that I work for a company that has made environmental protection its priority.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At Mercedes, we are driven by the goal of reconciling mankind and mobility with the environment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Knowing that we work hard to achieve our goals, I can take a deep breath during an evening walk with our four-legged friend in the woods and meadows and look forward to the next working day.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the next working day",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Jana Krägenbring-Noor is the Head of the Corporate Environmental Protection and Energy Management department.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Jana Krägenbring-Noor",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Corporate Environmental Protection and Energy Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "As a member of the Sustainability Competence Office, she coordinates the Group Sustainability Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Sustainability Competence Office",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Sustainability Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Her department covers the areas of sustainability, environmental protection, and energy management at Mercedes-Benz AG and is responsible for compliance with environmental and energy policy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Nachhaltigkeitsbericht 2021",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group Magazine .",
    "entities": [
      [
