[
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sustainability Report 2022\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nFOREWORD\nGOVERNANCE\n6 Stakeholder Perpectives\n12 Sustainable corporate governance\n42 Integrity and compliance\n60 Data responsibility\n69 Partnerships\nENVIRONMENT\n82 Stakeholder Perpectives\n90 Climate protection\n117 Air quality\n125 Resource conservation\nSOCIAL\n145 Stakeholder Perpectives\n152 People\n188 Sustainable urban mobility\n195 Traffic Safety\n209 Human rights\n227 Social commitment\nFACTS & FIGURES\n237 Report profile\n243 Calculation and documentation of CO emissions\n2\n245 KPMG auditor’s report\n248 GRI Index\n249",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "42",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "60",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "69",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "82",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Perpectives",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "90",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "117",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "125",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "145",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Perpectives",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "152",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "188",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "195",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Traffic Safety",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "209",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "227",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "237",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "243",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "245",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "KPMG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "248",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "249",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Glossary\n257 Imprint\nThis Sustainability Report also includes the content audited in the Non-Financial Declaration.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "257",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Imprint",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "the Non-Financial Declaration",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The relevant passages in this Sustainability Report are marked\nin blue font colour in the continuous text.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Audited graphs and tables are also referenced accordingly via footnotes.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Unless explicitly noted, this content was\naudited with reasonable assurance.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Unless marked with footnotes, graphs and tables have not undergone external audit, regardless of the colors used.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "2\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nForeword\nForeword\nDear Reader, points worldwide.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Dear Reader",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition, we will build up our own\nhigh-power charging network in North America, Europe,\nAccording to current forecasts, the global passenger China and other key markets.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "North America",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "car market is expected to exceed 91 million vehicles in\n2030 – around 25 percent more than in 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "91 million",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "around 25 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Our task at In order to conserve valuable resources, one of our\nMercedes-Benz is to meet this growing need for individu- major goals is the circular economy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In this regard, the\nal mobility in a sustainable way.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To achieve this, we have battery is an important factor for electric vehicles.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "That\ndefined a clear path on which we have reached important is why we are building our own battery recycling factory\nmilestones along our value chains in recent months.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "recent months",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "in Kuppenheim, where we will achieve a recycling rate\nof over 96 percent thanks to innovative technology.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Kuppenheim",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "over 96 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Many things are expected from\nMercedes-Benz – inside and In addition to sustainable products, we are increasingly\noutside our factory gates.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We want focused on sustainable production.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Since 2022, our own\nto live up to these expectations in a\nproducition sites are CO₂-neutral on the balance sheet.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This includes the\nambition of making our fleet of new By 2030, we want to cover more than 70 percent of the\npassenger cars net carbon-neutral energy demand in production with renewable ener-\nby 2039.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2030",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "more than 70 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "2039",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "By 2030, we plan to be\ngies – especially by expanding solar and wind energy at\naround halfway there.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2030",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To make\nfaster progress on climate our sites and concluding further corresponding power\nprotection, we need maximum purchase agreements.\ncommitment and even stronger\ncooperation between politics,\nCompelling products continue\nindustry and society.\nto be the core of our business: We\nnow offer at least one fully electric\nThe core of our business continues to be convincing model in every segment in which we\ncompete – from the compact EQA to\nproducts: we now offer at least one fully electric model\nthe spacious EQS SUV.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "at least one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EQA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "at least one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In order to\nin every segment we serve – from the compact EQA conserve valuable resources in the\nto the spacious EQS SUV.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EQA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EQS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "And that is well-received: in process, one of our major goals is\nthe circular economy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "That is why\n2022, more than twice as many customers opted for a\nalready during the development of\nvehicle from our electric brand Mercedes-EQ than in the our vehicles we use a “design for\nprevious year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-EQ",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "previous year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "circularity” approach.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "For example,\nwe already consider the recycling of\nour batteries during their\nWith our concept car Vision EQXX, we underlined development.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Vision EQXX",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "our claim to be the innovation leader in e-mobility:\nOn its record-breaking drive from Stuttgart to Silver-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Stuttgart",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Silver-",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It’s not only the demand for green energy that is in-\nstone, it covered over 1,200 kilometres on a single creasing, it’s also the demand for responsibly sourced\nbattery charge with an average consumption of just raw materials.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "over 1,200 kilometres",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This is why we work with the Canadi-\n8.3 kWh/100 km.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "8.3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "kWh/100 km",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "an government, for example.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Through direct contact\nwith raw material producers, we want to open up new\nIn order to attract even more people to electric cars in sources for important materials.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This gives us grea-\nthe long term, we also need a well-developed charging ter influence on sustainable supply chains and the\ninfrastructure.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Via Mercedes me Charge, our customers observance of human rights all the way to the mines.\nalready have access to around one million charging With our „Raw Materials Report“ we create more\n3\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Via Mercedes",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Charge",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "around one million",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nForeword\npublic transparency.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Additionally, tools like the “Human Beyond the boundaries of our company, education is\nRights Respect System” and our “Responsible Sourcing also a concern for us: we make donations to fund a\nStandards” help us a lot, which is why we encourage global fellowship programme that will provide know-\nour direct suppliers to comply with them.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "And with our ledge, coaching and scholarships to thousands of young\ngovernance and compliance structures, we ensure a people from around the world – in order to implement\nresponsible approach to future technologies – be it big innovative projects in the areas of environmental\ndata, automated driving or artificial intelligence.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "thousands",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "sustain ability and decarbonisation.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To raise the seed\nmoney for the programme, we auctioned the world’s\nAt Mercedes-Benz, we have\nmost valuable automobile – a Mercedes-Benz 300 SLR\nbeen conceiving sustainability\nholistically for many years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "many years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Uhlenhaut Coupé – for the record price of € 135 million.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Uhlenhaut Coupé",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "€ 135 million",
        "MONEY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Environmental protection, social\naspects and good corporate\nThere are many expectations towards Mercedes-Benz:\ngovernance must go hand in\nhand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "That is why on the path to Our customers expect first-class products.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Our colle-\nthe all-electric future we want agues expect future-proof jobs.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "agues",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Our shareholders expect\nclean supply chains and respect\nan appropriate return on their investment.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "And society\nfor human rights, from the raw\nmaterials mines all the way to our expects our commitment – inside and outside the fac-\ncustomers.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The right governance tory gates.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "tory",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "All these claims are legitimate.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The best way\nhelps us in this regard, for\nto deliver on them is to make our company economically\nexample, in the form of our\n\"Human Rights Respect System\".",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Human Rights Respect System",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "successful and sustainable in the long term.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "New technologies and business models also require At Mercedes-Benz, we are firmly committed to this.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "As an employer, we are responsible for more have set the course with our sustainable business stra-\nthan 170,000 colleagues from 145 nations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "170,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "145",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "On the following pages, you’ll read about the pro-\nin Germany alone, we will invest more than € 1.3 billion gress we made in 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "more than € 1.3 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We wish you an interesting read\nin the qualification, training and further education of and look forward to a constructive dialogue with you.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "our employees by 2030.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2030",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are also strengthening\ntraditional locations such as Stuttgart-Untertürkheim or\nBerlin-Marienfelde by developing them into centres of\nexcellence for future technologies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Stuttgart-Untertürkheim",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Berlin",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Yours\nOla Källenius Markus Schäfer Renata Jungo Brüngger\n4\nGOVERNANCE\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ola Källenius Markus Schäfer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Jungo Brüngger",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance • Stakeholder Perspectives\n“ESG risks on the radar”\nThe handling of ESG risks is increasingly coming into focus for many companies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\n",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This trend is accelerated by the growing due diligence obligations for companies.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "What does this mean for an international Group with complex supply chains?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In this\ninterview, Thilo Mangold, Head of the Group Risk and Opportunity Management,\ntalks about new perspectives and what they have to do with a speak up culture.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Thilo Mangold",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Risk and Opportunity Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Thilo Mangold\nMercedes-Benz AG\nMr Mangold, in order to manage risks, one denser due to the increasing integration of ESG issues\nmust first identify them.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Thilo Mangold",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mangold",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "What social risks does and an increasingly complex environment with numerous\nMercedes-Benz deal with?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "But that is only one side of the coin…\nThere are a number of them.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "First of all, a social risk\ndescribes the danger that events, developments, or What is the other side?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "First",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "actions hinder us from achieving our goals.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To prevent\nthis, we systematically address labour and human Where there are risks, there are also opportunities\nrights risks, for example.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We do this not only in all the for the Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In risk and opportunity management,\ncountries we operate in, but also in all areas of our we aim to identify and analyse these opportunities,\nvalue chain, from research and development, procure- where we can position ourselves as a ‘first mover’\nment, production, to sales and our financial services.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "to make a positive difference for our customers,\nSome risks arise from the fact that we, as an interna- employees, investors or other stakeholders in\ntional corporation, are subject to various, sometimes the future.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Through risk and opportunity manage-\nheterogeneous regulatory requirements.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Others are ment, we have the ability to identify changes in\ndirectly related to our sustainable business strategy.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "the Group's environment at an early stage, such as\nThrough forward-looking risk management, we ensure those affecting human rights, diversity or resource\nthe long-term performance and innovative strength conservation, and to develop appropriate responses\nof the Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It is crucial to take countermeasures for with foresight.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "That is an important building block\nthe identified risks as early as possible.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To sum up: The in creating additional value for both the Group itself\ntraditional risk map has changed.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It has become much and its stakeholders.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "6\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance • Stakeholder Perspectives\nHow does the handling of classic and ESG risks or area of human rights, the Social Compliance depart-\nopportunities differ?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\n",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Social Compliance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "ment, among others, provides important informati-\non via the Human Rights Respect System.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Human Rights Respect System",
        "LAW"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Risks\nThe first difference lies in how they are identified.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "arising from the shortage of skilled workers, on the\nTo stick with the metaphor of the risk map, it is other hand, would be reported primarily by Human\nimportant to be sensitive to the new topics and to Resource Management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Resource Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Behind each of these are\nview the entire environment with a 360-degree view.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "360-degree",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "different evaluation logics, yet everything is based on\nIt is about raising awareness of the expanded risk a uniform screening and reporting process.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "All of this\nmap in our organisation.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In this way, early warning serves our goal in central risk management: to bundle\nsignals can be detected as quickly as possible.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "At the and analyse information.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The assessment of external\nsame time, such assessment has also become more impulses also plays an important role.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To capture\ncomplex, since classical risks can usually be quanti- them, we have established a so-called \"risk radar\"\nfied more easily.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Putting a price tag on ESG risks that within the company, where we regularly work together\nshows the potential impact on the company's results with colleagues from the investor relations, external\nis much more difficult.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This is mainly due to the fact affairs or communications departments, for example.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "that cause and effect are often not clearly connec- There, early warning signals and current issues are\nted.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sometimes, effects occur in places that were not discussed, and it is examined what opportunities and\npreviously considered.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We have to deal with this and risks could arise for us.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The earlier we recognise deve-\nadjust our methods accordingly.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition, another lopments, the better.\nperspective must be taken into account in the\nassessment: the inside-out perspective.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It assesses\nhow a potential damage resulting from a risk would What possibilities do you see to promote early\naffect the Group's environment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Developing sensitivity for ESG issues throughout\nthe entire corporation is a central aspect.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are\nachieving this step by step, based on informati-\non accessible to everyone and a dialogue within\nthe Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "informati-",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "At the same time, we need people who\nopenly address risks.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This is what is meant when\nwe talk about a speak-up culture.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This culture is\nessential for risk management because it helps to\nensure that issues critical to success are discussed\nand assessed at an early stage.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Perhaps some may\nbe concerned about being seen as a sceptic, which\nis why it is not so easy to deal with risks in a trans-\nSensitivity to new topics in the risk landscape and a 360-degree view are important in order parent way.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "360-degree",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Part of our job in risk management is to\nto counteract risks at an early stage and take advantage of opportunities.\naddress these challenges and alleviate any con-\ncerns.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Our team therefore works across divisional\nMethodology is a good keyword.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Can such hete- and national boundaries to create a culture in which\nrogeneous risks as, for example, human rights we jointly assess risks at an early stage and take\nviolations and the shortage of skilled workers be countermeasures together early on as well.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "managed in one system at all?\nTo put it bluntly, we cannot afford to work with a Thilo Mangold\npatchwork.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Thilo Mangold",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We have a clearly defined process and an heads Group Risk and Opportunity Management at the Mercedes-Benz\nGroup.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group Risk and Opportunity Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz\nGroup",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Although he mostly deals with risks in his daily work, he still\nassociated IT system, a \"single source of truth\".",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The\ndescribes himself as a very optimistic and at the same time realistic\ninput for this comes from numerous sources.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "For the person.\n7\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance • Stakeholder Perspectives\n“We need to make sure that\nvalue is distributed equitably”\nInequalities of outcome and opportunity are jeopardizing social cohesion,\nmaking it more difficult to work together towards a net-zero future.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\n",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "net-zero",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "What\nshould businesses do to support equality, fairness and inclusion?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "And what\nrole can a luxury car manufacturer like Mercedes-Benz play in this respect?\nAn interview with James Gomme, head of WBCSD’s (World Business Council\nfor Sustainable Development) Business Commission to Tackle Inequality.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "James Gomme",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "WBCSD",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "World Business Council",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainable Development) Business Commission",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "James Gomme\nWBCSD\nMr. Gomme, income and wealth have always been So, while inequality has been a part of our societies over\nunequally distributed in societies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "James Gomme\nWBCSD",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Gomme",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "However, you say the ages, we have, I believe, now reached a critical junc-\nthat a critical point has now been reached.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The high level and structural nature of inequality,\ncoupled with several historic disruptions, make mounting\nFirst of all, while inequality between countries has been inequality a systemic and a business risk – one that af-\ndecreasing in recent decades, the wealth and income gap fects not only individual communities or companies, but\nwithin countries has widened.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "First",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "recent decades",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are now seeing wealth entire economies and societies.\ninequality as high as it has been since the early 1800s,\nwith the richest 10 percent of the population holding 75\npercent of all wealth, and the poorest 50 percent holding How does this imbalance relate to the climate crisis\njust 2 percent.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the early 1800s",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "10 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "75\npercent",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "50 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "just 2 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Historically, extreme inequality has been and the transformation aim to net-zero?\na precursor to instability, and today is no different.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "today",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "At the\nsame time, other emerging trends such as conflict, cli-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The planetary crisis that we are facing is having profound\nmate change, technological disruption, and the COVID-19 impacts on people.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It is undermining human health,\npandemic, for example, are all hitting the most vulnerable disrupting access to essential products and services,\nthe hardest and have the potential to further escalate the and destroying livelihoods.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The World Bank predicts\nscale of inequality around the world in the years ahead.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The World Bank",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the years ahead",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "that 132 million people could be pushed into extreme\n8\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "132 million",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance • Stakeholder Perspectives\npoverty by 2030, as a result of climate change if we do and productive.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\n",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "And then, there’s a key pillar of action\nnot take concerted action.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It will therefore not be possi- around jobs and economic opportunities.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Business\nble to tackle inequality without robust efforts to mitigate has to make sure that opportunities are available to\nand adapt to climate change.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "At the same time, it will everybody, regardless of their backgrounds, and that\nalso be impossible to address the climate emergency workers and those entering the workforce are empow-\nwithout putting people at the center of this agenda and ered with the right skills to thrive, both now and in the\nworking to ensure that the journey to a net-zero econo- future.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ered",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "net-zero",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Finally, there is also an urgent need to ensure\nmy creates a fairer, more prosperous future for all.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "that value and risk are distributed more equitably.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To-\nday, over a billion working people worldwide earn less\nWe must recognise that the transformation is going to than they need to afford a decent standard of living.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "profoundly impact workers, suppliers, communities, To tackle inequality and restore faith in our economic\nand consumers at the local and global level.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Compa- system, it is critical to ensure that work provides a path\nnies need to engage with governments and other sta- out of poverty and an opportunity for upward mobility\nkeholders to intentionally and collaboratively mitigate and prosperity for all.\nnegative impacts and to ensure a transition in which\neveryone can see opportunity.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "What responsibility do these topics imply for a\nluxury manufacturer like Mercedes-Benz?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "I think, there is a huge opportunity to redefine what\nluxury means, in terms of not only being the experi-\nence that the consumer has in relation to the product,\nbut also the assurance that this product has been\nproduced in a way that maximises positive social\nimpact throughout its value chain.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "That every com-\nponent of that product has been sourced or created\nin a way that has distributed value to a wide variety\nof global stakeholders, has enriched their lives and\nhas made a contribution to tackling inequality.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Our\nIf all stakeholder groups work together, a just transition can succeed.\nresearch at the BCTI (Business Commission to Tackle\nWhat can companies do to foster this scenario?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the BCTI (Business Commission",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Inequality) indicates that this is increasingly important\nfor consumers and moving forward could represent an\nThere are a number of key actions that business can important source of competitive advantage.\ntake to tackle inequality.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "First of all, corporate respect\nfor human rights should sit at the centre of everything.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "First",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It helps to ensure that human dignity moves to the Social inequality is often primarily viewed from\ncenter of how business gets done.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Social",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It reinforces a a risk perspective.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Do you also see opportunities\ncompany’s capacity to lift people out of poverty, impro- when it comes to tackling inequality and realizing a\nving the lives of the world's most vulnerable people.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "more just and inclusive society?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Following from that there is a role for business in terms While the business case for action to tackle inequa-\nof utilizing its innovation and capacity building to make lity is certainly about mitigating risk, it is also about\nessential products and services more accessible and building a world of opportunity in which companies\naffordable for consumers who are currently under- can thrive in the long-term.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Tackling inequality can\nserved.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Business has to explore new ways, perhaps in strengthen the operating environment by building\ncollaboration with government or through new blen- trust, enhancing social and political stability, and con-\nded finance mechanisms, to try and make sure that taining crises.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "There is also mounting evidence that\neveryone has access to what they need to be healthy it is an important driver for long-term, sustainable\n9\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance • Stakeholder Perspectives\nThe way the entire global business community is rallying behind net-zero commitments shows that the path can only be taken together.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\n",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This also applies to the path to social goals.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, as momentum builds force on Climate-related Financial Disclosure), and the\nbehind a shift in the way business performance is ISSB (International Sustainability Standards Board)\nperceived and measured, tackling inequality is also start to set clear standards which are helping to further\nabout unlocking a variety of company-level benefits, mainstream action.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Financial Disclosure",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "International Sustainability Standards Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "For me, this represents an important\nincluding attracting and retaining talent, winning blueprint for the path we need to tread on the social\nconsumers, enhancing access to capital and staying side of sustainable development as well.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "ahead of policy and regulatory change.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Of course,\nmeasures to promote social equality will come with And then on a personal level, interacting with leading\ncosts, but these costs should be seen as investments companies in this space also gives me hope.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "There is\nin long-term business success.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "So, yes, there are huge a growing community of passionate individuals and\nopportunities, both in the operating environment and purpose-led companies, who are driving this agenda\nat the individual company level.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "forward at pace, and we are really pleased to be able\nto count on their leadership.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The urgent call to action\nnow is for all businesses to use the tools and resour-\nWhat encourages you that the global community ces at their disposal to head off the risks posed by\nwill succeed in reversing the current trend and mounting inequality.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We need to ensure that equal op-\neffectively combating inequality?",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "portunities and better outcomes are available for all.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "There are a few things that give me hope.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Firstly, I take\na lot of encouragement from the progress that has James Gomme\nbeen made with regard to efforts to address the climate joined WBCSD in March 2016 on a long-term secondment from Mitsubishi\nCorporation, Japan’s largest general trading and investment company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Firstly",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "James Gomme",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "WBCSD",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "March 2016",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mitsubishi\nCorporation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Japan",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In\nemergency in recent years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "recent years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Of course, we still have a\nJuly 2021, James launched The Business Commission to Tackle Inequality,\nlot of work to do here as well, but we are seeing the a high-profile initiative that is seeking to clearly establish the role of busi-\nentire global business community rally behind net-zero ness when it comes to tackling the critical systemic challenge of mounting\nlevels of inequality globally.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "July 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "James",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "The Business Commission",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "net-zero",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Initial recommendations for action are sum-\ncommitments.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We have also seen governments take\nmarized in the report “Tackling inequality: The need and opportunity for\nstrong action, and we have seen bodies like TCFD (Task business action.”\n10\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "TCFD",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance\nGOVERNANCE\n12 Sustainable corporate governance\n42 Integrity and compliance\n60 Data responsibility\n69 Partnerships\nThis Sustainability Report also includes the content audited in the Non-Financial Declaration.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "42",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "60",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "69",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Non-Financial Declaration",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The relevant passages in this Sustainability Report are marked\nin blue font colour in the continuous text.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Audited graphs and tables are also referenced accordingly via footnotes.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Unless explicitly noted, this content was\naudited with reasonable assurance.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Unless marked with footnotes, graphs and tables have not undergone external audit, regardless of the colors used.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "11\nSustainable corporate governance\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sustainable corporate governance\nSustainable business strategy\nSustainability as a driver of change\nOne of the most important transformation goals at the\nMercedes-Benz Group is decarbonisation, which the\nThe Mercedes-Benz Group aims to create value that is Group has made a firm component of its sustainable\nsustainable – economically, ecologically and socially: business strategy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "One",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "At Mercedes-Benz Group, this goal\nThis is one of the core principles of the Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It is reflected in “Ambition 2039” and the “Electric Only”\napplies not only to the Group´s own products and approach.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ambition 2039",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "the “Electric Only",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "By the end of this decade, Mercedes-Benz\nmanufacturing locations, but also to the entire upstream intends to be all-electric wherever market conditions\nand downstream value chain.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the end of this decade",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It has translated this allow.\napproach in its sustainable business strategy, with which\nit firmly embeds sustainability considerations in the daily The Mercedes-Benz Group at a glance\nbusiness activities.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "daily",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In this way, the Mercedes-Benz Group GRI 2-1/-2/-4/-6\nintends, among other things, to fulfil the demands The Mercedes-Benz Group AG is the parent company\nand expectations of its stakeholders — i.e. customers, of the Mercedes-Benz Group and has its registered\nemployees, investors, business partners, non- office in Stuttgart.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2-1/-2/-4/-6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Stuttgart",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "With effect from 1 February 2022,\ngovernmental organizations and society as a whole.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1 February 2022",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Daimler AG changed its name to Mercedes-Benz\nStrategy chapter, AR 2022 Group AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Daimler AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz\nStrategy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "AR 2022 Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "As well as Mercedes-Benz Group AG, the\nMercedes-Benz Group is made up of all subsidiary\ncompanies over which the Mercedes-Benz Group AG\nThe global production network of the Mercedes-Benz Group in the midst of transformation\nGERMANY POLAND CZECH REP.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GERMANY POLAND CZECH REP",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "HUNGARY SLOVENIA\nBremen Rastatt Jawor Most Kecskemét Maribor\nSindelfingen Düsseldorf\nROMANIA\nLudwigsfelde Untertürkheim Sebeș Cugir\nHamburg Berlin\nKölleda/Arnstadt Kamenz SPAIN CHINA\nVitoria Beijing Fuzhou\nKuppenheim\nUSA/MEXICO EGYPT INDIA T IN",
    "entities": [
      [
        "HUNGARY",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Bremen",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Jawor",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Kecskemét",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Sindelfingen Düsseldorf\nROMANIA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Untertürkheim",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Cugir",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Hamburg Berlin",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Kölleda/Arnstadt Kamenz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SPAIN",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "CHINA",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Vitoria Beijing",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Fuzhou",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Kuppenheim",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "EGYPT",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "INDIA",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "H D A O IL N A E N S D IA / / V M IE",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "A A Y M SI / A\nTuscaloosa Charleston",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Tuscaloosa",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Charleston",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Cairo Pune\nBangkok Ho Chi Minh City\nAguascalientes Jakarta Pekan\nARGENTINA SOUTH AFRICA",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Cairo",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Pune",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Bangkok",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Ho Chi Minh City\n",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Aguascalientes",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Jakarta",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Buenos Aires East London Cars Plant/EV Battery Plant Transmissions (EV) Components\nVans Plant/EV Engines Axles Battery Recycling\n13\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Buenos Aires East London Cars Plant/EV Battery Plant Transmissions",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EV",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sustainable corporate governance\nMercedes-Benz Group\ncan exert a direct or indirect controlling influence.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The The Mercedes-Benz Group markets and sells vehicles\nMercedes-Benz Group AG determines the strategy of and services in almost all countries of the world and\nthe Group, is its controlling body and, as the Group has some 30 production sites in Europe, North and\nparent company, is responsible for legal, regulatory and Latin America, Asia and Africa.\ncompliance functions worldwide.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "some 30",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "North",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Latin America",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Asia",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Africa",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "14\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sustainable corporate governance\nCompany profile\n2022\nEmployees (Status December 31, 2022) 168,797\nProduction sites 30\nUnit sales (in mill.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "168,797",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "30",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "units) 2.456\nFinancial key figures (in € millions)\nRevenue 150,017\nResearch and development expenditure Mercedes-Benz Cars and Mercedes-Benz Vans 8,541\nPersonnel expenses (wages and salaries, social welfare services) 29,607\nTotal dividend (in €) 5.20\nThe brand portfolio of Mercedes-Benz Cars includes, The Mercedes-Benz Group has also formulated strategic\nalong with the Mercedes-Benz brand, the brands ambitions for each of the six areas of action:\nMercedes-AMG, Mercedes-Maybach and Mercedes-EQ.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2.456",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "millions",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "150,017",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Cars",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Vans",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "29,607",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "€",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "5.20",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Cars",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-AMG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Maybach",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-EQ",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Mercedes me brand offers access to the digital 1.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Climate protection and air quality: Plans call for\nservices of Mercedes-Benz Cars.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Cars",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz the Mercedes-Benz new vehicle fleet to be CO-\n2\nVans is a full-service provider in the van sector.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "CO-",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The neutral on the balance sheet across the entire value\nMercedes-Benz Mobility business division supports chain by 2039 and to no longer have any relevant\nsales of the Mercedes-Benz Group’s automotive brands impact on NO2 levels in urban areas by 2025.\naround the world through tailored mobility and financial\nservices.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Mobility",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2039",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Mobility is also active in the 2.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Mobility",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Resource conservation: The Mercedes-Benz Group\nfield of innovative mobility services.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "wants to decouple resource consumption from busi-\nness volume growth.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Areas of action and the foundations of\nsustainability 3.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sustainable urban mobility: The Mercedes-Benz\nGRI 3-2 Group wants to contribute to the improvement of the\nThe Mercedes-Benz Group acts in line with the quality of life in cities through its leading mobility\nsustainable business strategy adopted by the Board of and transport solutions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz\nGRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of and transport",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Management of Mercedes-Benz Group AG in 2019 with\nthe agreement of the Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Mercedes-Benz Group is working\ntopics are thus an integral part of the business strategy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "to make its vision of accident-free driving a reality\nStrategy chapter, AR 2022 as it develops automated driving systems while also\ntaking social and ethical issues into account.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "AR 2022",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Mercedes-Benz Group has set itself ambitious goals\nand defined six strategic areas of action for reaching 5.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Data responsibility: The future of the\nthese goals.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The strategic goals are based on the UN’s Mercedes-Benz Group consists of sustainable,\n17 Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) — especially data-based business models.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "UN",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "17",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "With these business\nSDGs 8 and 9 and 11 to 13 — among other factors.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "8 and 9",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In models, it focuses on the needs of its customers and\naddition, they take into account recognized international the responsible handling of data.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "frameworks, the requirements of the external and\ninternal stakeholders and global trends.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Human rights: The Mercedes-Benz Group has as-\nareas of action and areas of responsibility, as well as sumed responsibility for respecting and upholding\nbusiness-specific targets, processes and measures are human rights along its automotive value chain.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "derived from this analysis.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Mercedes-Benz Group\nundertakes periodic materiality analyses.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It uses these\nas the basis for a discussion of the current fields of\naction and an assessment of the need for updates.\n15\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "15",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sustainable corporate governance\nThe Mercedes-Benz Group has defined three enablers, 2.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "People: As an attractive employer, the\nor principles, that are crucial for achieving success in the Mercedes-Benz Group promotes the diversity of its\nsix areas of action: integrity, people and partnerships.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "workforce and provides the necessary skills to mas-\nter the challenges of digitalisation.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Integrity: In order to firmly anchor integrity in all\nareas, the Mercedes-Benz Group considers two 3.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "two 3",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Partnerships: The Mercedes-Benz Group enters into\ncrucial aspects: first of all, by establishing adequate partnerships with social and political players in or-\nstructures with appropriate policies and processes, der to achieve the goals of the sustainable business\nthe organisation is able to provide the foundation for strategy against the backdrop of the ecological and\nall parties to act with integrity.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Secondly, the Group social challenges in these times.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Secondly",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Group’s prin-\nfocuses on putting each employee individually in a ciples for political dialogue and advocacy provide\nposition to understand the concept of integrity and the basis for responsible and reliable action within\nthereby to act ethically and sustainably.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Six fields of action and three enablers\nAreas of action\nClimate protection & Resource Sustainable\nair quality conservation urban mobility\nTraffic safety Data responsibility Human Rights\nEnabler\nIntegrity Partnerships People\n16\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Climate protection & Resource Sustainable",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "16",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sustainable corporate governance\nUnited Nations Sustainable SDG 9 – Industry, Innovation and Infra-\nDevelopment Goals structure: Digitalisation and electrification –",
    "entities": [
      [
        "United Nations Sustainable",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In 2015, the United Nations defined a blueprint for with these, the Mercedes-Benz Group is\nworldwide sustainable development.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2015",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the United Nations",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This includes shaping the sustainable mobility of the future\n17 Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "17",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Through and contributing to greater safety and climate\ntheir innovation and investment power, businesses play protection, for example.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It is also able to\na decisive role in achieving these goals – which the demonstrate the potential of digital innova-\nMercedes-Benz Group actively embraces.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In order to assess its corporate performance with SDG 11 – Sustainable Cities and Communi-\nregard to the 17 SDGs, the Mercedes-Benz Group ties: The Mercedes-Benz Group is making a\nconducted an SDG analysis together with the analytical contribution to sustainable mobility in densely\nexperts of TruCost in 2020.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "SDG 11",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Communi-",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "17",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SDG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "TruCost",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This involved examining the populated urban areas with its vehicles,\npositive and potentially negative impacts of its business data-based solutions for greater traffic safety\nactivities on the SDGs. or improvement of traffic flow, as well as\nmultimodal connectivity of mobility packages.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition, the Mercedes-Benz Group identified\nthose UN Sustainability Goals that entail the greatest SDG 12 – Sustainable Consumption and\nopportunities and risks for itself.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "UN Sustainability Goals",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SDG 12 – Sustainable Consumption",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Production: The Mercedes-Benz Group is\nworking to increase the efficiency of its\nThe Mercedes-Benz Group uses the results to vehicles and significantly reduce its use of\nmake an even greater contribution to achieving raw materials.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "One of the tasks here is to\nthe UN Sustainable Development Goals through its reinforce the closed material loops for the\ncorrespondingly aligned business activities.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "One",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the UN Sustainable Development Goals",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To this end, primary raw materials which are needed for\nthe Mercedes-Benz Group is focusing on the areas in electric vehicles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In this way, the\nwhich it can create the greatest value.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "One example Mercedes-Benz Group is setting the course\nof this is the “Electric only” approach.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "One",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the “Electric",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "for sustainable production.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The following SDGs are the focus of the work of the SDG 13 – Climate Protection Measures:\nMercedes-Benz Group: Through its sustainable business strategy and\nthe associated measures and targets for\nSDG 8 –Decent Work and Economic Growth: reducing emissions from its own vehicles,\nThe Group develops and implements a risk- plants and supply chains, the Mercedes-Benz\nbased management approach to respect and Group aims to reduce its environmental\nprotect human rights in its own business units impact on the climate.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "8 –Decent",
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "as well as in the supply chain – through this,\nthe Mercedes-Benz Group supports the\nimplementation of humane working conditions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Through its production and large procurement\nvolume, the Mercedes-Benz Group also creates\nemployment all over the world.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "17\nSustainability Report 2022 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "17",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Group\nGovernance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sustainable corporate governance\nAlong the value chain\nGRI 2-6\nThe automotive industry is currently undergoing a minimise the negative impacts of its business activities\nprofound process of change, which the Mercedes-Benz as far as possible, and to create sustainable value –\nGroup would like to actively shape.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI 2-6",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In doing so, the Group economically, ecologically and socially.\nconsiders the entire value chain.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This encompasses the\ncomplete life cycle of the vehicle – from development The diagram below shows the main stages of the\nto its recycling after the use phase.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It aims to avoid or Mercedes-Benz value chain in simplified form.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Product development\nThe Mercedes-Benz Group offers a broad product portfolio of passenger cars along\nwith both private and commercial vans.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Mercedes-Benz Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It is systematically electrifying all model\nseries and, as part of this, is strongly involved in research and development.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Recycling,\nProduct\nSupply chain Production Vehicle operation remanufacturing\ndevelopment\nand disposal\n8.5 86\n% Share of renewable energies",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Production Vehicle",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "8.5 86",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The share of electrified\nbillion euros AlmSoustp ply chain in the production of vehicles (xEV) in Group sales Pilot factory built at Kuppen-\nheim site for recycling\nspent on research and of the Mproedruccetiodne msa-tBereianl z vehMiecrlceesde cs-oBnenszi Csatr so afn sde veraalt tMheorcuedseasn-Bde ncz oCmarsp iso nenltitshi u–m r-aiown b mattaertye sryisatelsm s;\ndevelopment expenditures suppliers of Mercedes-Benz Mercedes-Benz Vans in total 16\nBy 2030, the Mercedes-Benz Ca V r a s n as a s n u s h d a cM s v h e t e e r s ac",
    "entities": [
      [
        "AlmSoustp",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "heim",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mproedruccetiodne",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "afn sde",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "tMheorcuedseasn-Bde",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "iso nenltitshi u",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "sryisatelsm",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz Mercedes-Benz Vans",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "16",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Mercedes-Benz",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "a s n",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "d rs s o- e t B h ne m e n, z",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i c p ai 0 t r ly o u c",
    "entities": [
      [
        "0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "d m 0 on u isn c u m t",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i % u s pm t s io u ,n c p is h r e a li s m s i e n a a t r s y , p",
    "entities": [
      [
        "t s io u",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "r i d w n u o g r c ld h t",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "d r p n e r e e s l s im es i , n e a t r c y .",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "c t t h s e s uch\nProduct Grou to p t a in l t o e f n m ds",
    "entities": [
      [
        "l t o",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i h n a v n es t a “A s m u b p iti p on ly L e c tt h e a r” in is accordingly complex: it co T m he",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "oyf c n ful e ilnl a yg r e, l l e y c t 4 ri 0 c ,000 diroef cthte sreutpurpnalbieler s for\nSupply chain Pr8od2uc5tion Vehicle operation verheicmleas ninu Gfraocutpu srailensg a t high-voltage lithium-ion\ns 8 p\nd\nen .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "diroef",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "cthte sreutpurpnalbieler s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Gfraocutpu",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "e\nt 5\nv\no\ne\nn\nl\nb r\no\ne i\np\nl s l e",
    "entities": [
      [
        "t 5",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "o",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i\nm\no a n r\ne\nc e h\nn\nu\nt\na ro n s d otf",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i e pn\n3\no gr qs o t o u d 8 f a b u l e",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "o t o",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i e m o y u e % n a r e t o a se s n r i",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "l Sh M s a u e r i p",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "e p r n o c r p o n o t",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "d i s e e r n\nr\nu e i e r t\no\nc",
    "entities": [
      [
        "o",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "p s s d n e t - r\nd\ne w i B o v o w N",
    "entities": [
      [
        "o",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "d\nu\ni n s t a n u h oi\nc\nm t b z c s r\nt\nr l t C a e e",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "o t g a\no\nth e e n a r n r i\nn\ns",
    "entities": [
      [
        "o",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "A e d a s a f r l\na\nn t m g o d\nn\nie e\nd\ns r i\nn\nc\no\nv G a e\nn\nr a .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "o",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "oh e le\nC\ne - r\nr\ne s w l s r\nOo\nd h c 4 s i ( w\n2d\ne",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2d",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "d a x e\ne\nd r E e i\nu\nd e\nm\ne V 3 p ei\nc\ns o )",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i\nt\nB\ns\nn e e\ni\nd\ni\nt e d\noo\n% l G u u e n u\nn\nc\nn\nr c z cr\ns\no t t e n",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i r b e s\na\ns s ya d a i\nt\ni t l s v e\ne\ne s s",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "e\nr i a\ns\nl\nuP l\ns\ni ib t l\n,\nh o\nM\n- h\nm",
    "entities": [
      [
        "o",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i t u 4 s e\ne\nf m a i\nra\nu\na\nm\nc\nc -\nn\np\nei\nt",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i n r\ne\nt\nl\ny e\ny\nl\nds\nb i\n-\nb f a e\niBf\nwo u\ns\nt\nre\nr r t",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "e\non\ns r t r r e\noz\nl .",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i\ntn\nu dl s\nlh\ni\ns\nt",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "p ne e\nie\np g\ns\nm e\nr\nn s;\ne\n-\ngio\nse\nbn\nc\na\nr t\ns\no\nt\ne o\nt\nn u\neo\nr d s e\nr\ne\nfi\nl m\ne\ni f",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i\nsE\ne a n n\na u\ni v n u\nr\ne\ner\nf e h a\no\nn\nb\ni c c e\npe\nt l",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "r\ni\nu e g\nne\nr s y\ng\ni\n,\nn o s\nrA\ng t r\no\no\nu\nf f\ns\nr o o a\nti\nr\ne\nr g\na d\ne s\nB",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "d y G e 2 v r s 8 o 1 0 e p u t d l 3",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "e t p 3 t , a i 5 v m P n t l o",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "h e t o r e n e e o l f",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "d i l p l e l s s o e l u",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "r r o t p c a c n e o",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "n e r e t e t e c i n d e h n h u n d u e a v r t",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "a i r s n e o t o - n u s s B s d t r e e a n s z a T\nB\ns p\nd\ne h o\ny\nu T p\nG\nC\ne\nn t",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "e\nr h b a v D e i l s o\nu t\nt “\nl\nl\n3\ns n S",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i c n r\nt\nd u s\np\ne p n r m - o",
    "entities": [
      [
        "u s",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "n w I o\n3\nn o\n, a\ne g\ni\ns s V\nm\ng r\nn\nh",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "o",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "p q\nt\nd s\nl\nd 4 o b o",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i\nt\na t t o o\no\nu\ne\nt e p d r i r\ne\ne M o r e f\ne\nv t i l 8 f\nf\nr\nn\na P s b o u\nn\ni d m n lr e s M t v 2 o - l e e\nt m M\n.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "e M o r e",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "o",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "u\nn",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "n lr e s M",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "n f r a m s7\ne\ne l s t s l\ns o e",
    "entities": [
      [
        "o",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "d g o L p e t\nr r\na 5 n n\nt",
    "entities": [
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Mercedes-Benz",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "i c a T a\np\nh\nc\nn s\ne\no e",
    "entities": [],
