[
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sustainability Report\n2022\nCONTENTS FOCUS TOPICS\n1\nDECARBONIZATION\n36 Decarbonization\n56 EU Taxonomy\n5 FO REWORD\n2\nCIRCULAR ECONOMY\n7",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "36",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "56",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "ABOUT THIS REPORT\n68 Circular Economy\n10 SUSTAINABILITY IN THE\nGROUP’S DNA 3\nP EOPLE IN THE TRANSFORMATION\n11 Corporate Governance\n75 People in the Transformation\n14 NEW AUTO Group Strategy\n18 ESG Performance Management 4\nand Materiality Analysis D IVERSITY\n20 Sustainability Management 89 Diversity\n22 Sustainability Impact of\nNew Mobility Options 5\nINTEGRITY\n24 Stakeholder Management\n94 Integrity\n26 Environmental Compliance\nManagement\n6\n33 Risk Management SUPPLY CHAIN AND HUMAN RIGHTS\n35 Corporate Citizenship 104 Supply Chain and Human Rights\nA detailed description of the sustainability activities of the Volkswagen Group’s brands 114 APPENDIX\nand regions is available at:\nwww.volkswagenag.com > Sustainability > 115",
    "entities": [
      [
        "68",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "75",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "18",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Materiality Analysis D IVERSITY",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "20",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "89",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "22",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "New Mobility Options",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "24",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "94",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "26",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "33",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "35",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "114",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "115",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "I ndependent Auditor’s Limited\nReporting & ESG Performance Assurance Report\nNAVIGATION 118 Contact Information\nReferences to chapters in the Sustainability Report\nReferences to websites\nReferences to the Annual Report\n2\nSTNETNOC\nFO\nELBAT\nSUSTAINABILITY AND ESG (ENVIRONMENTAL, SOCIAL, GOVERNANCE)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Auditor",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Limited\nReporting & ESG Performance Assurance Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Sustainability Report\nReferences",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ELBAT",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "ARE PART OF THE NEW AUTO GROUP STRATEGY\nVOLUME PREMIUM SPORT & LUXURY\nTTEECCHH PPLLAATTFFOORRMMSS",
    "entities": [
      [
        "PREMIUM SPORT & LUXURY\n",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "IINNIITTIIAATTIIVVEESS\nMECHATRONICS\nSOFTWARE\nBATTERY & CHARGING\nMOBILITY SOLUTIONS\nBBAASSEE IINNIITTIIAATTIIVVEESS\n06",
    "entities": [
      [
        "MECHATRONICS\nSOFTWARE\nBATTERY & CHARGING\nMOBILITY SOLUTIONS\nBBAASSEE IINNIITTIIAATTIIVVEESS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "06",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "| ESG, Decarbonization and Integrity\nPEOPLE IN THE\nDECARBONIZATION CIRCULAR ECONOMY\nTRANSFORMATION\nSUSTAINABILITY IN THE\nGROUP’S DNA\nDIVERSITY INTEGRITY SUPPLY CHAIN AND\nHUMAN RIGHTS\nEESSGG PPEERRFFOORRMMAANNCCEE",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Decarbonization",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The aim is to improve performance in the capital market’s ESG ratings and rankings so\nas to increase the ability to invest and optimize the cost of capital.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "As we transition from automotive manufacturer to mobility group, we are resetting our priorities with the NEW AUTO Group strategy\nand positioning ourselves for the future.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the NEW AUTO Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are keeping our aim of being a world-leading provider of sustainable mobility firmly in\nour sights and making the Group more focused, efficient, innovative, customer-oriented and sustainable, as well as systematically\ngearing it toward profitable growth.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The NEW AUTO Group strategy defines the six key focus issues shown above for the area of sustainability and ESG in Group initiative 6.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The NEW AUTO Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This Sustainability Report including nonfinancial report is structured in accordance with these.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition, the Sustainability in the Group’s DNA chapter provides a definition of sustainability for the Group and an insight into topics\nsuch as risk management, environmental management, stakeholder management and corporate citizenship.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "3\n2022 HIGHLIGHTS¹\nFOCUS TOPICS\nDECARBONIZATION\n+26% BEVs\nCIRCULAR ECONOMY\n572,100 all-electric\n633,881 vehicles delivered to\ncustomers worldwide.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "+26%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "572,100",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "633,881",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "metric tons\n1.5 °C\nof CO₂ saved through\nthe Aluminum\nClosed Loop as goal\nprocess since 2017.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1.5 °",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "2017",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Reconditioning a SBTi confirms tightened\ngearbox reduces climate targets in\nCO₂ emissions production.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "54%\nby\nand reduces the primary\nenergy requirement by 52%\ncompared with the\nnew part.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "54%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "52%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "PEOPLE IN THE\nTRANSFORMATION\nTraining costs\nin the\nVolkswagen Group:\nDIVERSITY\n€398.6 m\n12.8 m\nProportion of women\nin management\ntraining hours\nworldwide\nin the\nand internationality\nVolkswagen Group.\nof top management\nincreased.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "398.6",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "12.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "hours",
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "94%\nof managers\nhave taken part in\nthe Diversity\nWins@Volkswagen\nprogram.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "94%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "INTEGRITY\nSUPPLY CHAIN AND\nHUMAN RIGHTS The T4I program\nhas been rolled out\n784\nin\ncontrolled companies\nto date.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "784",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Development and\nimplementation of\na new management\napproach for\nresponsible supply\nchains.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "1,517\n> 2,900\ninquiries were processed\nat the compliance\nsuppliers were\ninformation point.\ntrained on\nsustainability.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1,517",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2,900",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "1 Further information on the figures on this page, such as definitions and scope, can be found in the relevant chapters.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "GRI 2-22\nFOREWORD\nOliver Blume, Daniela Cavallo,\nChairman of the Board of Management of Volkswagen AG Chairwoman of the General and Group Works Council of Volkswagen AG\nDear stakeholders and colleagues, hours of additional green electricity by 2025.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2-22",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Oliver Blume",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Daniela Cavallo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management of Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the General and Group Works Council of Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "hours",
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This should even better\ncover the electricity needs of the electric vehicles brought to market\nLeaving a better world for future generations is, in our eyes, the and mean a net carbon-neutral use phase can be achieved for the\ngreatest challenge of our times.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sustainability is not a fad.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It’s firmly electric fleet.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It’s clear that Volkswagen is committed to the electric\nembedded at Volkswagen as one of five principles of corporate drive for decarbonization – for cars, trucks and buses.\ngovernance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We think of sustainability holistically:",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It’s about the\nenvironment – including climate protection – and about our social We’re delighted that the renowned Science Based Targets initiative\nresponsibility, the transformation of the workforce and the way last year honored our more stringent CO2 targets in production.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Science Based Targets",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "last year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "By\nwe run our company.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "2030, we want to reduce our passenger cars and light commercial\nvehicles’ production-related CO2 emissions by 50% – instead of our\nIn the Group, we have set ourselves the long-term goal of becoming previous target of 30%.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "50%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "30%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Science Based Targets initiative has\nnet carbon neutral by no later than 2050 – this includes our supply confirmed to us that this means our Group meets the requirements\nchains, plants and business divisions and our customers’ use of the for the 1.5 °C goal for the production phase.\nvehicles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Science Based Targets",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2050",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1.5 °",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The biggest contribution to reducing our emissions has\nbeen made by electric mobility.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "And its share in our sales is rising:",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In battery production too, we’re mindful of sustainability.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We laid\nIn 2022, almost 7% of all the vehicles we delivered globally were the foundation for our own first battery cell factory at the Salzgitter\nall-electric.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "almost 7%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Salzgitter",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "At 572,000 units, we sold a good 26% more e-cars in total site in 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "572,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "a good 26%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Five more factories in Europe will follow by the end of\nthan in the previous year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "the previous year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Our attractive e-models, including the the decade in order to cover the rising demand for electric cars.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the the decade",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Buzz, the ID.5 and the Audi RS e-tron GT, have been factory will be run entirely on renewable energy and will be de-\nimpressing customers since their launch.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Audi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "tron GT",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "For this year, we’re aiming signed for future closed loop recycling – with the aim of recycling\nfor 11% of our sales to be electric vehicles, and we want to increase as much material as possible and keeping our own raw materials\nthis to 20% by 2025.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "this year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "11%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "20%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "loop as closed as possible.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Volkswagen Group is also the first automotive manufacturer to Our first battery cell manufacturing facility shows that the focus\ndirectly support the expansion of renewable energy on an industrial on e-mobility and software development is going to change work.\nscale.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Group brands have already supported the construction of Volkswagen wants to make this transition in an employee-friendly\nwind farms in Germany, Sweden and Finland in 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Sweden",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Finland",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It is planned and socially acceptable way.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "that all the projects together will generate around seven terawatt\n5\nDROWEROF\nTable of Contents\nGRI 2-22\nIn 2022, we continued to anchor sustainability in our core business.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "seven",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2-22",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are in communication with our suppliers around the world in\nWe were able to use our social power at the start of the year when order to achieve environmental and social improvements in supply\nmany people were experiencing immeasurable suffering as a result chains.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the start of the year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We want to act as a role model in the design of circular, cli-\nof Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Ukraine",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We provided help with donations of mate-neutral and fair supply chains.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In order to identify particularly\ngoods, financial support and the use of our vehicles.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We’re proud of high risks in the chains, we introduced the human rights focus system\nour employees in Germany, who donated more than €2 million for in 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "more than €2 million",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It identifies and addresses particularly high risks in the area\nemergency aid.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The big Volkswagen family shows solidarity and of human rights and the environment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Our newly appointed human\nholds together in times of crisis.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "rights officer will independently monitor whether human rights\ndue diligence requirements are being met.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Not only does the transformation to e-mobility underline the need\nto safeguard jobs, so do other challenges from the past year, includ- As part of the 10-point plan, which defines the Group’s most im-\ning the aftereffects of the Covid-19 pandemic, the impact of the war portant action areas, we are going to anchor sustainability even\nin Ukraine, the supply-chain bottleneck and striking increases in more strongly in daily business in 2023.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the past year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ukraine",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "daily",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are now going to go a\nthe prices of raw materials and issues with their availability.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This step further and break down our ambitious ESG targets into brands\nmakes it all the more crucial that job security, which we consider and business divisions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It’s about the brands and sites in the Group\none of the most important action areas for our Group, has been living up to their responsibility as a whole.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In the end, there will be\nplanned in advance until 2029.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2029",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This gives us a decisive competitive uniform ESG profiles for all brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This is important because\nedge compared with other companies looking for new employees.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "doing business sustainably is becoming increasingly important –\nThis security plays a major role for our future colleagues when they including for our investors.\nare choosing where to work and increases our attractiveness as an\nemployer.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The codetermination tools, which were set up at an early Sustainability is also firmly anchored in our strategy in 2023.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We\nstage, offer new talent attractive future prospects and ensure a are going to continue to advance the key topics of decarbonization\nhigh level of internationalization in top management, because of transportation and production, the transformation of the work-\ncodetermination is an important factor here as well.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "force and our responsibility in supply chains.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "You are cordially\ninvited to join us in this.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Gender diversity is also taken for granted in codetermination at\nVolkswagen.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We actively encourage an increase in the proportion\nof female managers and participate in the UN Global Compact’s Oliver Blume and Daniela Cavallo\nTarget Gender Equality program.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the UN Global Compact’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Oliver Blume",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Daniela Cavallo\nTarget Gender Equality",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Our goal is gender equality at all\nlevels of the Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "6\nDROWEROF\nTable of Contents\nGRI 2-2\nABOUT THIS REPORT\nFurther information, particularly information relevant to ESG in-\nvestors – for example, on the brands’ and regions’ sustainability\nREPORT STRUCTURE activities and also ESG KPIs – is available on the Group’s corporate\nwebsite and is not part of this report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This 2022 Group Sustainability Report is based on internationally\nestablished frameworks and requirements, such as the standards Sustainability in the Group’s DNA > Sustainability Management\nof the Global Reporting Initiative (GRI, see also following section),\nthe German CSR Directive Implementation Act (CSR-Richtlinie- Sustainability in the Group’s DNA >\nUmsetzungsgesetz – CSR-RUG), ESG sustainability ratings and stake- ESG Performance Management and Materiality Analysis\nholder expectations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Global Reporting Initiative",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "CSR-Richtlinie- Sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "stake- ESG Performance Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Materiality Analysis",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The report is supplemented by a detailed de-\nscription of the sustainability activities of our brands and regions www.volkswagenag.com > Sustainability >\nand of the Volkswagen Group’s corporate citizenship projects.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Reporting & ESG Performance\nVOLKSWAGEN GROUP SUSTAINABILITY COMMUNICATION\n2022 SUSTAINABILITY WEBSITE ADDITIONAL\nREPORT COMMUNICATION\nwww.volkswagenag.com > www.volkswagen-\nincluding Sustainability > Reporting newsroom.com/en\n2022 Nonfinancial\nStatement\nBASIS FOR REPORT Volkswagen systematically uses the GRI Standards (with reference\nto) as the underlying structure for reporting on management ap-\nFor reporting year 2022, Volkswagen AG is issuing a nonfinancial proaches and the specific standard disclosures.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "newsroom.com/en",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The GRI Content In-\nstatement at Company level and a nonfinancial Group declaration, dex has been separated from the 2022 Sustainability Report and can\nwhich are being published together as a combined separate non- be found as a separate document in the Group portal:\nfinancial report within the meaning of German Commercial Code\n(Handelsgesetzbuch – HGB) sections 289b para.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the 2022 Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "289b",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "3. www.volkswagenag.com >",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The nonfinancial report is drawn up in accordance with HGB section Reporting & ESG Performance > Sustainability Report\n315c, in conjunction with sections 289c through 289e.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Reporting & ESG Performance > Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "315c",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "289c",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "289e",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In line with\nthe German CSR Directive Implementation Act (CSR-RUG), this non-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "As a member of the United Nations Global Compact, we also contin-\nfinancial report concentrates on the focus issues necessary for an uously report how we are putting the Ten Principles into corporate\nunderstanding of the Volkswagen Group’s business development, practice.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the United Nations Global Compact",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Our current progress report can be found on the UN Global\noverall performance and position as well as the Volkswagen Group’s Compact’s website:\nimpact on nonfinancial aspects.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "UN Global",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are again reporting on our climate\nprotection activities in line with the requirements of the Task Force United Nations Global Compact\non Climate-related Financial Disclosures (TCFD).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Task Force United Nations Global Compact",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Disclosures",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The strategy chapter and the six following chapters on focus issues\nFurthermore, the GRI Standards are used as the framework for in the report each consist of a text section plus a consolidated KPI\ndrawing up the nonfinancial report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "KPI",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In this Sustainability Report, table at the end of each chapter.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "7\nTROPER\nSIHT\nTUOBA\nTable of Contents\nGRI 2-2, 2-4, 2-5\nReferences to disclosures outside the nonfinancial report are sup- report prepared in accordance with HGB sections 289b para.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "TROPER\nSIHT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2-2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2-4",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289b",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "3 and\nplementary information and do not form part of this report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "3 to verify that its disclosures comply with the relevant\nfollowing passages are also not part of the nonfinancial report: statutory requirements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Further information on the engagement\ncan be found in the independent practitioner’s report on a limited\n• Foreword (pp.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "•",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "5–6) assurance engagement on the nonfinancial reporting.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "• The German Corporate Governance Code – A Blueprint for\nSuccessful Corporate Governance (p. 12) DISCLOSURES IN CONNECTION WITH THE ANNUAL FINANCIAL\n• Further Information and The Volkswagen Value Chain (p. 13)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "•",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "•",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Value Chain",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "STATEMENTS\n• Making the Social and Environmental Impact of Our Actions\nMeasurable (p. 19) Connections have been identified in this combined nonfinancial\nreport to amounts reported in the 2022 annual or consolidated\nThe information in this report relates to the Volkswagen Group as a financial statements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "•",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Social and Environmental Impact of Our Actions\nMeasurable",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "19",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Where information relates to individual Group divisions only,\nthis is clearly indicated in the text.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Unless indicated otherwise, any In fiscal year 2022, the operating result in the Passenger Cars Business\ninformation provided for the Group also applies to Volkswagen AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Passenger Cars Business",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Area was affected by negative special items of €0.4 billion in\nIn addition to Volkswagen AG, the Group includes all major sub- connection with the diesel issue.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "€0.4 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "These special items were mainly\nsidiaries inside and outside Germany that are directly or indirectly attributable to additional expenses for legal risks.\ncontrolled by Volkswagen AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To hedge the currently known legal risks related to the diesel issue,\nIn the financial data, our joint ventures in China are reported using the provisions for litigation and legal risks as of December 31, 2022\nthe equity accounting method.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "However, they are included in full include an amount of around €1.4 billion, based on existing infor-\n(100%) in volume-related data (sales, production and workforce) and mation and current assessments.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "around €1.4 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "100%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Insofar as these can be adequately\nin production-related environmentally relevant data.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The manage- measured at this stage, contingent liabilities relating to the diesel\nment approaches described in this report (e.g., the environmental issue were disclosed in the notes to the consolidated financial state-\ncompliance management system",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "[ECMS] and the compliance man- ments in an aggregate amount of €4.2 billion, whereby €3.6 billion of\nagement system for business and human rights [CMS BHR]) apply to this amount results from lawsuits filed by investors in Germany.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "€4.2 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "€3.6 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "CMS BHR",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "all the Volkswagen Group’s controlled companies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The provisions recognized, the contingent liabilities disclosed, and\ncontrolled companies – i.e., companies that are not controlled by a the other latent legal risks in the context of the diesel issue are in part\ncompany of the Volkswagen Group as the majority owner – we work subject to substantial estimation risks given the complexity of the\nto the extent feasible and permitted by law toward implementation individual relevant factors, the ongoing coordination with the au-\nof the adjusted management approaches.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Chinese joint ven- thorities, and the fact that the fact-finding efforts have not yet been\ntures are included in the information on the Volkswagen Group in concluded.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Should these legal or estimation risks materialize, this\nthe KPIs and the associated targets on the topics of the UEP, the DCI, could result in further substantial financial charges.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "UEP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "DCI",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In particular,\nthe Opinion Survey, the diversity index, training hours per employee, adjustment of the provisions recognized in light of knowledge\naccident indices and accident figures.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Opinion Survey",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "hours",
        "TIME"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The risks of the Chinese market acquired or events occurring in the future cannot be ruled out.\nare recorded by Volkswagen (China) Investment Company Ltd.\nThe remaining provisions relate to a wide range of identifiable indi-\nThe KPIs presented in this report build on the indicators presented vidual risks, price risks and contingent liabilities, which are fac-\nin previous years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "previous years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Any material changes to the methods used to tored in in the amount of their probable occurrence.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Depending on\ncollect and measure the data on our sustainability performance are the jurisdiction concerned, risk provisions for any non compliance\nexplicitly disclosed for the respective KPIs.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "All figures shown in the with statutory emissions limits are also included.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Their measure-\nreport are rounded, so minor discrepancies may arise from addition ment takes into account, among other things, the respective sales\nof these amounts.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "volume and the legally defined fee or the cost of acquiring emission\nrights from other manufacturers.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Advantage has been taken of\nREPORT AUDITING synergies between individual brands of the Volkswagen Group by\nestablishing emission pools where possible.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Additional information\nErnst & Young GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft (EY) con- on this matter and the valuation assumptions and bases can be\nducted a voluntary, limited assurance engagement in accordance found in the Annual Report in the notes to the consolidated financial\nwith ISAE 3000 (Revised) on the combined separate nonfinancial statements.\n8\nTROPER\nSIHT\nTUOBA\nTable of Contents\nGRI 2-3\nADDITIONAL REPORTING WITHIN THE GROUP ABOUT THIS REPORT\nBy referencing this combined separate nonfinancial report, all The editorial deadline was February 17, 2023.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ernst & Young GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Annual Report",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "ISAE 3000 (",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "TROPER\nSIHT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "February 17",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Group Sustain-\nGroup companies that are required by national legislation to disclose ability Report is published in the first quarter of 2023 and is also\nnonfinancial and diversity-related information pursuant to Direc- available in the original German.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the first quarter",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In the event of any discrepancies,\ntive 2014/95/EU but do not issue their own nonfinancial statement the German authoritative version of the document takes precedence\nare exempted from the obligation to submit their own nonfinancial over the English translation.\nreports.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2014/95",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "English",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "TERMINOLOGY RELATING TO CLIMATE PROTECTION",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This sustainability report contains statements relating to the future\nThe use of the term CO2 emissions in this report includes the con- business development of the Volkswagen Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "These statements\nsideration and identification of additional climate-damaging green- are based on assumptions relating to the development of the eco-\nhouse gases such as methane (CH₄) and laughing gas (N2O) (CO2 nomic, political and legal environment in individual countries,\nequivalents).",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "All figures in this report on CO2 emissions correspond economic regions and markets, and in particular for the automotive\nto CO2 equivalents, except for fleet emission figures.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "industry, which we have made on the basis of the information avail-\nable to us and which we consider to be realistic as of the time of go-\nNet carbon neutrality is achieved when anthropogenic CO2 emissions ing to press.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The estimates given involve a degree of risk, and the\nare balanced worldwide through avoidance, reduction and offsetting actual developments may differ from those forecast.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Any changes\nover a specific period of time.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "With regard to climate protection, in in significant parameters relating to our key sales markets, or any\naddition to CO2 emissions Volkswagen also pays attention to all other significant shifts in exchange rates, energy and other commodities\nrelevant greenhouse gases.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Avoidance and reduction have priority or the supply of parts relevant to the Volkswagen Group, or devia-\nover offsetting for the Volkswagen Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "For offsetting measures, tions in the actual effects of the Covid-19 pandemic from the sce-\nthe Group follows internationally established standards.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "nario presented in this report will have a corresponding effect on\nthe development of our business.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition, there may be depar-\nEDITORIAL NOTES tures from our expected business development if the assessments\nof the factors influencing sustainable value enhancement, and of\nWhenever this report uses the term Sustainability Report, this ex- risks and opportunities, presented in this sustainability report\npression includes the nonfinancial report each time it is mentioned develop in a way other than we expect at the time of publication, or\nto the extent described on page 8 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "if additional risks and opportunities or other factors that affect the\ndevelopment of our business emerge.\nREPORTING PRACTICES\nThe nonfinancial report is published annually.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "annually",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The last nonfinancial\nreport was published on March 15, 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "March 15",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition to information\nabout the Group’s sustainability activities in the 2022 fiscal year\n(January 1 to December 31, 2022), this 2022 nonfinancial report\nalso contains selected information from the 2023 fiscal year.\n9\nTROPER\nSIHT\nTUOBA\nTable of Contents",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the 2022 fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "January 1 to December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the 2023 fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "TROPER\nSIHT",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "10\nGRI 2-1, 2-6\nCORPORATE GOVERNANCE\nwww.volkswagenag.com > Investor Relations\nOUTLINE OF THE LEGAL STRUCTURE OF THE GROUP Volkswagen AG is a vertically integrated energy supply company\nas defined by section 3 no.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2-1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "section 3 no.",
        "LAW"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "38 of the German Energy Industry Act\nVolkswagen AG is the parent company of the Volkswagen Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "38",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the German Energy Industry Act",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "(Energiewirtschaftsgesetz – EnWG) and is therefore subject to the\nIt develops vehicles and components for passenger cars and light provisions of the EnWG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Energiewirtschaftsgesetz",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "EnWG",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In the electricity sector, Volkswagen AG\ncommercial vehicles for the Volkswagen Passenger Cars and generates, sells and distributes electricity together with Group\nVolkswagen Commercial Vehicles brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In its capacity as parent subsidiaries.\ncompany, Volkswagen AG holds direct or indirect interests in\nAUDI AG, SEAT S.A., ŠKODA AUTO a.s., Dr. Ing.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "AUDI AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SEAT S.A.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ŠKODA AUTO a.s.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ing",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Volkswagen AG Board of Management has sole responsibility\n(Porsche AG), TRATON SE, Volkswagen Financial Services AG, for managing the Company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Porsche AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Financial Services AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board appoints,\nVolkswagen Bank GmbH and a large number of other companies in monitors and advises the Board of Management and is directly\nGermany and abroad.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Bank GmbH",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "More detailed disclosures are contained in consulted on decisions of fundamental significance for the Company.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "the list of shareholdings in accordance with sections 285 and 313\nof the German Commercial Code (Handelsgesetzbuch – HGB), which\ncan be accessed on the website and is part of the annual financial\nstatements.\nVOLKSWAGEN AG SHAREHOLDER STRUCTURE EMPLOYEES BY MARKET\nas of December 31, 2022, in % of voting capital as of December 31, 2022, in %\nGerman institutional Porsche Automobil Europe (excluding\ninvestors 2.6 Holding SE 31.9 South America 5 Germany)/other\nmarkets 30\nState of Lower Saxony11.8 North America 6\nQatar Holding LLC 10.5 Asia-Pacific16\nForeign institutional\nPrivate shareholders/ investors 22.2 Germany 43\nothers 21.0\nThe Volkswagen Group is one of the leading multi-brand groups in brands, the Volkswagen Group is present in all relevant markets\nthe automotive industry.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "285",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "313",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "VOLKSWAGEN AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Porsche Automobil Europe",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2.6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "31.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "South America",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "30",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "State of Lower Saxony11.8 North America 6",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Qatar Holding",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "10.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Asia",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "22.2 Germany",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "43",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "21.0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Group’s business activities comprise the around the world.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The key sales markets currently include the\nAutomotive and Financial Services divisions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Automotive and Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Our core brands within Western Europe region and China, the USA, Brazil, Poland, Mexico,\nthe Automotive Division – with the exception of the Volkswagen Türkiye and the Czech Republic.\nPassenger Cars and Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles brands – are\nindependent legal entities.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Western Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "USA",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Brazil",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Poland",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Mexico",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Czech Republic",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Passenger Cars",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Automotive Division comprises the Volkswagen AG and the Volkswagen Group are managed by the\nPassenger Cars, Commercial Vehicles and Power Engineering business Volkswagen AG Board of Management in accordance with the\nareas.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Passenger Cars",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Commercial Vehicles",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Power Engineering",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Passenger Cars Business Area essentially consolidates the Volkswagen AG Articles of Association and the rules of procedure for\nVolkswagen Group’s passenger car brands and the Volkswagen Volkswagen AG’s Board of Management issued by the Supervisory\nCommercial Vehicles brand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Passenger Cars Business Area",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Articles of Association",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Volkswagen AG’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Activities focus on the development of Board.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Accordingly, responsibilities were divided among 11 board-\nvehicles, engines and vehicle software, the production and sale of level management functions starting from January 1, 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "January 1",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition\npassenger cars and light commercial vehicles, and the genuine parts to the Chair of the Board of Management, which also includes the\nbusiness.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Chair of the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The product portfolio extends from small cars through to Volume brand group, the other Board positions are Purchasing,\nluxury vehicles in the premium segment.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It also includes motor- Technology, Finance, Human Resources and Truck & Bus, Integrity\ncycles and is supplemented by mobility solutions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Human Resources and Truck & Bus",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Commercial and Legal Affairs, Premium, Sport & Luxury, IT, China, and Volkswagen\nVehicles Business Area primarily comprises the development, produc- Passenger Cars.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Commercial and Legal Affairs",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Premium, Sport & Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Vehicles Business Area",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Passenger Cars",
        "PRODUCT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "A new Group Sales function was created with effect\ntion and sale of trucks and buses, the corresponding genuine parts from February 1, 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group Sales",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "February 1",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "As of September 1, 2022, the Volkswagen\nbusiness and related services.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "September 1",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The commercial vehicles portfolio Group refined its Group management.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management was\nranges from light vans to heavy trucks and buses.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The collaboration streamlined, and responsibilities were reallocated: The Purchasing\nbetween the commercial vehicle brands is coordinated within and Group Sales Board functions were dissolved.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group Sales Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition, the\nTRATON SE.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Power Engineering Business Area combines the large- Volkswagen Passenger Cars function was renamed Volume.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Power Engineering Business Area",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Passenger Cars",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Since\nbore diesel engines, turbomachinery and propulsion components then, responsibilities have been divided between ten board- level\nbusinesses.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ten",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Financial Services Division’s activities comprise dealer management functions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Financial Services Division",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition to the Chair of the Board of\nand customer financing, vehicle leasing, direct banking and insur- Management, the other Board positions are Technology, Finance,\nance activities, fleet management and mobility services.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Chair of the Board of\n",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "With its Human Resources and Truck & Bus, Integrity and Legal Affairs,\n11\nAND\nS’PUORG\nEHT\nNI\nYTILIBANIATSUS\nTable of Contents",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Human Resources and Truck & Bus",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity | Supply Chain and Human Rights\nVolume, Premium, Sport & Luxury, IT, and China.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Premium, Sport & Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Chair of the In the Mobility Solutions technology platform, Volkswagen\nBoard of Management is also responsible for Sport & Luxury.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mobility Solutions",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen\nBoard of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sport & Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Directly strengthened the Group’s expertise in advanced fleet management\nconnected to the Board are a number of Group Management through the equity investment in the Europcar Mobility Group in\nfunctions that act as an extension to the board-level management the reporting period.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Europcar Mobility Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The aim is to be able to achieve even better\nfunctions.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "These comprise the Group Sales, Group Production, coverage of all customers’ mobility needs based on a new mobility\nProcurement and Technical Architecture functions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Group Sales",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group Production",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The allocation of responsibilities of the Board of Management is We are convinced that our corporate structure, which efficiently\nbased on the schedule of responsibilities decided by the Supervisory connects the brand groups and technology platforms, will enable\nBoard, which takes into account the changes in the management us to make better use of existing expertise and economies of scale,\nduring the reporting period.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Its structure contributes to enabling the leverage synergies more systematically and accelerate decision-\nBoard of Management to focus on key tasks such as strategy, central making.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Clear responsibilities and a high degree of business respon-\ndecisions on the Company’s direction, capital allocation and finan- sibility in the brand groups and technology platforms will enable\ncial requirements.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The tasks of the extended Group management comprehensive implementation of the Group’s NEW AUTO strategy.\nserve to leverage synergies in the Group and to connect the brands\nand divisions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "LEGAL FACTORS INFLUENCING BUSINESS",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition, at Group level, Board of Management committees Like other international companies, the business of the Volkswagen\naddress key strategic issues relating to products, technologies, in- companies is affected by numerous laws in Germany and abroad.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "vestments, digital transformation, integrity and compliance, risk In particular, there are legal requirements relating to services, de-\nmanagement, human resources and management issues.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are velopment, products, production and distribution, as well as super-\ncontinually revising and optimizing the committees in order to visory, data protection, financial, company, commercial, capital\nverify that they still align with our corporate strategy and to further market, antitrust and tax regulations and regulations relating to\nincrease the efficiency of their decision-making.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This is intended labor, banking, state aid, energy, environmental and insurance law.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "to r educe complexity and reinforce governance within the Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "THE GERMAN CORPORATE GOVERNANCE CODE –\nThe matrix of brand groups and technology platforms created under A BLUEPRINT FOR SUCCESSFUL CORPORATE GOVERNANCE\nthe Group Steering Model base initiative from the Group strategy\nNEW AUTO was enhanced in both dimensions during the reporting Corporate governance provides the regulatory framework for corpo-\nperiod.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GERMAN",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "A BLUEPRINT FOR SUCCESSFUL CORPORATE GOVERNANCE\nthe Group Steering Model",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This involved both strengthening the brand groups and creat- rate management and supervision.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This includes a company’s orga-\ning new units for key technology areas of the future within our strate- nization and values and the principles and guidelines for its business\ngic technology platforms.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Group steering model will be further policy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The German Corporate Governance Code (the Code) contains\nrefined in the future on this basis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The German",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "principles, recommendations and suggestions for corporate man-\nagement and supervision.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Its principles, recommendations and sug-\nThe Volume brand group comprises the Volkswagen Passenger Cars, gestions were prepared by a dedicated government commission on\nŠKODA, SEAT/CUPRA and Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ŠKODA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "the basis of the material provisions and nationally and internation-\nThe Premium brand group comprises the Audi, Lamborghini, Bentley ally accepted standards of sound, responsible corporate governance.\nand Ducati brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Audi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Lamborghini",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Bentley",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ducati",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Sport & Luxury brand group consists of the In the interests of best practice, the government commission regu-\nPorsche brand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Sport & Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Porsche",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The company responsible for this brand, Porsche AG, larly reviews the Code’s relevance in light of current developments\nhas been listed on the stock market since the end of September 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Porsche AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Code",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the end of September 2022",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "and updates it as necessary.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management and the\nIn the Truck & Bus brand group, TRATON SE acts as the umbrella for Supervisory Board of Volkswagen AG base their work on the Code’s\nthe Scania, MAN, Volkswagen Truck & Bus and Navistar commercial principles, recommendations and suggestions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Scania",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Truck & Bus",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Navistar",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We consider good\nvehicles brands.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "TRATON SE is also a listed company.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "As well as corporate governance to be a key prerequisite for achieving a lasting\nstrengthening the brand groups, the reorganization and creation of increase in the Company’s value.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Company",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "It helps strengthen the trust of\nnew units enabled substantial progress with the Software, Battery & our shareholders, customers, employees, business partners and in-\nCharging and Mobility Solutions technology platforms in the vestors in our work and enables us to meet the steadily increasing\nreporting period.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Software, Battery &",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mobility Solutions",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The software subsidiary CARIAD was further ex-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "demand for information from national and international stake-\npanded, getting a subsidiary of its own in China, among other things.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "You can find our published Declaration of Conformity\nwith the German Corporate Governance Code here:",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the German",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition to this, Volkswagen founded PowerCo SE in the reporting\nperiod as part of the Battery & Charging technology platform.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "PowerCo SE",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Battery & Charging",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This www.volkswagenag.com > Investor Relations > Corporate\ncompany is responsible for the Group’s global battery business.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Declarations\naddition to producing battery cells, it will also take on other activi-\nties along the battery value chain in the future.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "12\nAND\nS’PUORG\nEHT\nNI\nYTILIBANIATSUS\nTable of Contents The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity | Supply Chain and Human Rights\nGRI 2-6\nFURTHER INFORMATION The Volkswagen AG Group Board of Management has adopted an\nupdate of the tax strategy principles, which has been published on\nExplanations of the composition, working methods and diversity Volkswagen AG’s website.\nconcept of the Board of Management and the Supervisory Board\nand information on voting rights are available in the Corporate Each year, Volkswagen AG sends the German Federal Central Tax\nGovernance chapter in the 2022 Annual Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Group Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Corporate Each year",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the German Federal Central Tax\nGovernance",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Annual Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Office a country-by-country report, which includes information on\ntax payments and tax expenses/income by country.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "2022 Annual Report > Corporate Governance\nThe Volkswagen Group has the ambition of implementing its\nmarketing and communication activities transparently and respon-\nExtensive explanations of the remuneration system and the indi- sibly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This includes attentiveness towards our environment and re-\nvidual remuneration of the members of the Board of Management quires us to treat all individuals with respect and honesty and as\nand Supervisory Board can be found in the Remuneration Report for equals.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Remuneration Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This applies internally and externally, online and off.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "To\nfiscal year 2022, which forms part of the 2022 Annual Report, in the this end, the Group has developed principles that serve as a com-\nnotes to Volkswagen’s 2022 consolidated financial statements and in pass for implementing the Volkswagen Group’s values with regard\nthe notes to the 2022 annual financial statements of Volkswagen AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "to marketing and communication activities.\nwww.volkswagenag.com > Investor Relations > Corporate www.volkswagenag.com > Sustainability >\nGovernance > Remuneration Strategy, Policy & Engagement > Policy\nTHE VOLKSWAGEN VALUE CHAIN\nRESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT\nThe Automotive Division’s research and development costs in the reporting year totaled €18.9 billion and were thus 21.3% higher than in the\nprevious year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "VOLKSWAGEN",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Automotive Division’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the reporting year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "€18.9 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "21.3%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "the\nprevious year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition to new models, our activities focused above all on the electrification of our vehicle portfolio, digitalization, new\ntechnologies and enhancements of our modular and all-electric toolkits and platforms.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "PROCUREMENT\nEvery year, the Volkswagen Group purchases a wide range of raw materials, components and other goods.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Every year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "A sustainable supply chain and\nenvironmentally compatible transportation are important for fully assuming responsibility for human rights, environmental protection and the\nbattle against corruption.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "PRODUCTION\nThe Volkswagen Group manufactured an average of around 24,000 vehicles globally every working day in 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "around 24,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "every working day",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Efficient production ranks alongside\nenvironmental protection and employee health and safety as one of our core goals.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "MARKETING & SALES\nBusiness relationships with fleet customers are often long-term and stable partnerships.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "MARKETING & SALES\nBusiness",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Volkswagen Group’s share of commercial fleet\ncustomers is 43.5% in Germany and 25.7% in the rest of Europe.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "43.5%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "25.7%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "AFTER-SALES & FINANCIAL SERVICES\nOur service includes supporting dealerships to ensure they can provide quality advice and maintenance, managing our original parts business,\nand providing vehicle-related financial services.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "In addition to recycling vehicles at the end of their useful life, we pay close attention during the new-vehicle development stage to the\nrecyclability of the required materials, the use of high-quality recycled materials, and the avoidance of pollutants.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "13\nAND\nS’PUORG\nEHT\nNI\nYTILIBANIATSUS\nTable of Contents The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity | Supply Chain and Human Rights\nNEW AUTO GROUP STRATEGY\ncustomers with constantly improving digital functionality.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "As with\ntechnological trends, global economic as well as geopolitical con-\nIn the context of the fast-changing environment and the challenges straints are increasingly confronting the automobile industry\nresulting from it, the Group Board of Management adopted the with greater challenges – for example, the economic influence\nGroup strategy “NEW AUTO” – Mobility for Generations to Come in wielded by the biggest mobility markets, China, the USA and Europe,\nMay 2021 with the approval of the Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Group Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "USA",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "May 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The strategy’s and the way they are diverging.\nfocus is the world of mobility in 2030.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2030",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "As technology advances, the\nautomotive industry is rapidly forging ahead with its transformation Sustainability will continue to be a recurring theme in the business\ntoward e-mobility and digitalization.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We therefore expect the market world and will gain further pertinence, driven by the increasingly\nfor electric vehicles to grow strongly in the next few years, meaning noticeable consequences of climate change, a greater consciousness\nthat cost-efficient and sustainable production of battery systems of sustainable lifestyles on the part of the customer and, not least, un-\nand the expansion of charging infrastructure will be crucial to suc- derlying factors such as the Paris Climate Agreement.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the next few years",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Paris Climate Agreement",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The shift to connected, intelligent and eventually self-driving tion from automotive manufacturer to mobility group, we are reset-\nvehicles, however, will bring more wide-reaching changes for the ting our priorities with NEW AUTO and positioning ourselves for the\nautomotive industry.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Autonomous driving will change the customer’s future.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We are keeping our aim of being a world-leading provider of\nmobility experience forever and lay the ground for new business sustainable mobility firmly in our sights and making the Group\nmodels.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "Sources of revenue will gradually shift and will expand be- more focused, efficient, innovative, customer-oriented and sustain-\nyond the core product of the automobile.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "This shift will be depen- able, as well as systematically gearing it toward profitable growth.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "dent on increasing software development capabilities so as to excite\nTHE 12 INITIATIVES OF THE NEW AUTO STRATEGY\nVOLUME PREMIUM SPORT & LUXURY\nTTEECCHH PPLLAATTFFOORRMMSS",
    "entities": [
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "PREMIUM SPORT & LUXURY\n",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "IINNIITTIIAATTIIVVEESS\nMECHATRONICS 01",
    "entities": [
      [
        "MECHATRONICS 01",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "| Backbone and Scalable Systems Platform (SSP)\nSOFTWARE 02 | CARIAD:",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Backbone and Scalable Systems Platform",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "One E3 Platform and Autonomous Driving Stack\nBATTERY & CHARGING 03",
    "entities": [
      [
        "One",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "03",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "| Cell and Battery Strategy 04",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Cell and Battery Strategy 04",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "| Charging and Energy Services\nMOBILITY SOLUTIONS 05",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Energy Services",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "05",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "| Mobility Solutions\nBBAASSEE IINNIITTIIAATTIIVVEESS\n06",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mobility Solutions\nBBAASSEE IINNIITTIIAATTIIVVEESS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "06",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "| ESG, Decarbonization and Integrity\n07",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Decarbonization",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "07",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "| China 10 | Group Steering 11 | People &\nModel 2.0 Region Region Model Transformation\n12 | Financing the Transformation\n14\nAND\nS’PUORG\nEHT\nNI\nYTILIBANIATSUS\nTable of Contents",
    "entities": [
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "People &\nModel 2.0 Region Region Model Transformation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity | Supply Chain and Human Rights\nTo this end, we have established 12 Group initiatives across the brand long term, the standardized E³ 2.0 software architecture that is al-\ngroups.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "E³",
        "PRODUCT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "We will use these to develop the competences needed to ready being developed, together with the VW.OS software platform\nimplement the strategy.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The focus is on the main multidisciplinary and the Volkswagen Automotive Cloud, will form the basis of a\ntopics of mechatronics, software, battery & charging, and mobility complete digital ecosystem, offering customers a wide range of soft-\nsolutions, on which the five tech initiatives described below are based.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Automotive Cloud",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "ware-based services throughout the product life cycle.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2022,
    "sentence": "The aim is\nA further seven base initiatives form the basis for the Volkswagen for every function that is needed or requested and every service to\nGroup’s strategic realignment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "seven",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
