[
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "SUSTAINABILITY REPORT\n2021\nNEW AUTO: VOLKSWAGEN REINVENTS ITSELF\nThe world of mobility will change fundamentally by 2030:\nelectric drives and fully networked, self-driving transportation will\ndetermine how we move around in the future.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "VOLKSWAGEN",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With the new Group strategy, “NEW AUTO – Mobility for Generations to\nCome”, the Volkswagen Group wants to be a significant driver of this\ntransformation and accelerates its realignment from a vehicle manu-\nfacturer to a world-leading, software-driven mobility provider.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A company\nthat is redefining mobility while also doing business climate neutrally\nand conscientiously.\nCONTENTS 36 FOCUS TOPICS\n1\nD ECARBONIZATION\n37 Decarbonization\n52 EU Taxonomy\n4 INTERVIEW\n2\nC IRCULAR ECONOMY\n7 ABOUT THIS REPORT\n60 Circular Economy\n10 S USTAINABILITY IN THE\nGROUP’S DNA 3\nPEOPLE IN THE TRANSFORMATION\n11 Corporate Governance\n65 People in the Transformation\n14 NEW AUTO Group strategy\n18 ESG Performance Management and 4\nMateriality Analysis D IVERSITY",
    "entities": [
      [
        "36",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ECARBONIZATION",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "37",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "52",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "60",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "65",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "NEW AUTO Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "18",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "79 Diversity\n20 Sustainability Management\n22 Sustainability Impact of New Mobility 5\nOptions I NTEGRITY\n24 Stakeholder Management 85 Integrity\n26 Environmental Management\n6\n32 Risk Management RESPONSIBILITY FOR SUPPLY CHAINS\nAND BUSINESS\n34 Corporate Citizenship\n94 Responsibility for Supply Chains\nand Business\nA detailed description of the sustainability activities of the Volkswagen Group’s brands\nand regions is available at:\n106 APPENDIX\nwww.volkswagenag.com > Sustainability > Reporting\nNAVIGATION 107 Independent Auditor’s\nLimited Assurance Report\nReferences to chapters in the sustainability report\nReferences to websites\nReferences to the Annual Report 110 Contact Information\n3\nSTNETNOC",
    "entities": [
      [
        "79",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "20",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "22",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Impact of New Mobility 5",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NTEGRITY",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "24",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "85",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "26",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Environmental Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "32",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "34",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "94",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "106",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "107",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "FO\nELBAT\nINTERVIEW\nGRI 102-14, 102-16\nDr. Herbert Diess, Daniela Cavallo, Georg Kell,\nChairman of the Board of Management of Chairwoman of the General and Group Founding Director of the UN Global Compact\nVolkswagen AG Works Council of Volkswagen AG and Spokesperson of the Volkswagen Sus-\ntainability Council\n1.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ELBAT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "102-14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Herbert Diess",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Daniela Cavallo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Georg Kell",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management of Chairwoman",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the General and Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the UN Global Compact",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Works Council of Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "tainability Council\n1",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "How is sustainability reflected in the new strategy, NEW AUTO?\nDr. Herbert Diess: The NEW AUTO world will be free of emissions, smarter and above all more sus-\ntainable.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Herbert Diess",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The key to making that happen is getting more electric cars on the road.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This is what we\nachieved in 2021: we are the e-mobility market leader in Europe and the number two in the USA.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "USA",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We\nare expanding the charging infrastructure in Europe, China and the USA to 45,000 charging points\nby 2025.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "USA",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "45,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We are planning to build six battery factories by 2030 together with partners and deal with\nentire battery cycles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "And electric drives bring economic advantages in the truck segment as well.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Only sustainable products will stand the test of time.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "E-mobility is increasingly paying off for cus-\ntomers.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Calculated per kilometer, our electric vehicles are already cheaper to run than vehicles with\ninternal combustion engines.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We are driven by our commitment to the Paris climate goals and we at\nVolkswagen want to be carbon neutral by 2050.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Paris",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2050",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, we have embedded the issues of ESG,\ndecarbonization and integrity as points of strategic focus in NEW AUTO.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "What is important for decarbonization is a shared consensus between politicians, industry, customers\nand society.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A key milestone in 2021 was our readmission to the UN Global Compact, the world’s\nlargest sustainable corporate management initiative.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the UN Global Compact",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We regard this as a sign that we are building\nstakeholders’ trust in our strategy.\n4\nWEIVRETNI\nGRI 102-16\n2.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-16",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "What progress has the Volkswagen Group made in 2021?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Is sustainability becoming a business\nmodel?\nGeorg Kell:",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Georg Kell",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The NEW AUTO strategy signals Volkswagen’s determination to advance electric mo-\nbility and establish new areas of business along the value chain.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The associated investments and\nbusiness decisions are obviously the most important development.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "By doing this, Volkswagen is\npositioning itself at the forefront of the transition from the fossil-driven approaches of the pollut-\ning industrial age to smart and clean processes.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Implementing the strategy is causing an upturn\nin green electricity, efficiency and circular material flows and thus significantly contributes to\nreducing greenhouse gases.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We also made progress on the management of ESG data and on decarbonization approaches.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Measures to promote compliance and integrity, particularly in supply chain management, are now\nfirmly established across the Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Herbert Diess has very clearly spoken out in favor of the energy\ntransformation and higher carbon prices, and a new industrial collaboration has also been started.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Herbert Diess",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Volkswagen has become more innovative and more modern.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Sustainability is already a prerequisite for long-term business success.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It’s long been known how\nmuch mistakes cost companies.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Volkswagen’s recent diesel crisis is just one example of this.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Legal\nchanges, the shift in customer preferences and investor awareness of risks and opportunities in\nconnection with sustainability topics mean sustainability will now also become a value driver.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Companies will only be successful in the long term if they integrate these trends into their strategy\nand activities.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The key word here is “integration” – i.e. that sustainability becomes completely matter\nof course in all roles and in the minds of all the Group’s managers and employees.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It is just as im-\nportant to propagate and embed the concept of decarbonization and circular material flows within\nour business and at suppliers, so what matters is accelerating the transformation.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "3. Where does the Volkswagen Group need to show even more engagement?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Where are the\nsustainability challenges for a group that operates in 153 countries?\nDaniela Cavallo: We support the Group’s strategy of concentrating on electric drives and see our job\nas ensuring that profitability and job security are given equal consideration.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "153",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Daniela Cavallo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In addition to the technical shift to e-mobility, the area of socio-environmental change will also be\none of the most pivotal points of the transformation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Here we need to help shape this change at an\nearly stage.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Rapid implementation of the transformation can only succeed if we reach the whole\nGroup and every employee and get them on board.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It’s important to us as a works council that a top-\nic such as employer attractiveness and the associated employee satisfaction are factored in.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "That’s in\nline with our Volkswagen culture.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "5\nWEIVRETNI\nGRI 102-16\nBy implementing new business areas and as a result of employee training, we’re on the right track\nto develop issues such as sustainability, transformation and employee satisfaction into a success.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The challenge for us is to create standards that conform to the goals of the Paris Agreement.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Paris Agreement",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We’re\nconfident that we can derive rules on the basis of these standards that our international partners\nwill adopt.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "However, this also includes convincing people at sites that have to deliver sustainability\npromises under different political conditions.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Our society is becoming more and more conscious of sustainable action.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Just like with a technological\nedge, the field of sustainability naturally still has a lot of potential, and Volkswagen can also be a pi-\noneer here.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The business model therefore not only needs to be measured by its monetary success\nbut must also pursue social and environmental issues.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The trend among rating agencies to prioritize\nthe social area in addition to the environmental and governance areas is in line with the Works\nCouncil’s principles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Works\nCouncil",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "6\nWEIVRETNI\nABOUT THIS REPORT\nGRI 102-54\nREPORT STRUCTURE",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-54",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This information, which does not form part of this report, can be\nfound on the Volkswagen Group’s corporate website.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This 2021 Group Sustainability Report is based on international-\nly established frameworks and requirements, such as the GRI Sustainability in the Group’s DNA > Sustainability Management\nstandards of the Global Reporting Initiative (GRI, see also fol-\nlowing section), ESG sustainability ratings and stakeholder ex-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the GRI Sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Global Reporting Initiative",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Sustainability in the Group’s DNA > ESG Performance Manage-\npectations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The report is supplemented by a detailed description ment and Materiality Analysis\nof the sustainability activities of our brands and regions and of\nthe Volkswagen Group’s corporate citizenship projects.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Materiality Analysis",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "www.volkswagenag.com >",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Sustainability > Reporting\nVOLKSWAGEN GROUP SUSTAINABILITY COMMUNICATION\n2021 SUSTAINABILITY WEBSITE ADDITIONAL\nREPORT COMMUNICATION\nincluding www.volkswagenag.com >\nSustainability > Reporting https://www.volkswagen-\n2021 Nonfinancial newsroom.com/en\nStatement\nBASIS FOR REPORT consol i dated KPI table at the end of each chapter.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "VOLKSWAGEN GROUP SUSTAINABILITY COMMUNICATION",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "KPI",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "At the same\ntime, the separate GRI Content Index shows how we are imple-\nFor reporting year 2021, Volkswagen AG is issuing a nonfinancial menting the requirements of the United Nations Global Com-\nstatement at Company level and a nonfinancial Group declaration, pact (UNGC).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI Content",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "year 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the United Nations Global",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "UNGC",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The GRI Content Index has been separated from the\nwhich are being published together as a combined separate 2021 Sustainability Report and can be found as a separate docu-\nnonfinancial report within the meaning of HGB sections 289b ment in the Group portal:\npara.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI Content",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289b",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The nonfinancial report is drawn up in\naccordance with HGB section 315c, in conjunction with sections www.volkswagenag.com >",
    "entities": [
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "315c",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Sustainability > Reporting >\n289c through 289e.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "289c",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "289e",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Furthermore, the GRI Standards of the Glob- Sustainability Report\nal Reporting Initiative (GRI) are used as the framework for draw-\ning up the nonfinancial report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In this nonfinancial report, References to disclosures outside the nonfinancial report are sup-\nVolkswagen systematically uses the GRI Standards as the under- plementary information and do not form part of this report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The\nlying structure for reporting on management approaches and following passages are also not part of the nonfinancial report:\nthe specific standard disclosures.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In line with the German CSR\nDirective Implementation Act (CSR-Richtlinie-Umsetzungs- •",
    "entities": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "CSR",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "(p. 4–6)\ngesetz – CSR-RUG), this nonfinancial report concentrates on the • Value Chain (p. 12)\nfocus issues necessary for an understanding of the Volkswagen • The German Corporate Governance Code and\nGroup’s business development, overall performance and position Further Information (p. 13)\nas well as the Volkswagen Group’s impact on nonfinancial as- •",
    "entities": [
      [
        "4–6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the • Value Chain",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen •",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Further Information",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "•",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Making the Social and Environmental Impact\npects.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Social and Environmental Impact",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "We are reporting in detail on our climate protection activi- of Our Actions Measurable (p. 19)\nties in line with Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclo-\nsures (TCFD) requirements for the first time.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Our Actions Measurable",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "19",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Task Force",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Disclo-",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "TCFD",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The information in this report relates to the Volkswagen Group\nas a whole.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Where information relates to individual Group divi-\nThe Group Sustainability Report was prepared in compliance sions only, this is clearly indicated in the text.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Group Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Unless indicated\nwith the GRI Standards of the Global Reporting Initiative (GRI), otherwise, any information provided for the Group also applies\napplying the “Core” option.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the GRI Standards of the Global Reporting Initiative",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the “Core",
        "LAW"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In addition to Volkswagen AG, the Group\nincludes all major subsidiaries inside and outside Germany that\nThe strategy chapter and the six following chapters on focus are directly or indirectly controlled by Volkswagen AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The KPIs\nissues in the report each consist of a text section plus a and the associated targets include the Bugatti brand companies\n7\nTROPER\nSIHT\nTUOBA\non the topics of the UEP (the reduction of the environmental im- financial statements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Bugatti",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "TROPER\nSIHT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "UEP",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In fiscal year 2021, negative special items\npact of production), the DCI (the decarbonization index), the in connection with the diesel issue amounting to € -0.8 billion\nOpinion Survey and the diversity index on a pro rata basis up to affected operating profit in the Passenger Cars business area.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "fiscal year 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "DCI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "€ -0.8 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "Passenger Cars",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To\nand including October 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "October 2021",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "hedge the currently known legal risks related to the diesel issue,\nthe provisions for litigation and legal risks as of December 31,\nBugatti is not included in the accident figures.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Bugatti",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "2021 include an amount of around € 2.1 billion, based on exist-\ning information and current assessments.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "around € 2.1 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Insofar as these can\nNavistar International Corporation (Navistar), which was ac- be adequately measured at this stage, contingent liabilities relat-\nquired on July 1, 2021, is not included in the key figures or asso- ing to the diesel issue were disclosed in the notes to the consoli-\nciated targets on the topics of the UEP (the reduction of the envi- dated financial statements in an aggregate amount of € 4.3 bil-\nronmental impact of production), the DCI (the decarbonization lion, whereby € 3.6 billion of this amount results from lawsuits\nindex), the Opinion Survey or occupational safety (accident fig- filed by investors in Germany.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Navistar International Corporation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "July 1, 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "UEP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "4.3",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "DCI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "€ 3.6 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The provisions recognized, the\nures).",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Navistar is included in the diversity index.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Navistar",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In the financial contingent liabilities disclosed, and the other latent legal risks in\ndata, our joint ventures in China are reported using the equity ac-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "the context of the diesel issue are in part subject to substantial\ncounting method.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "However, they are included in full (100%) in estimation risks given the complexity of the individual relevant\nvolume-related data (sales, production and workforce) and in factors, the ongoing coordination with the authorities, and the\nproduction-related environmentally relevant data.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "100%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The manage- fact that the fact-finding efforts have not yet been concluded.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "ment approaches described in this report (e.g. the environmen- Should these legal or estimation risks materialize, this could re-\ntal compliance management system",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "[ECMS] and the compliance sult in further substantial financial charges.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In particular, ad-\nmanagement system for business and human rights [CMS BHR]) justment of the provisions recognized in light of knowledge ac-\napply to all the Volkswagen Group’s controlled companies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "CMS BHR",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With quired or events occurring in the future cannot be ruled out.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The\nour non controlled companies – i.e. companies that are not con- remaining provisions relate to a wide range of identifiable indi-\ntrolled by a company of the Volkswagen Group as the majority vidual risks, price risks and contingent liabilities, which are fac-\nowner – we work to the extent permitted by law toward imple- tored in in the amount of their probable occurrence.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Depending\nmentation of the adjusted management approaches.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Chinese on the jurisdiction concerned, risk provisions for any non-com-\njoint ventures are included in the information on the pliance with statutory emissions limits are also included.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Their\nVolkswagen Group in the KPIs and the associated targets on the measurement takes into account, among other things, the\ntopics of the UEP (the reduction of the environmental impact of respective sales volume and the legally defined tax or the cost of\nproduction), the DCI (the decarbonization index), the Opinion acquiring emission rights from other manufacturers.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "UEP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "DCI",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Advantage\nSurvey, the diversity index, accident indices and accident fig- has been taken of synergies between individual brands of the\nures.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The risks of the Chinese market are assessed by Volkswagen Volkswagen Group by establishing emission pools where possible.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "China Investment Company Ltd.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "China Investment Company Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Additional information on this matter and the valuation as-\nsumptions and bases can be found in the Annual Report in the\nThe KPIs presented in this report build on the indicators pre- notes to the consolidated financial statements.\nsented in previous years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Annual Report",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "previous years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Any material changes to the methods\nused to collect and measure the data on our sustainability per-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "ADDITIONAL REPORTING WITHIN THE GROUP\nformance are explicitly disclosed by the respective KPIs.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GROUP",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "All fig-\nures shown in the report are rounded, so minor discrepancies By referencing this combined separate nonfinancial report, all\nmay arise from addition of these amounts.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Group companies that are required by national legislation to\ndisclose nonfinancial and diversity-related information pursuant\nREPORT AUDITING to Directive 2014/95/EU but do not issue their own nonfinancial\nstatement are exempted from the obligation to submit their own\nErnst & Young GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft (EY) con- nonfinancial reports.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ernst & Young GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "ducted a voluntary, limited assurance engagement in accordance\nwith ISAE 3000 (Revised) on the combined separate nonfinancial TERMINOLOGY RELATING TO CLIMATE PROTECTION\nreport prepared in accordance with HGB sections 289b para.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISAE 3000 (",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289b",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "3 to verify that its disclosures comply with the relevant The use of the term CO emissions in this report includes the\n2\nstatutory requirements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Further information on the engagement consideration and identification of the additional climate-dam-\ncan be found in the independent practitioner’s report on a limited aging greenhouse gases methane (CH) and laughing gas (NO)\n4 2\nassurance engagement on the nonfinancial reporting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "4 2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "All figures in this report on CO emissions cor-\n2 2\nrespond to CO equivalents, except for fleet emission figures.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2 2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "2\nDISCLOSURES IN CONNECTION WITH THE ANNUAL\nFINANCIAL STATEMENTS Net carbon neutrality is achieved when anthropogenic CO emis-\n2\nsions are balanced worldwide through avoidance, reduction and\nConnections have been identified in this combined nonfinancial offsetting over a specific period of time.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ANNUAL",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "anthropogenic CO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With regard to climate\nreport to amounts reported in the 2021 annual or consolidated protection, in addition to CO emissions Volkswagen also pays\n2\n8\nTROPER\nSIHT\nTUOBA\nGRI 102-50, 102-51, 102-52\nattention to other relevant greenhouse gases.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "TROPER\nSIHT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "102-50",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-51",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Avoidance and re- LEGAL INFORMATION\nduction have priority over offsetting for the Volkswagen Group.\nFor offsetting measures, the Group follows the highest inter-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This sustainability report contains statements relating to the\nnationally established standards.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "future business development of the Volkswagen Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "These\nstatements are based on assumptions relating to the develop-\nEDITORIAL NOTES ment of the economic, political and legal environment in indi-\nvidual countries, economic regions and markets, and in particular\nWhenever this report uses the term Sustainability Report, this ex- for the automotive industry, which we have made on the basis of\npression includes the nonfinancial report each time it is men-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "the information available to us and which we consider to be real-\ntioned, to the extent described on page 7 .",
    "entities": [
      [
        "7",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "istic as of the time of going to press.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The estimates given involve\na degree of risk, and the actual developments may differ from\nREPORTING PRACTICES those forecast.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Any changes in significant parameters relating to\nour key sales markets, any significant shifts in exchange rates or\nThe nonfinancial report is published annually.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "annually",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The last non- commodities relevant to the Volkswagen Group or in parts supply\nfinancial report was published on March 16, 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "March 16, 2021",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In addition to (especially semiconductors), or any deviations in the actual effects\ninformation about the Group’s sustainability activities in the of the COVID-19 pandemic from the scenario presented in this re-\n2021 fiscal year (January 1 to December 31, 2021), this 2021 non- port will have a corresponding effect on the development of our\nfinancial report also contains selected information from the business.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021 fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "January 1 to December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In addition, there may be departures from our expected\n2022 fiscal year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2022 fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "business development if the assessments of the factors influencing\nsustainable value enhancement, and of risks and opportunities,\nABOUT THIS REPORT presented in this sustainability report develop in a way other\nthan we expect at the time of publication, or if additional risks\nThe editorial deadline was Friday, February 11, 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Friday, February 11",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Group and opportunities or other factors that affect the development of\nSustainability Report is published in German and English and is our business emerge.\nreleased in the first quarter of 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "LANGUAGE"
      ],
      [
        "English",
        "LANGUAGE"
      ],
      [
        "the first quarter",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "9\nTROPER\nSIHT\nTUOBA\nSUSTAINABILIT Y IN\nTHE GROUP’S DNA\n10\nCORPORATE GOVERNANCE GRI 102-1, 102-2, 102-3, 102-4, 102-5, 102-6, 102-7, 102-8\nOUTLINE OF THE LEGAL STRUCTURE OF THE GROUP www.volkswagenag.com > Investor Relations\nVolkswagen AG is the parent company of the Volkswagen Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "TROPER\nSIHT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SUSTAINABILIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Investor Relations\n",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Volkswagen AG is a vertically integrated energy supply company\nThe parent company’s head office is Wolfsburg.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Wolfsburg",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It develops vehicles as defined by section 3 no.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "section 3 no.",
        "LAW"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "38 of the German Energy Industry Act\nand components for the Group brands",
    "entities": [
      [
        "38",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the German Energy Industry Act",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "but also produces and sells (Energiewirtschaftsgesetz – EnWG) and is therefore subject to the\nvehicles, in particular passenger cars and light commercial vehicles provisions of the EnWG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Energiewirtschaftsgesetz",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "EnWG",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In the electricity sector, Volkswagen AG\nfor the Volkswagen Passenger Cars and Volkswagen Commercial generates, sells and distributes electricity together with Group\nVehicles brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In its capacity as parent company, Volkswagen AG subsidiaries.\nholds direct or indirect interests in AUDI AG, SEAT S.A.,",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "AUDI AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SEAT S.A.",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "ŠKODA AUTO\na.s., Dr. Ing.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "a.s.",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Ing",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "h.c. F. Porsche AG, TRATON SE, Volkswagen Financial The Volkswagen AG Board of Management has sole responsibility\nServices AG, Volkswagen Bank GmbH and a large number of other for managing the Company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "F. Porsche AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Financial",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Services AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Bank GmbH",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board appoints,\ncompanies in Germany and abroad.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "More detailed disclosures can monitors and advises the Board of Management and is directly\nbe found in the list of shareholdings in accordance with sections consulted on decisions of fundamental significance for\n285 and 313 of the German Commercial Code (Handelsgesetzbuch – the Company.\nHGB) or accessed on our website.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "285",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "313",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "VOLKSWAGEN AG SHAREHOLDER STRUCTURE EMPLOYEES BY MARKET\nas of December 31, 2021, by % of subscribed capital as of December 31, 2021, in %\nGerman institutional Porsche Automobil Europe (excluding\ninvestors 3.3 Holding SE 31.4 South America 4 Germany)/other\nmarkets 30\nState of Lower Saxony11.8 North America 6\nQatar Holding LLC 10.5 Asia-Pacific15\nForeign institutional\nPrivate shareholders/ investors 27 Germany 44\nothers 16\nORGANIZATIONAL group, the other Board positions are Purchasing, Technology, Fi-\nSTRUCTURE OF THE GROUP nance, Human Resources and Truck & Bus, Integrity and Legal\nAffairs, Premium, Sport & Luxury, and China.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "VOLKSWAGEN AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Porsche Automobil Europe",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "3.3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "31.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "South America",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "30",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "State of Lower Saxony11.8 North America 6",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Qatar Holding",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "10.5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Asia",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "27",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "44",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "16",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Purchasing, Technology",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GROUP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Human Resources and Truck & Bus",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Premium, Sport & Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Until December 31,\nThe Volkswagen Group is one of the leading multi-brand groups in 2021, the Chair of the Board of Management was also responsible\nthe automotive industry.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Chair of the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Group’s business activities comprise for China and the Board member for IT was also responsible for\nthe Automotive and Financial Services divisions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "All brands within Finance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Finance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Since February 1, 2022, a separate Board member has\nthe Automotive Division – with the exception of the Volkswagen been responsible for the IT Board position.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "February 1",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Board position\nPassenger Cars and Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles brands – are with responsibility for China was once again allocated to a dedi-\nindependent legal entities.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Passenger Cars",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Automotive Division comprises the cated Board member, to take effect on August 1, 2022.\nPassenger Cars, Commercial Vehicles and Power Engineering busi-\nness areas.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "August 1",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Passenger Cars",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Commercial Vehicles",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Power Engineering",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Passenger Cars Business Area essentially consoli-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Passenger Cars Business Area",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Alongside the brand groups, Volkswagen continued to build the\ndates the Volkswagen Group’s passenger car brands and the Group company CARIAD SE in the reporting year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the reporting year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It is pooling and\nVolkswagen Commercial Vehicles brand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Activities focus on the de- expanding the Volkswagen Group’s software expertise and will of-\nvelopment of vehicles, engines and vehicle software, the produc- fer a standardized operating system for the vehicles of the Group\ntion and sale of passenger cars and light commercial vehicles, and brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "the genuine parts business.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The product portfolio extends from\nsmall cars through to luxury vehicles in the premium segment.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It Effective from the beginning of 2021, the former Components &\nalso includes motorcycles and is supplemented by mobility solu- Procurement Board division was split up and two new Board posi-\ntions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Components &\n",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Procurement Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With its brands, the Volkswagen Group is present in all rele- tions created for Procurement and Technology.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Procurement and Technology",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The new Technol-\nvant markets around the world.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Technol-",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The key sales markets currently ogy Board position will be responsible for all Group Components\ninclude Western Europe, China, the USA, Brazil, Russia, Mexico, activities across the Group, the marketing of the Volkswagen plat-\nPoland and Turkey.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group Components",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Western Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "USA",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Brazil",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Mexico",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Poland",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Turkey",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "forms to third parties, the development and manufacturing of\nbattery cells as well as the associated procurement, the areas of\nResponsibilities were divided between ten Board of Management charging and charging systems ,and the corresponding joint\npositions until December 31, 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "third",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ten",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In addition to the Chair of the ventures worldwide.\nBoard of Management, which also includes the Volume brand\n11\nAND\nS’PUORG\nEHT\nNI\nYTILIBANIATSUS\nGRI 102-2, 102-9\nThe Supervisory Board resolved in December 2021 to increase the with the principle of subsidiarity, decisions will be taken at the\nnumber of members in the Group Board of Management and to re- lowest competent level, close to business operations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Chair of the ventures",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "11",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "December 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "For fur-\norganize the structure and functions of the Board of Management ther information, see the “Structure and Business Activities”\nin this context.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the “Structure and Business Activities",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The new Board position, Volkswagen Passenger chapter in the Annual Report.\nCars, was established with effect from January 1, 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Passenger",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Annual Report",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "January 1",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Another\nnew Board position, Group Sales, was created effective February 1, 2021 Annual Report > Group Management Report > Structure\n2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group Sales",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "February 1",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Annual Report > Group Management Report > Structure\n2022",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "and Business Activities\nThe “Volume” brand group comprises the Volkswagen Passenger LEGAL FACTORS INFLUENCING BUSINESS\nCars, SEAT/CUPRA, ŠKODA and Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles\nbrands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Business Activities",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Passenger LEGAL",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ŠKODA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Since March 1, 2021, Bentley has been assigned to the Like other international companies, the business of Volkswagen\n“Premium” brand group, which previously comprised the Audi, companies is affected by numerous laws, domestically and\nLambor ghini and Ducati brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "March 1, 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Bentley",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Audi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ducati",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Following the departure of abroad.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In particular, there are legal requirements relating to\nBugatti from the Group’s brand portfolio in November 2021, services, development, products, production and distribution,\nthe Sport & Luxury brand group now only comprises the Porsche as well as supervisory, data protection, financial, company,\nbrand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Bugatti",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "November 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Sport & Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Porsche",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Truck & Bus brand group is the umbrella for the Scania, commercial, capital market, anti-trust and tax regulations as\nMAN and Navistar commercial vehicles brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Truck & Bus",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Scania",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Navistar",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "well as regulations relating to labor, banking, state-aid, energy,\nenvironmental and insurance law.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Our management model means better use can be made of exist-\ning skills and economies of scale, synergy effects can be boost-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "THE GERMAN CORPORATE GOVERNANCE CODE – A BLUEPRINT\ned more systematically and decision-making can be accelerated.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GERMAN",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "FOR SUCCESSFUL CORPORATE GOVERNANCE",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In addition, this prepares the Volkswagen Group for a manage-\nment structure that is simpler, leaner and more effective, and Corporate governance provides the regulatory framework for cor-\nstrengthens the brands, giving them more autonomy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In line porate management and supervision.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This includes a company’s\nTHE VOLKSWAGEN VALUE CHAIN\nRESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT\nThe Volkswagen Group is further advancing its transformation to a digital mobility group and will invest around € 89 billion in future\ntechnologies such as electric mobility and digitalization in the next five years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "VOLKSWAGEN",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "around € 89 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "the next five years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "PROCUREMENT\nEvery year, the Volkswagen Group purchases a wide range of raw materials, components and other goods.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Every year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A sustainable supply chain and\nenvironmentally compatible transportation are important for fully assuming responsibility for human rights, environmental protection and the\nbattle against corruption.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "PRODUCTION\nEvery working day, the Volkswagen Group manufactures an average of around 33,000 vehicles globally.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Every working day",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "around 33,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Efficient production ranks alongside\nenvironmental protection and employee health and safety as one of our core goals.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "MARKETING & SALES\nBusiness relationships with fleet customers are often long-term and stable partnerships.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "MARKETING & SALES\nBusiness",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Volkswagen Group’s share of commercial fleet\ncustomers is 42.1% in Germany and 26.5% in the rest of Europe.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "42.1%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "26.5%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "AFTER-SALES & FINANCIAL SERVICES\nOur service includes supporting dealerships to ensure they can provide quality advice and maintenance, managing our original parts business,\nand providing vehicle-related financial services.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In addition to recycling vehicles at the end of their useful life, we pay close attention during the new-vehicle development stage to the\nrecyclability of the required materials, the use of high-quality recycled materials, and the avoidance of pollutants.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "12\nAND\nS’PUORG\nEHT\nNI\nYTILIBANIATSUS\norganization and values, and the principles and guidelines for its Extensive explanations of the remuneration system and the\nbusiness policy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The German Corporate Governance Code (the individual remuneration of the members of the Board of\nCode) contains principles, recommendations and suggestions for Management and Supervisory Board can be found in the\ncorporate management and supervision.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The German",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of\nCode",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Management and Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Its principles, recommen- Remuneration Report for fiscal year 2021, which forms part of the\ndations and suggestions were prepared by a dedicated government 2021 Annual Report, in the notes to Volkswagen’s 2021\ncommission on the basis of the material provisions and nationally consolidated financial statements and in the notes to the 2021\nand internationally accepted standards of sound, responsible cor- annual financial statements of Volkswagen AG.\nporate governance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Remuneration Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "fiscal year 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Annual Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In the interests of best practice, the government\ncommission regularly reviews the Code’s relevance in light of cur- www.volkswagenag.com > Investor Relations >\nrent developments and updates it as necessary.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Code",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Board of Man- Corporate Governance > Remuneration\nagement and the Supervisory Board of Volkswagen AG base their\nwork on the Code’s principles, recommendations and suggestions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board of",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Code",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "In 2021, the Volkswagen AG Group Board of Management adopted\nWe consider good corporate governance to be a key prerequisite for an update of the tax strategy principles, which can be found on our\nachieving a lasting increase in the Company’s value.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Group Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Company",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It helps website.\nstrengthen the trust of our shareholders, customers, employees,\nbusiness partners and investors in our work and enables us to meet Each year, Volkswagen AG sends the German Federal Central Tax\nthe steadily increasing demand for information from national and Office a country-by-country report, which includes information on\ninternational stakeholders.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Each year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the German Federal Central Tax",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "national and Office",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "You can find our published Declaration tax payments and tax expenses/income by country.\nof Conformity with the German Corporate Governance Code here:\nThe Volkswagen Group has the ambition of implementing its mar-\nwww.volkswagenag.com > Investor Relations > Corporate keting and communication activities transparently and responsibly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Governance This includes attentiveness towards our environment and requires\nus to treat all individuals with respect and honesty and as equals.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This applies internally and externally, online and off.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To this end, the\nGroup has developed principles that serve as a compass for imple-\nExplanations of the composition, working methods and diversity menting the Volkswagen Group’s values with regard to marketing\nconcept of the Board of Management and the Supervisory Board and communication activities.\nand information on voting rights are available in the “Corporate\nGovernance” chapter in the 2021 Annual Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the\nGroup",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Corporate\nGovernance",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Annual Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "www.volkswagenag.com >",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Sustainability >\nStrategy & Reporting > Policy\n2021 Annual Financial Statements > Corporate Governance\n13\nAND\nS’PUORG\nEHT\nNI\nYTILIBANIATSUS\nNEW AUTO GROUP STRATEGY\nWith the new Group strategy “NEW AUTO – Mobility for Genera-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Strategy & Reporting",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "THE 12 INITIATIVES OF THE NEW AUTO STRATEGY\ntions to Come”, we are preparing ourselves for the global changes\nin mobility and thus driving Volkswagen’s transformation into a The Group strategy consists of 12 initiatives in total.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The focus is\nsoftware-driven company.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "on the technology initiatives Mechatronics, Software, Battery,\nCharging and Mobility Solutions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mechatronics, Software",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Battery",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Mobility Solutions",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A further seven initiatives form\nWith the TOGETHER 2025+ Group strategy, which the Group the basis for the Volkswagen Group’s strategic realignment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "seven",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "These\nenhanced in 2019, Volkswagen kicked off one of the biggest pro- are ESG, Decarbonization & Integrity, Business Model 2.0, NAR and\ncesses of change in its corporate history with the aim of making China Regions, Group Steering Model, People & Transformation,\nthe Group more focused, efficient, innovative, customer-oriented and Financing the Transformation.\nand sustainable, and systematically gearing it toward profitable\ngrowth.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Decarbonization & Integrity",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NAR",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China Regions, Group Steering Model, People & Transformation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Financing the Transformation",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "These strategies have provided the framework and key To make the goals of the strategy’s various initiatives as transparent\npillars with which we aim to achieve our vision of being a world- as possible for management and employees, the Group Board of\nleading provider of sustainable mobility.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Group Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Management has decided to structure and regularly measure the\nstrategic goals and milestones using the OKR (objectives and key\nAs technology advances, the automotive industry is forging ahead results) method.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "OKR",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This means that, for each initiative, achievable\nwith the transformation toward e-mobility and digitalization.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The objectives will be defined for each quarter along with envisaged\nmarket for electric vehicles will thus continue to grow strongly in key results, and their progress discussed with the Board of Manage-\nthe next few years, meaning that cost-efficient and sustainable pro- ment every three months.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "each quarter",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Manage-",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the next few years",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "every three months",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "duction of battery systems and the expansion of charging infra-\nstructure will be crucial to success.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "MECHATRONICS\nThe shift to connected, intelligent and eventually self-driving Innovation, technology and lasting competitiveness are to be en-\nvehicles, however, will bring more wide-reaching changes for the sured using a future-oriented mechatronics platform.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "A standard\nautomotive industry.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This shift will be dependent on increasing platform known as the SSP – Scalable Systems Platform will enable\nsoftware development capabilities so as to excite customers with maximum synergy effects, reduced investment costs and fast,\nconstantly improving digital functionality.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Scalable Systems Platform",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The most important regular technology updates, while also providing the necessary\nmilestone in this context is the development of autonomous driv- product differentiation in the Group’s portfolio.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It will form the\ning, which will change customers’ experience of mobility forever basis for autonomous driving and help us offer electric cars for all.\nand pave the way to new business models.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "SOFTWARE\nAs with technological trends, global economic as well as geopolitical\nconstraints are increasingly confronting the automobile industry Software-based customer functions (such as driver assistance sys-\nwith greater challenges, for example the economic influence wield- tems) have already improved driving comfort and vehicle safety\ned by our biggest mobility markets, China, USA and Europe, and the significantly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "USA",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "As vehicles become fully connected in future and\nway they are diverging.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Chinese economy will continue to gain increasingly complex software technologies are developed (for\ninfluence and grow rapidly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The enormous growth in economic instance with the aid of artificial intelligence), a completely new\noutput (GDP) underlines the importance of the Asian market.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Asian",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "experience of mobility and additional product differentiation will\nbecome possible, due in part to the development of automated\nSustainability will continue to be a recurring theme in the business driving.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To maximize synergies in the development of software\nworld, driven by the increasingly noticeable consequences of cli- platforms and software-driven customer functions, the Volkswagen\nmate change and customers’ greater awareness of sustainable Group will combine this development expertise with CARIAD’s\nlifestyles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "new software architecture E³ 2.0.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Software strategy initiative\nthus comprises measures to drive the development of software\nIn the context of the fast-changing environment and the challenges platforms for connectivity and automated driving and their roll-\nresulting from it, the Group Board of Management adopted the out to all the Group’s vehicles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Software",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "new Group strategy “NEW AUTO – Mobility for Generations to\nCome” in May 2021 with the approval of the Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "May 2021",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The BATTERY\nstrategy’s focus is the world of mobility in 2030.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BATTERY",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With NEW AU-\nTO, we are Energy, batteries and charging are becoming one of our core\nresetting our priorities and developing the necessary expertise as competencies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Energy",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To achieve our strategic objectives, we must\nwe continue our transition from automotive manufacturer to become a profitable expert along the entire battery life cycle.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Alongside software development and capabilities To this end, the Cell and Battery Strategy initiative will pool ex-\nin autonomous driving, this also includes areas such as battery pertise from all across the Group and drive the transformation\ntechnology, battery recycling, charging infrastructure and mobility process together with our strategic partners.\nservices.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Cell and Battery Strategy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "14\nAND\nS’PUORG\nEHT\nNI\nYTILIBANIATSUS\nCHARGING sales is concentrated on this growth market.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "This strategy initia-\ntive therefore brings together all key measures to continue the\nCoordinated and cohesive cooperation within the Group is success story of Volkswagen in China.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "It includes a comprehen-\nneeded to establish Volkswagen as a global, comprehensive sive program of measures to expand market share in the electric\ncharging and energy services provider in future.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Charging vehicle segment and safeguard market share in combustion en-\nand Energy Services initiative will combine related activities gine models.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Energy Services",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The core component remains a Group-wide local-\nacross the brands, create synergies and drive the creation of a ization strategy, which aims to offer Chinese customers tailored\ndense and comprehensive charging network.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "products using globally developed platform technologies (hard-\nware and software).",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "MOBILITY SOLUTIONS\nGROUP STEERING MODEL",
    "entities": [
      [
        "MOBILITY SOLUTIONS\nGROUP",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "With the motto “Mobility for Generations to Come”, the\nVolkswagen Group is developing the mobility solutions of the To implement the Group strategy and achieve long-term success\nfuture, taking into account global trends and changing customer for the Volkswagen Group, we need to establish mechanisms for\nneeds.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Mobility for Generations to Come”",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Autonomous driving, combined with new mobility making swift decisions and realizing synergy effects at a consis-\nsolutions, is expected to mark Volkswagen’s transformation tently high level and keep enhancing them further.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The updated\ninto one of the leading providers of sustainable mobility.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Group steering model hones the definition of responsibilities\nand roles and provides transparency, thus strengthening collab-\nESG, DECARBONIZATION & INTEGRITY oration within the Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Combined with a reoriented financial\nmanagement along the brand groups and cross-brand value drivers,\nESG (Environmental, Social, Governance) refers to the basic the Volkswagen Group is creating a future-oriented governance\nprinciples of doing business sustainably.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Group’s stakehold- model to match the changing environment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "ers (e.g. investors, employees, customers and NGOs) have high\nexpectations of the Company’s ESG performance, including on PEOPLE & TRANSFORMATION\nissues such as decarbonization and integrity.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Company",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "PEOPLE & TRANSFORMATION",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The ESG perfor-\nmance thus directly affects the Group’s market capitalization With its intended transformation into a global tech company,\nand the cost of capital as well as, for example, its attractiveness the Volkswagen Group will undertake the biggest transforma-\nas an employer.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The ESG Group initiative therefore aims to tion of its workforce in its history.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The ESG Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To ensure the Group remains\nimprove the Group’s ESG performance in order, among other competitive in future, we need to attract and retain top talent\nthings, to ensure it can attract investment and to optimize its and support employees with extensive training provision.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "Aligning the structure of the workforce with the fields that will\ndrive the future will also be centrally important.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "BUSINESS MODEL 2.0\nFINANCING THE TRANSFORMATION",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "By connecting vehicles, we will be able in future to remain in\ncontact with customers throughout the vehicle life cycle and The transformation being driven by digitalization and electrifi-\nthus to offer them services and functions for their individual cation will require substantial investment.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "To cover this financing\nneeds.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "The Business Model 2.0 initiative is developing a Group- requirement, the “Financing the Transformation” initiative\nwide portfolio of services that aims to create a seamless and intends, in the light of the two issues of costs and efficiency,\ninnovative product experience to connect brands, customers, to leverage even more Group-wide synergies across all areas of\ndealerships, our partners and whole markets.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the “Financing the Transformation",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2021,
    "sentence": "activity along the value chain.",
    "entities": [],
