[
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "SUSTAINABILITY REPORT\n\n“The coronavirus pandemic hit the Volkswagen Group at the start of 2020, in the middle of one of the largest transformation processes in the history of our Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "From the start, our focus has been on protecting our employees and our business against the threat of COVID-19.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Despite this massive challenge, at the same time we further advanced the Group’s restructuring toward decarbonization and mobility for future generations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "My express thanks go to everyone who successfully contributed to this, specifically to our 662,000 employees of the Volkswagen Group around the world and to our stakeholders.”",
    "entities": [
      [
        "662,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Gunnar Kilian Member of the Board of Management of Volkswagen AG with responsibility for Human Resources and “Truck & Bus” Head of the Volkswagen Crisis Team\n\nD ECARBONIZATION CONTENTS 45 Decarbonization\n\nFOREWORD CIRCULAR ECONOMY ABOUT THIS REPORT 55 Circular Economy 1 4 STRATEGY AND MANAGEMENT RESPONSIBILITY IN SUPPLY CHAINS AND BUSINESS 10 Group Governance, Goals and TOGETHER 2025+",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Kilian",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management of Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Human Resources",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Truck & Bus",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Crisis Team",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "45",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Decarbonization",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "FOREWORD",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "55",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1 4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "BUSINESS 10 Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Strategy 60 Responsibility in Our Group 15 Sustainability and Materiality 64 Responsibility in Our Supply Chain 18 Sustainability Management 21 Stakeholder Management 24 Corporate Citizenship 26 Digitalization 5 33 Integrity and Compliance W ORKFORCE T RANSFORMATION 39 Risk Management 41 Environmental Management 70",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Our Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "15",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Materiality 64 Responsibility",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "18",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "21",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "24",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "26",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "W ORKFORCE",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "39",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "41",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Workforce Transformation A detailed description of the sustainability activities of our brands and regions and of APPENDIX the Volkswagen Group’s CC projects is available at: www.volkswagenag.com > Sustainability > Reporting 81 About the Nonfinancial Report (NFR) NAVIGATION 83 Tables and KPIs 94 Independent Auditor’s Limited References to chapters in the sustainability report Assurance Report References to websites 96 Contact Information References to the Annual Report References to the nonfinancial report (highlighted in chapter color, see “About the Report”)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "APPENDIX",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "CC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "81",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Nonfinancial Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "83",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "94",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Independent Auditor’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Assurance Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "96",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Contact Information References to the Annual Report References",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "About the Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "STNETNOC FO ELBAT FOREWORD GRI 102-14, 102-15, 102-16 Dr. Herbert Diess, Bernd Osterloh, Chairman of the Board of Management Chairman of the General and of Volkswagen AG Group Works Council of Volkswagen AG Ladies and gentlemen, Dear colleagues, Volkswagen has lived up to its corporate responsibility even in 2020, the year of the coronavirus.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ELBAT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "102-14",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-15",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Herbert Diess",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Bernd Osterloh",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Group Works Council of Volkswagen AG Ladies",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "As one of the largest employers in the world, the Group coordinated and donated aid supplies internationally, conducted 25,000 coronavirus tests, organized employee projects and produced medical equipment.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "25,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Thanks to the broad product portfolio and regional positioning, the Group has remained financially robust while navigating the crisis.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "At the same time, addressing the consequences of the pandemic has provided an opportunity for sustainable economic restructuring: in 2020, three times more electric vehicles were sold than in the previous year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the previous year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Group has launched a unique e-model offensive with the Volkswagen ID.3 and ID.4, the Porsche Taycan, Audi e-tron and Skoda Enyaq iV as well as numerous hybrid models.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Audi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Skoda Enyaq",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In 2020, we tripled our unit sales of e-vehicles in the Group and were able to reduce our CO2 fleet average in the EU by around 20 percent.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "around 20 percent",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We are convinced that the battery-electric drive is, for the foreseeable future, the only solution for achieving the goals of the Paris Agreement.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Paris Agreement",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Within the Group we have also set the goal of attaining a climate-neutral footprint worldwide by 2050 at the latest – this includes our supply chains, plants and business divisions and our customers’ use of the vehicles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2050",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "On our path to climate-neutral mobility, we seek to collaborate with society and politicians.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We believe that a reduction in CO2 emissions within the scope of the EU Green Deal of at least 55% by 2030 compared to 1990 levels is attainable, if the appropriate measures are implemented across all sectors as part of a joint effort.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "at least 55%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "1990",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "As a member of the Europe-wide CEO Alliance, we are therefore working on the cross-sectoral decarbonization of the economy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Volkswagen sees itself as part of the solution, not the problem.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "For Volkswagen, social sustainability is just as important as environmental.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The focus on e-mobility will change employment at Volkswagen.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "A study carried out for Volkswagen by the Fraunhofer\n\nDROWEROF Institute has worked out exactly how.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Fraunhofer",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "DROWEROF Institute",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The experts say that in the next ten years, job creation, job improvement and job elimination will coexist.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the next ten years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The findings show that Volkswagen’s employment needs are going to fall less sharply than previous studies had suggested due to e-mobility and digitalization.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We can sustainably manage the transformation of the workforce if the right measures are introduced.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "At Volkswagen, these primarily include additional training and retraining, the transformation of the components segment in the Group and the Digital Transformation Roadmap.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Digital Transformation Roadmap",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Profitability is a prerequisite for job security.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Fraunhofer study was commissioned by the Volkswagen’s Sustainability Council.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Fraunhofer",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Council",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "It contributes external, international and cross-sectoral sustainability expertise to our strategies.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In 2020, we extended collaboration with the Council by a further two years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Council",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "two years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In addition to ad hoc management of the coronavirus crisis, Volkswagen has continued to focus on its competitiveness, securing jobs, the future viability of jobs, protecting health and enabling a work/life balance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Our Social Charter has also undergone revision.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We successfully completed the Monitorship in 2020 that was part of the agreements with the US authorities following the diesel issue.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Monitorship",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In collaboration with Larry Thompson and his monitor team, Volkswagen met its commitment to sustainably improve compliance within the Company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Larry Thompson",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The change in structures, processes and systems has made us a stronger business.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Together with our employees, we will continue work on the change in corporate culture in the future – integrity is not a project with a beginning and an end but an ongoing task.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "As part of our sustainability strategy, we have succeeded in anchoring sustainability more firmly in the Group’s core business.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We set ourselves strong, measurable targets for the four focus areas of decarbonization, circular economy, responsibility in the supply chain & business and transformation of the workforce.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This ensures an effective operationalization of sustainability, with clear responsibilities and processes.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Sustainable business practices are also playing an increasingly important role for our investors.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We are taking this into account by anchoring an ESG action plan in our Group strategy and in doing so, want to contribute to permanently increasing our Company’s value.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Volkswagen Group’s readmission to the UN Global Compact at the start of 2021 is another signal of confidence for our stakeholders and at the same time proof of our strategy’s effectiveness.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the UN Global Compact",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The “Shaping mobility – for generations to come” vision of our TOGETHER 2025+ Group strategy guides us in all our activities.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "It is our responsibility to contribute to the sustainability of environmental, social and economic systems for us and for generations to come.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We are working on this every day.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "this every day",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Best regards, Herbert Diess Bernd Osterloh\n\nDROWEROF ABOUT THIS REPORT GRI 102-45, 102-48, 102-49, 102-50, 102-51, 102-52 REPORT STRUCTURE",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Herbert Diess",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Bernd Osterloh",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "DROWEROF",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "102-45",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-50",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-51",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In addition, the Sustainability Report takes account of additional GRI Standards of the Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) and sustainability For the fourth time, this 2020 Group Sustainability Report includes rating requirements, stakeholder expectations and special issues.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI Standards",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "fourth",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "a combined separate nonfinancial report that complies with sections 289b para.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "289b",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "3 of the Handelsgesetzbuch Strategy and Management > Sustainability Management (HGB – German Commercial Code), hereinafter referred to as the “nonfinancial report”.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The nonfinancial report serves to meet the All text passages, tables and graphics in the Group Sustainability disclosure requirements of the CSR Richtlinie-Umsetzungsgesetz Report that form part of the nonfinancial report are highlighted.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group Sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Richtlinie-Umsetzungsgesetz Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "(CSR-RUG – German CSR Directive Implementation Act).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Group Sustainability Report 2020 is supplemented by a detailed description of the sustainability activities of our brands and The requirements of the CSR-RUG on disclosing nonfinancial infor- regions and of the Volkswagen Group’s CSR projects.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Group Sustainability Report 2020",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "CSR",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "CSR",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This additional mation in accordance with section 315c in conjunction with sec- information, which does not form part of the nonfinancial report, tions 289c to 289e HGB were taken into account in the materiality can be found on the Volkswagen Group’s corporate website at: analysis process for the Volkswagen Group’s sustainability narrative.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "315c",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "289c",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "289e",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The process also includes an analysis of the United Nations Sus- www.volkswagenag.com > Sustainability > Reporting tainable Development Goals (SDGs).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the United Nations",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Development Goals",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The nonfinancial report covers both the focus areas and the enablers of the materiality analysis.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "SUSTAINABILITY COMMUNICATION AT VOLKSWAGEN GROUP 2020 WEBSITE SHIFT, THE ADDITIONAL SUSTAINABILITY REPORT SUSTAINABILITY COMMUNICATION MAGAZINE https://www.volkswagenag.com/ https://www.volkswagenag.com/ https://www.volkswagen de/sustainability/reporting.html de/sustainability/shift.html newsroom.com/de 2020",
    "entities": [
      [
        "VOLKSWAGEN",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "THE ADDITIONAL SUSTAINABILITY REPORT SUSTAINABILITY COMMUNICATION MAGAZINE https://www.volkswagenag.com/ https://www.volkswagenag.com/ https://www.volkswagen de/sustainability/reporting.html de/sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Nonfinancial including brands and regions as Statement well as CC projects BASIS FOR REPORT The information in this report relates to the Volkswagen Group as a whole.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "CC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Where information relates to individual Group divisions only, For reporting year 2020, Volkswagen AG will for the fourth time issue this is clearly indicated in the text.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "year 2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "fourth",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Unless indicated otherwise, any a nonfinancial statement at company level and a nonfinancial Group information provided for the Group also applies to Volkswagen AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "declaration, which will be published together as a combined sepa-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In addition to Volkswagen AG, the Group includes all major subsidirate nonfinancial report in the sense of HGB sections 289b para.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289b",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "3 aries inside and outside Germany that are directly or indirectly and 315b para.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "315b para",
        "PRODUCT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "as part of the 2020 Group Sustainability Report. controlled by Volkswagen AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the 2020 Group Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Renk AG, which was sold on October",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Renk AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "October",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The nonfinancial report is drawn up in accordance with HGB sec- 6, 2020, is not taken into account in this information.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6, 2020",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In the finantion 315c in conjunction with sections 289c through 289e.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "315c",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "289c",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "289e",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "cial data, our joint ventures in China are reported using the equity more, the GRI Standards of the Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) accounting method.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the GRI Standards of the Global Reporting Initiative",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "However, they are included in full (100%) in were used as the framework for drawing up the nonfinancial report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "100%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "volume-related data (sales, production and workforce) and in proIn this nonfinancial report, Volkswagen has systematically used duction-related environmentally relevant data.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The management the GRI Standards as the underlying structure for reports on manage- approaches described in this report (e.g. the environmental compliment approaches and the specific standard disclosures.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In line ance management system (ECMS) and the compliance managewith CSR-RUG, this nonfinancial report will concentrate on focus ment system for business and human rights (CMS BHR) etc.) apply areas and enablers that are necessary for an understanding of the to all the Volkswagen Group’s controlled companies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ance",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "CSR",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "CMS BHR",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "With our nonVolkswagen Group’s business development, overall performance controlled companies, we work to the extent permitted by law toand position as well as the Volkswagen Group’s influence on non-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "nonVolkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "ward implementation of the adjusted management approaches.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The financial aspects.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Chinese joint ventures are included in the information on the Volkswagen Group in the KPIs and the associated targets on the topics of the UEP (the reduction of the environmental impact of\n\nTROPER SIHT TUOBA production), the DCI (the decarbonization index), the Opinion Sur- new vehicle registrations (of cars or light commercial vehicles) of vey, the diversity index, accident indices and accident figures.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "UEP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "TROPER SIHT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "DCI",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Ex- the manufacturers in this emission pool.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Group CO2 fleet value cept for the sites under construction, all the Chinese joint ventures’ is the value derived from the official monitoring for the Group sites have a certified environmental management system and all brands that are members of the “VW-SAIC POOL (open)” emission the Chinese joint ventures’ vehicle-producing sites have an occupa- pool.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "If the Group brands are in an emission pool with third-party tional safety management system.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "third",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The risks of the Chinese market manufacturers – as was the case in 2020 – the Group CO2 fleet value are assessed by Volkswagen China Investment Company Ltd.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen China Investment Company Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In our is not derived directly from the published documents.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "whistleblower system, whistleblower information concerning our Chinese joint ventures is processed via the regional investigation REPORT REVIEW office at Volkswagen (China) Investment Company Ltd. Ernst & Young GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft (EY) conIn terms of content, the Group Sustainability Report was prepared ducted a voluntary, limited assurance engagement in accordance in compliance with the GRI Standards of the Global Reporting with ISAE 3000 (Revised) on the combined separate nonfinancial Initia tive (GRI), applying the “Core” option.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen (China) Investment Company Ltd. Ernst & Young GmbH Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Group Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the GRI Standards of the Global Reporting",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ISAE 3000 (",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Initia",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the “Core",
        "LAW"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The strategy chapter report prepared in accordance with HGB sections 289b para.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289b",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "and and the four following chapters on focus issues in the report con- 315b para.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "315b",
        "PRODUCT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "3 to verify that its disclosures comply with the relevant sist of a text section; a consolidated KPI table for the entire report statutory requirements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "KPI",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "follows with a breakdown for the respective chapter on a focus issue in the appendix.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "appendix",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "At the same time, the separate GRI Content In-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI Content In-",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Further information on the engagement can be found in the indedex shows how we are implementing the requirements of the Unit- pendent practitioner’s report on a limited assurance engagement ed Nations Global Compact (UNGC) and using the United Nations on the nonfinancial reporting.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Nations Global Compact",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the United Nations",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) as guidance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainable Development Goals",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The GRI Content Index has been separated from the 2020 Sustainability Report ADDITIONAL REPORTING WITHIN THE GROUP and can be found as a separate document in the Group portal at: The nonfinancial report is drawn up in accordance with HGB secwww.volkswagenag.com > Sustainability > Reporting tion 315c in conjunction with sections 289c through 289e.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI Content",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the 2020 Sustainability Report ADDITIONAL",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "315c",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "289c",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "289e",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "By referencing this combined separate nonfinancial report, all Group comThe KPIs presented in this report build on the indicators presented panies required by national legislation to disclose nonfinancial and in previous years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "previous years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Any material changes to the methods used to diversity-related information pursuant to Directive 2014 / 95 / EU collect and measure the data on our sustainability performance are are exempted from the obligation to submit their own nonfinanexplicitly disclosed by the respective KPIs.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Directive 2014 / 95 /",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "All figures shown in the cial reports.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "report are rounded, so minor discrepancies may arise from addition of these amounts.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "All figures in this report on CO2 except for More detailed insights into our environmental management apthe CO2 fleet values correspond to CO2 equivalents.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "proach can be found in the environmental statements published by numerous Group locations as part of their voluntary participation CALCULATION OF FLEET EMISSIONS IN EUROPE in the European Eco-Management and Audit Scheme (EMAS).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EUROPE",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "the European Eco-Management and Audit Scheme",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EMAS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The sustainability reports published by the Audi, MAN, Porsche, Scania The CO2 fleet values are determined for each calendar year in ac- and ŠKODA brands also bear testimony to the Group’s commitment cordance with Regulation (EU) 2019 / 631 within the European Un- to sustainability.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Audi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Porsche",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Scania",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "each calendar year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "ŠKODA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "631",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "European",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "ion (plus Norway and Iceland).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Norway",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Iceland",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "They are initially provisionally calculated within the framework of the official monitoring of the REPORTING PRACTICES European Commission (the Directorate-General for Climate Action [DG Climate]) with the involvement of the European Environment The nonfinancial report and Group Sustainability Report are pubAgency (EEA) and are then published by way of implementing act lished annually.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the European Environment",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EEA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "annually",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In addition to information about the Group’s susfollowing successful review, amendment where applicable, and tainability activities in the 2020 fiscal year (January 1 to December confirmation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the 2020 fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "January 1 to December",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "A manufacturer’s CO2 fleet value is the volume- 31, 2020), the sustainability report also contains selected informaweighted average of the CO2 emissions of all the manufacturer’s tion from the 2021 fiscal year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the 2021 fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "new cars (car fleet value) or new light commercial vehicles (LCV fleet value) that are registered for the first time in the respective The editorial deadline was February 8, 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "LCV",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "February 8, 2021",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Both reports appear in calendar year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "calendar year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "If several manufacturers join together in an emis- German and English.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "German",
        "LANGUAGE"
      ],
      [
        "English",
        "LANGUAGE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Both the nonfinancial report and the Group sion pool (also known as a pool), a CO2 fleet value is calculated for Sustainability Report are expected to be published in the first quarthis emission pool from the average of the CO2 emissions of all the ter of 2021.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "TUOBA LEGAL INFORMATION NOTICE PURSUANT TO DIRECTIVE 1999 / 94 / EC",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1999",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "EC",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This sustainability report contains statements relating to the fu-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Further information on the official fuel consumption and official ture business development of the Volkswagen Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "These state- specific CO2 emissions of new passenger cars can be found in the ments are based on assumptions relating to the development of the “Guide on the Fuel Economy, CO2 Emissions and Power Consumpeconomic, political and legal environment in individual countries, tion of All New Passenger Car Models Offered for Sale on the Gereconomic regions and markets, and in particular for the automo- man Market”, which can be obtained free of charge from all sales tive industry, which we have made on the basis of the information outlets of and directly from DAT Deutsche Automobil Treuhand available to us and which we consider to be realistic at the time of GmbH, Hellmuth-Hirth-Strasse 1, 73760 Ostfildern, Germany.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Gereconomic",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Deutsche Automobil Treuhand",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GmbH",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Hellmuth-Hirth-Strasse 1, 73760 Ostfildern",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The estimates given involve a degree of risk, and the actual developments may differ from those forecast.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Any changes www.dat.de in significant parameters relating to our key sales markets, any significant shifts in exchange rates or raw materials relevant to the Volkswagen Group or any difference between the actual impact of the COVID-19 pandemic and the scenario assumed in this report will have a corresponding effect on the development of our business.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In addition, there may be departures from our expected business development if the assessments of the factors influencing sustainable value enhancement, and of risks and opportunities, presented in this sustainability report develop in a way other than we expect at the time of publication, or if additional risks and opportunities or other factors that affect the development of our business emerge.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This version of the annual report is a translation of the German original.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The German takes precedence.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "TUOBA STR ATEGY AND M ANAGEMENT\n\nGroup Governance, Goals and TOGETHER 2025+ Strategy\n\nSustainability and Materiality\n\nSustainability Management\n\nStakeholder Management\n\nCorporate Citizenship\n\nDigitalization\n\nIntegrity and Compliance\n\nRisk Management\n\nEnvironmental Management\n\nGROUP GOVERNANCE, GOALS AND TOGETHER 2025+ STRATEGY GRI 102-1, 102-2, 102-3, 102-4, 102-5, 102-6, 102-7, 102-8, 102-9 OUTLINE OF THE LEGAL STRUCTURE OF THE GROUP More detailed disclosures can be found in the list of shareholdings in accordance with sections 285 and 313 of the Handelsgesetzbuch Volkswagen AG is the parent company of the Volkswagen Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Environmental Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102-9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "285",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "313",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Handelsgesetzbuch Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "(HGB – German Commercial Code) or accessed on our website: The parent company’s head office is Wolfsburg.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Wolfsburg",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "It develops vehicles and components for the Group’s brands, but also produces and sells www.volkswagenag.com/en/InvestorRelations.html vehicles – in particular passenger cars and light commercial vehicles – under the Volkswagen Passenger Cars and Volkswagen Com-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Volkswagen AG is a vertically integrated energy supply company as mercial Vehicles brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In its capacity as parent company, defined by section 3 no. 38 of the Energiewirtschaftsgesetz (EnWG – Volkswagen AG holds direct or indirect interests in AUDI AG, German Energy Industry Act) and is therefore subject to the proviSEAT S.A., ŠKODA AUTO a.s., Dr. Ing.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "section 3 no. 38",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "Energiewirtschaftsgesetz",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "EnWG",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "AUDI AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "German Energy Industry Act",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the proviSEAT S.A.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ŠKODA AUTO a.s.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ing",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "h.c. F. Porsche AG, TRATON SE, sions of the EnWG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "F. Porsche AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EnWG",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In the electricity sector, Volkswagen AG generates, Volkswagen Financial Services AG, Volkswagen Bank GmbH and a sells and distributes electricity together with Group subsidiaries.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Financial Services AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Bank GmbH",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "large number of other companies in Germany and abroad.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Volkswagen AG and the Volkswagen Group are managed by the Volkswagen AG Board of Management in accordance with the Volkswagen AG Articles of Association and the rules of procedure for Volkswagen AG’s Board of Management issued by the Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen AG Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen AG Articles of Association",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "VOLKSWAGEN AG SHAREHOLDER STRUCTURE EMPLOYEES BY MARKET as of December 31, 2020, in % of subscribed capital as of December 31, 2020, in % German institutional Porsche Automobil Europe investors3.4 Holding SE 31.4 South America 4 (excluding Germany)/ other markets31 State of Lower Saxony 11.8 North America 4 Asia-Pacific 16 Qatar Holding LLC 14.6 Foreign institutional investors26.0",
    "entities": [
      [
        "VOLKSWAGEN AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "December 31, 2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "December 31, 2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Porsche Automobil Europe",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "31.4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "South America 4",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "markets31 State",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "11.8",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "North America 4",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "16",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Qatar Holding",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "14.6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Germany44 Private shareholders/ others12.9 ORGANIZATIONAL STRUCTURE OF THE GROUP LEGAL FACTORS INFLUENCING BUSINESS",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Volkswagen Group is one of the leading multibrand groups in With its brands, the Volkswagen Group is present in all relevant the automotive industry.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Group’s business activities comprise markets around the world.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The key sales markets currently include the Automotive and Financial Services divisions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Automotive and Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "All brands within Western Europe, China, the USA, Brazil, Russia, Poland, Turkey and the Automotive Division – with the exception of the Volkswagen Mexico.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Western Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "USA",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Brazil",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Poland",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Turkey",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Mexico",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Passenger Cars and Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles brands – are independent legal entities.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Like other international companies, the business of the Volkswagen companies is affected by numerous laws in Germany and abroad.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Automotive Division comprises the Passenger Cars, Commer-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In particular, there are legal requirements relating to development, cial Vehicles and Power Engineering business areas.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Vehicles and Power Engineering",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Passenger products, production and distribution as well as supervisory, data Cars Business Area essentially consolidates the Volkswagen Group’s protection, financial, company, commercial, capital-market, antipassenger car brands and the Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles trust and tax regulations and regulations relating to labor, bankbrand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Cars Business Area",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Activities focus on the development of vehicles and engines, ing, state-aid, energy, environmental and insurance law.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "the production and sale of passenger cars and light commercial vehicles, and the genuine parts business.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The product portfolio ex-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In addition to the Finance & IT, Human Resources and Integrity & tends from small cars through to luxury vehicles in the premium Legal Affairs divisions, the Volkswagen Group works together segment, and also includes motorcycles, and will be supplemented across six Group Board of Management business areas and the Chiby mobility services as needed.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Finance & IT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Human Resources and Integrity &",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Legal Affairs",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Chiby",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Our management model means better use can be made For further information, see the “Structure and Business Activities” of existing economies of scale, synergy effects can be boosted more chapter in the Annual Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the “Structure and Business Activities",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "the Annual Report",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "systematically and decision-making can be accelerated.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In addition, this prepares the Volkswagen Group for a management structure 2020 Annual Report > Group Management Report > Structure that is simpler, leaner and more effective, and strengthens the and Business Activities brands, giving them more autonomy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Annual Report > Group Management Report > Structure",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Business Activities",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In line with the principle of subsidiarity, decisions will be taken at the lowest competent level, close to business operations.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "For more information on the operating units and responsibilities, regularly reviews these for relevance in light of current developsee the “Structure and Business Activities” chapter in the Annual ments and updates them as necessary.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the “Structure and Business Activities",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "Annual",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Board of Management Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Board of Management Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "and the Supervisory Board of Volkswagen AG base their work on the Code’s principles, recommendations and suggestions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board of",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Code",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The devi2020 Annual Report > Group Management Report > Structure ations from the recommendations can be found in our declaration and Business Activities of compliance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Business Activities",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We consider good corporate governance to be a key prerequisite for achieving a lasting increase in the Company’s valTHE CORPORATE GOVERNANCE CODE AS A BLUEPRINT FOR ue.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "It helps strengthen the trust of our shareholders, customers, SUCCESSFUL CORPORATE GOVERNANCE employees, business partners and investors in our work and enables us to meet the steadily increasing demand for information Corporate governance provides the regulatory framework for cor- from national and international stakeholders.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "You can find our porate management and supervision.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This includes a company’s published Declaration of Conformity with the German Corporate organization and values, and the principles and guidelines for its Governance Code here: business policy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Declaration of Conformity",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Governance Code",
        "LAW"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The German Corporate Governance Code (the Code) contains principles, recommendations and suggestions for w ww.volkswagenag.com/en/InvestorRelations/ corporate-governance/declaration-of-conformity.html corporate management and supervision.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The German",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "w ww.volkswagenag.com/en/InvestorRelations/",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Its recommendations and suggestions were prepared by a dedicated government commission 2020",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Annual Report > Group Management Report > Structure and Business Activities on the basis of the material provisions and nationally and internationally accepted standards of sound, responsible corporate governance.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In line with best practice, the government commission THE VOLKSWAGEN VALUE CHAIN RESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT The Volkswagen Group is further advancing its transformation to a digital mobility group and will invest around €73 billion in capex and development costs for e-mobility, hybridization and digitalization in the next five years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "VOLKSWAGEN",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "around €73 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "the next five years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Every year, the Volkswagen Group purchases a wide range of raw materials, components and other goods.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Every year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "A sustainable supply chain and environmentally compatible transportation are vital for fully assuming responsibility for human rights, environmental protection and the battle against corruption.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Every working day, the Volkswagen Group manufactures an average of around 36,000 vehicles globally.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "around 36,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Efficient production ranks alongside environmental protection and employee health and safety as one of our core goals.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "MARKETING & SALES Business relationships with fleet customers are often long-term and stable partnerships.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "MARKETING & SALES Business",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The Volkswagen Group’s share of commercial fleet customers is 42.1% in Germany and 26.5% in the rest of Europe.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "42.1%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "26.5%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "AFTER-SALES & FINANCIAL SERVICES",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Our service includes supporting dealerships to ensure they can provide quality advice and maintenance, managing our original parts business, and providing vehicle-related financial services.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In addition to recycling vehicles at the end of their useful life, we pay close attention during the new-vehicle development stage to the recyclability of the required materials, the use of high-quality recycled materials, and the avoidance of pollutants.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "DNA YGETARTS OUR FUTURE-ORIENTED PROGRAM TOGETHER",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "2025+ place within the Group and between individuals in their day-today work.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Its core values are encapsulated in the terms “genuine”, With the future-oriented program TOGETHER – Strategy 2025 an- “straightforward”, “open-minded”, “as equals” and “united”.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "T4I nounced in 2016, we are seeking to make the Volkswagen Group brings together all activities relating to integrity, culture, complimore focused, efficient, innovative, customer-oriented and sus- ance, risk management and human resources, creating a common tainable, and systematically geared toward generating profitable path toward a new corporate culture.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2016",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "FIVE MODULES OF THE TOGETHER 2025+ STRATEGY We at the Volkswagen Group have set ourselves the goal of continuing to excite our customers in future and meeting their diverse Our TOGETHER 2025+ Group strategy comprises consistent strateneeds with an appealing product portfolio of impressive vehicles gic decisions and specific modules aimed at safeguarding the longand forward-looking, tailor-made mobility solutions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "FIVE",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "gic",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Every day, term future of the Group and generating profitable growth.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Every day",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "we actively assume and exercise responsibility in relation to the environment, safety and society, and we aim to be a role model in These modules are namely Best Governance, Best Performance, these areas.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Best Governance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Integrity, reliability, quality and passion thus form Best Brand Equity, Software-enabled Car Company and Excellent the basis for our work.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Best Brand Equity",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Car Company and Excellent",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Using this approach, we aim for technolog- Leadership.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We continuously review the status and progress of ical leadership in the industry and competitive profitability while these initiatives in order to analyze the target achievement, imporalso striving to be an excellent employer.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "tance and suitability of the measures defined.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This enables us to tailor these modules to the transformation underway within our The TOGETHER 2025+ Group strategy, which we further developed company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The TOGETHER 2025+ Group",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "in 2019, steps up the pace at which we will achieve our strategic objectives and sharpens our focus.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "To this end, the strategic vi-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In the Best Governance module, we are working to create a focused, sion of the Volkswagen Group was also revised.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "With “Shaping streamlined corporate structure to manage the brands, continually mobility – for generations to come”, we aim to more actively leverage synergies and accelerate decision-making processes.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We shape the future of mobility while safeguarding it sustainably – want the Group to be perceived as efficiently managed, trustworfor present and future generations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "thy, sustainable and transparent.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "To this end, we are intensifying the dialog with our key stakeholders and systematically reviewing With electric drives, digital connectivity and autonomous driv- whether we are still the best owner for our various brands and ing, we want to make the automobile cleaner, quieter, more intel- companies.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In addition, we want to make our CO2 targets mea surligent and safer.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "At the same time, our core product will become able and make our progress towards becoming carbon neutral in more emotive and offer a completely new driving experience.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In 2050 transparent.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2050",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Within international ESG rankings (ESG = envithis way, the car can continue to be a cornerstone of sustainable, ronment, social, governance), we strive for a leading position in our individual and affordable mobility in the future.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In addition, we industry in the future.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "are committed to the Paris Agreement on climate protection and are one of the first companies in our industry to commit our-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Paris Agreement",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The aim of the Best Performance module is to achieve a sustainable selves to becoming a company with a neutral carbon footprint by value enhancement in our enterprise by increasing efficiency, pro2050.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This includes our vehicles, our plants and all processes.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "ductivity and profitability.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "As a global company, our size enables us to make increased use of economies of scale.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We remain firmly The automotive industry is being shaped particularly by the committed to our ambitious targets, work consistently on achievtransformation to e-mobility and digitalization.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We have posi- ing them and strive to exceed them.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This will lay the foundations tioned ourselves to successfully tackle this radical change: the for extensive investment in our Company, in our employees and in strategies of our brands and regions as well as those of our func- mobility for present and future generations.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "tional areas are consistently aligned with the TOGETHER 2025+ Group strategy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In the Best Brand Equity module, the focus is on realigning and further refining the brand portfolio, making a significant increase in Under the umbrella of the TOGETHER 2025+ Group strategy, we the value of our Group brands possible.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Best Brand Equity",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We are defining the prohave defined five central modules that put the focus on corporate files, brand missions and core competitors of the Volkswagen Group governance, improved performance, increased brand equity, soft- brands in a more nuanced and distinctive way.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This will enable the ware and excellence in employee management.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Group to better serve the market as a whole.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Based on these optimizations, we will decide on the future design, product portfolio and Our Code of Collaboration, along with our integrity and compli- services of each Group brand – using the needs of our customers as ance program Together4Integrity (T4I), is a central pillar of the a starting point.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Our Code of Collaboration",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ance program Together4Integrity",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This Code describes how collaboration is to take\n\nTNEMEGANAM",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In the Software-enabled Car Company module, we are working to more open, more partnership-based and more value-based leadermake software development one of the Volkswagen Group’s core ship culture.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Car Company",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "leadermake software development one",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We are developing digital and dialog-oriented comcompetencies.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "To achieve this, we are pooling existing expertise, munication formats to achieve a quicker flow of information and substantially strengthening our resources and establishing a dedi- even stronger connectivity across all brands and regions.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We are cated organizational unit.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Going forward, all new vehicle models completely restructuring management development and training across the Group will be based on our own cross-brand software and taking an even more systematic approach to succession planplatform.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This approach will provide the opportunity to leverage ning so that, at our Group, the right talent is always in the right posynergies between the individual brands and vehicle projects.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The sition at the right time.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We are also defining clear expectations for aim is that the Volkswagen Group and its brands will stand not the Group’s managers.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "These involve greater customer focus, more only for the best vehicles but in equal measure for exciting digital corporate responsibility, greater effectiveness and focus on results products and services.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "as well as a culture of constructive dissent and a positive approach in dealing with mistakes.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Volkswagen also wants to increase diverThe Excellent Leadership module is based on three main areas: sity at all levels of the company and is pursuing clear, measurable communication, human resources development and collaboration.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "diverThe Excellent Leadership",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "targets for raising the proportion of female and international To remain competitive and fit for the future, we are shifting to a managers.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Our new vision Excited customers Shaping mobility – e E m xc p e l l o le y n e t r Su g s r t o a w in t a h ble p C r o o m fi p ta e b ti",
    "entities": [
      [
        "w",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "i t v y e for generations to come.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Role model for environment, safety and integrity Our updated action plan Software-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "ExcelBest Best Best enabled lent Gover- Perfor-",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Brand Car Leadernance mance Equity Company ship Brands and Functional regional strategies strategies Values and Integrity",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Car Leadernance",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Our belief GROUP STRATEGY GOALS AND KEY PERFORMANCE INDICATORS our Group strategy depend on the respective business model, as the business model for our passenger car-producing brands is different The five strategic modules describe how we want to achieve our vi- from the business model for trucks and buses and also differs from sion of sustainable mobility for present and future generations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We the business model for our Power Engineering business area and are managing our project using four target dimensions, which are our services business.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Power Engineering",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "also reflected in the Volkswagen strategy rhombus.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The four target dimensions are as follows:",
    "entities": [
      [
        "four",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "excited customers, excellent employer, The strategic KPIs of the competitive profitability target dimension role model for environment, safety and integrity, and competitive have been defined and standardized.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "As the Group strategy is curprofitability.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We want to grow sustainably by consistently pursuing rently being revised and specified in detail, the content of some these objectives.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "strategic KPIs in the other target dimensions is still being determined.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The relevance of the KPIs is reviewed at Group level and The target dimensions apply throughout the whole Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The stra- their focus is continuously monitored and adjusted as necessary.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "tegic KPIs that we use to measure how well we have implemented\n\nTNEMEGANAM",
    "entities": [
      [
        "tegic",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We report on the defined nonfinancial strategic KPIs in the “Sus- Our primary objectives in this process include complying with tainable Value Enhancement” section of the Annual Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Value Enhancement",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Annual Report",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "laws and regulations, establishing secure processes and dealing openly with mistakes so that they can be avoided or rectified in the 2020 Annual Report > Group Management Report > Sus tain- future.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "In terms of integrity, Volkswagen aims to become a role able Value Enhancement model for a modern, transparent and successful enterprise.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Value Enhancement",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "EXCITED CUSTOMERS The strategic KPIs of this target dimension consist of the decarbonization index and fleet CO2 emissions figures, compliance, a culture This target dimension focuses on the diverse needs of our custom- of dealing openly with mistakes, and integrity.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "ers and on tailor-made mobility solutions.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We aspire to exceed our customers’ expectations, thus generating maximum customer Circular Economy benefit.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This requires not only the best products, the most efficient solutions and the best service, but also flawless quality and an out- TARGET DIMENSION:",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "COMPETITIVE PROFITABILITY standing image.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We want to excite our existing customers, win over new ones and retain their loyalty in the long term – because Investors judge us by whether we are able to meet our obligations only loyal and faithful customers will recommend us to others.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "as regards interest payments and debt repayments.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "As equity holders, they expect appropriate dividends and a long-term value enThe strategic KPIs consist of the conquest rate and KPIs pertaining hancement of their shares.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "to loyalty, customer satisfaction and quality.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "These KPIs are explained in more detail in the “Sustainable Value We make investments with a view to achieving profitable growth Enhancement” section of the Annual Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the “Sustainable Value We",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Annual Report",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "and strengthening our competitiveness, thus keeping the Volkswagen Group on a firm footing in the future and ensuring it 2020 Annual Report > Group Management Report > Sus tain- remains an attractive investment option.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Annual Report > Group Management Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "able Value Enhancement The goals we have set ourselves are operational excellence in all TARGET DIMENSION:",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Value Enhancement",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "EXCELLENT EMPLOYER business processes and becoming the benchmark for the entire industry.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "To achieve sustainable success, we need skilled and dedicated employees.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We aim to increase their satisfaction and motivation by The strategic KPIs are operationalized for internal management means of equal opportunities, an attractive and modern working purposes: target and actual data are derived from Volkswagen environment, and a forward-looking organization of work.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "An ex- Group figures.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "emplary management and corporate culture forms the basis for this, allowing us to retain our core workforce and attract new STRATEGIC KPIS: talent.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "COMPETITIVE PROFITABILITY 2015 2025",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2015 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "The strategic KPIs of this target dimension cover internal employer Operating return on sales1 6.0% 7 to 8% attractiveness determined by means of the opinion survey, external employer attractiveness, an external employer ranking as well Research and development ratio (R&D 7.4% ~ 6% ratio) in the Automotive Division as the diversity index.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6.0%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "7 to 8%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "7.4%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "6%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "the Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Ratio of capex in the 6.9% ~ 6% Automotive Division Workforce Transformation Net cash flow in the €8,887 million > €10 billion Automotive Division TARGET DIMENSION:",
    "entities": [
      [
        "6.9%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "6%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "Automotive Division Workforce Transformation Net",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "€8,887 million",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "€10 billion",
        "MONEY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "ROLE MODEL FOR ENVIRONMENT, SAFETY AND INTEGRITY Payout ratio Negative ≥ 30% Net liquidity in the €24,522 million, ~ 10% of Every day, we at the Volkswagen Group assume and exercise re-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "30%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "€24,522 million",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "10%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Automotive Division 11.5% Group sales revenue sponsibility in issues relating to the environment, safety and society.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "11.5%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "This aspiration should be reflected in our thoughts and actions Return on investment (ROI) –0.2% > 14% in the Automotive Division and in all our decisions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "0.2%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "14%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "the Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "We pay particular attention to the use of resources and the emissions of our product portfolio, sites and ¹ 2015 before special items.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "¹ 2015",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Our goal is to continuously reduce our carbon footprint and lower our pollutant emissions.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Through innovations and outstanding quality, we aim for high product safety.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "DNA YGETARTS SUSTAINABILITY AND MATERIALITY GRI 102-46, 102-49 NEW MATERIALITY ANALYSIS RESULTS IN FOUR FOCUS AREAS At the start of the materiality process, an analysis of the Group’s existing sustainability activities was made and a cross-sectoral list of We continued revising our materiality analysis in 2020, having be- relevant sustainability topics compiled.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "102-46",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "102",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "FOUR",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2020",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2020,
    "sentence": "Subsequently, the order of gun the process the previous year, and established a new strategic priority of the topics for developing the narrative was worked out.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the previous year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
