[
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "I T Y R E P O R T\n\nContents Focus Topics\n\nDecarbonization 48 Decarbonization 69 EU Taxonomy 6 Foreword 2 Circular Economy 9 About This Report 83 Circular Economy 12 Sustainability in the Group’s DNA 3 P eople in the Transformation 13 Corporate Governance 90 People in the Transformation 17 NEW AUTO Group Strategy 22 ESG Performance Management 4 and Materiality Analysis Diversity 25 Sustainability Management 104 Diversity 27 Sustainability Impact of New Mobility Options 5 Integrity and Compliance 30 Stakeholder Management 109 Integrity and Compliance 33 Environmental Compliance Management\n\n42 Risk Management S upply Chain and Human Rights 45 Corporate Citizenship 117 Supply Chain and Human Rights 131 Appendix Navigation 132 I ndependent Auditor’s Limited Assurance Report References to chapters in the Sustainability Report 135 Contact Information References to websites\n\nVolkswagen Group Sustainability Communication SUSTAINABILITY REPORT ANNUAL REPORT 2023 2023 Information Accompanying Information on the Group the Reporting Website ESG KPIs Policies Indicators along our focus topics are clearly Voluntary commitments and principles presented in Excel.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Focus Topics",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "69",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "12",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Transformation 13",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "90",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "17",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "4",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Materiality Analysis Diversity",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "25",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Management 104 Diversity",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "27",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Management 109 Integrity and",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "42",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Chain and Human Rights 45",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "117",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Auditor",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group Sustainability Communication SUSTAINABILITY",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Information Accompanying Information on the Group the Reporting Website ESG KPIs Policies Indicators",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "Voluntary",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Excel",
        "PRODUCT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "that apply across the Group GRI index ESG controversies",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "GRI content index (with reference) Factual information on current and ongoing controversies SASB index Automobiles index Reports on Special Issues International Initiatives Responsible Raw Materials Report UN Sustainable Development Goals Progress on transparency and risk mitigation Activities and projects that help achieve the in the raw material supply chain (annual) sustainability goals (annual) Association Climate Review Report UN Global Compact Overview of climate policy positions Implementation of the Ten Principles of the UN Global Compact (annual) Green Finance Report Implementation of sustainable financing CDP Score Report – Climate Change strategies (annual) Assessment of climate-related risks, goals and measures Further ESG topics Information on further topics of importance for CDP Score Report – Water Security sustainability and ESG Assessment of water resources Sustainability and ESG Are Part of the Group Strategy Core Progressive Sport Luxury Trucks Architecture Software Battery, Charging & Energy Volkswagen Group",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SASB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Automobiles index Reports on Special Issues International Initiatives Responsible Raw Materials Report",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Association Climate Review",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Implementation of the Ten Principles of the UN Global Compact",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Green Finance Report Implementation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "CDP Score Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "CDP Score Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG Assessment",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "& Energy Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Mobility 06 | ESG, Decarbonization and Integrity People in the Decarbonization Circular Economy Transformation Sustainability in the Group’s DNA Integrity and Supply Chain and Diversity Compliance Human Rights EESSGG PPeerrffoorrmmaannccee The aim is to improve performance in the capital market’s ESG ratings and rankings so as to increase the ability to invest and optimize the cost of capital.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Decarbonization",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "As we transition from automotive manufacturer to mobility group, we are resetting our priorities with the NEW AUTO Group strategy and positioning ourselves for the future.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the NEW AUTO Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "We are keeping our aim of being a world-leading provider of sustainable mobility firmly in our sights and making the Group more focused, efficient, innovative, customer-oriented and sustainable, as well as systematically gearing it toward profitable growth.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The NEW AUTO Group strategy defines the six key focus issues shown above for the area of sustainability and ESG in Group initiative 6.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The NEW AUTO Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ESG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "6",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This Sustainability Report including nonfinancial report is structured in accordance with these.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In addition, the Sustainability in the Group’s DNA chapter provides a definition of sustainability for the Group and an insight into topics such as risk management, environmental management, stakeholder management and corporate citizenship.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Highlights 20231 Decarbonization Circular Economy Access to More than 600,000 charging points 850,000 metric tons of CO₂ in Europe have been saved in net terms since 2017 through the Aluminum Closed Loop.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "20231",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "More than 600,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "850,000 metric tons",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "2017",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Aluminum Closed Loop",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "By 2030, the whole dealer network’s carbon footprint is to be decreased by In 2023, we processed at least 30%.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2030",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "at least 30%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "77,090 tools to make them suitable to return to use.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "77,090",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "People in the Transformation Diversity 14.3 million 94% training hours in the of managers have taken part in the Volkswagen Group Diversity Wins@Volkswagen program.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "94%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group Diversity",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "72 locations Proportion of women are certified in accordance in management worldwide and with ISO 45001.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "72",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Proportion",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "ISO 45001",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "internationality of top management increased.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Integrity and Supply Chain and Compliance Human Rights In 2023, more than 7,791 4,100 business partners direct suppliers worldwide were audited.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supply Chain and",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "more than 7,791 4,100",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "were trained on sustainability.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "1,551 Suppliers with a positive S rating account for inquiries were processed at the 79% of revenue compliance information point.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1,551",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the 79%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "in the total procurement volume.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Further information on the figures on this page, such as definitions and scope, can be found in the relevant chapters.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity and Compliance | Supply Chain and Human Rights Foreword GRI 2-22 Oliver Blume, Daniela Cavallo, Chairman of the Board of Management of Volkswagen AG Chairwoman of the General and Group Works Council of Volkswagen AG",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain and Human Rights Foreword",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Oliver Blume",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Daniela Cavallo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management of Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the General and Group Works Council of Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Dear stakeholders and colleagues, Sustainability Strategy: Clear Goals, Clear Responsibility Sustainability is one of our top priorities.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability Strategy: Clear Goals, Clear Responsibility Sustainability",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "As a strategic field, Values create value.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "We in the Volkswagen Group remain true we set ourselves clear goals and plans for sustainability – to this principle.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "It’s an important compass for our actions.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "which are binding with clear responsibilities.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The focus is on And this stance lets us sustainably create long-term added implementing our strategic measures.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "For our staff, for our customers, for our investors – and for society as a whole.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "As one of the world’s largest industrial We also leverage the synergies in the Volkswagen Group here: groups, we carry a special responsibility.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "All goals are systematically broken down into goals for the ference.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "We want to and will seize this opportunity.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "brands and Group companies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Management has personal responsibility for complying with these.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "We think of sustainability holistically – in terms of nature, people, society and value-adding entrepreneurship.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "From the Decarbonization: What Drives Us supply chain through our production to the delivery and use of The Volkswagen Group is clearly committed to electric our products.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decarbonization",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Our goal is to help to shape nature and society mobility.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Inspirational product innovations of recent weeks positively.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "recent weeks",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "And it will take a great deal of and months – such as the Audi Q6 e-tron, the VW ID.7, the work.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "months",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Audi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "VW",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "At the same time, achieving this goal is an obligation – Porsche Macan electric or the long wheelbase version of the internally to our colleagues and externally to our customers, ID.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Porsche Macan",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Buzz – show that e-mobility is synonymous with emotion society and, in particular, future generations.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Our delivery figures confirm this trend too.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In 2023, the Volkswagen Group delivered 771,100 all-electric vehicles.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "771,100",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This is equivalent to a year-on-year rise of 34.7%.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "34.7%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The share of deliveries accounted for by all-electric vehicles increased to 8.3%.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "8.3%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Table of Contents The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity and Compliance | Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-22 A key lever for reducing emissions is production: Our aim is has long been more than a question of salary.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Table of Contents The Group’s",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-22",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Talented indito reduce production-related CO₂ emissions from passenger viduals also assess potential employers on factors such as cars and light commercial vehicles by 50.4% by 2030 compared flexibility, work-life balance, diversity, social benefits and with the base year 2018.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "indito",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "50.4%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the base year 2018",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "personal responsibility.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The renowned Science Based Targets initiative (SBTi) con-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Science Based Targets",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "What do these changes mean for the Volkswagen Group?",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The firmed that our Group meets the requirements for contributing responsibility for “people in the transformation” is at the core to limiting global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius with this of our current and future activities in human resources.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "1.5 degrees Celsius",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The objective for the production phase (Scope 1 and 2).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "SBTi has “Transform to Tech” Group People Strategy, which the Group confirmed that the aim of reducing CO₂ emissions by 30% in Board of Management adopted in 2021, plays a key role.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Transform to Tech",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "30%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2021",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "the use phase (Scope 3) is in line with limiting global warming to two degrees Celsius.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "two degrees Celsius",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This confirmation spurs us on.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "When it comes to training, the Volkswagen Group’s focus is on training colleagues on future technologies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This includes The Volkswagen Group is aiming to reduce the average CO₂ closely supporting them in the transformation process.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "For emissions per vehicle (passenger cars and light commercial example, Volkswagen specifically added courses on e-movehicles) over the entire life cycle by 30% by 2030 compared bility to its professional training program with the aid of the with 2018.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "30%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "2030",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Volkswagen Group Academy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group Academy",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Newly designed and innovative programs from our Health department look after our emRamping up electric mobility and expanding renewable ener- ployees’ psychological safety during the transformation.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "And gies go hand in hand here.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "That’s why we are supporting the where major changes are planned in a factory or office, we construction of wind farms and solar parks on an industrial have transformation offices on hand.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "They are intended to give scale.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "New wind farms and solar parks are to be constructed people an outlook for the future and provide a clear direcin several regions of Europe by 2025.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In Germany, for example, tion for the change process in the transformation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Job secuVolkswagen supported the construction of a solar plant with rity until 2029 at Volkswagen AG gives employees the supa total capacity of 170 million kWh a year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2029",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "170 million kWh",
        "QUANTITY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The plant in Tramm- port they need.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Göthen in Mecklenburg in northeastern Germany is the largest of its kind in Germany with around 420,000 solar panels.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Göthen",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Mecklenburg",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "northeastern Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "420,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Holistic Responsibility: The Supply Chain at a Glance",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Holistic Responsibility",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In addition to responsibility for its own employees, the The Team: Engine of the Transformation Volkswagen Group also has a global responsibility.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the The Team: Engine of",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Transformation Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The GerEmployees are any company’s most valuable asset.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GerEmployees",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The man Supply Chain Due Diligence Act, which has been in Volkswagen Group is only as strong as the people who work force in Germany for more than a year, has a special role here.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supply Chain",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Diligence Act",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "more than a year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Particularly in times of skills shortages, employer at- Focuses include protecting human rights and minimizing tractiveness is vital for companies’ future viability.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "environmental risks – both topics the Volkswagen Group identifies with through and through.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Sustainability ProOur sector’s shift toward e-mobility but also toward new curement Network shares information between our brands business models and digitalization brings with it considerable and regions, which serves as a component in managing suschanges for many workers.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ProOur",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "Network",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Jobs are being realigned, and tainability in our supply chains.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "More than 110 experts from new fields of work are emerging, while others permanently five continents work together in the network.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "More than 110",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The network disappear.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "We are managing and monitoring these changes allows the identification of current developments and chalin a sustainable and socially responsible manner in the inter- lenges in the regions of the world and enables joint solutions ests of our colleagues.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This is also very much intended to to be developed.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This is crucial because Volkswagen has ensure corporate success.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Because employer attractiveness over 63,000 direct suppliers in more than 95 countries.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "63,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "more than 95",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Table of Contents The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity and Compliance | Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-22 Technology:",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-22",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The True Key to Sustainability The Volkswagen Group stands for tradition and for strong The Volkswagen Group has been a technology company for brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The True Key to Sustainability The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "For advancing developments and overcoming chalmany decades.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "decades",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This is expertise we will also use in sustain- lenges.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Today, we are undergoing automotive history’s ability because we believe that technology is the key to prog- greatest transformation: We want to enable sustainable moress in the sustainability strategy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Today",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "As the Volkswagen Group, bility for generations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Sustainability is deeply rooted in the we are one of the few companies in the world that is taking Volkswagen Group’s identity.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "It is an integral part of our the strategic expansion of technology leadership in electric Group strategy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "For 2024, we are providing important and mobility fully into its own hands – from cell and battery re- targeted new impetus.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Volkswagen Group is aware of its search to the development and production of breathtaking role, importance and responsibility.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Together, we will do evelectric vehicles.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "erything we can to make our important contribution – with team spirit, fairness and passion.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Since PowerCo was launched in July 2022, the battery company has already defined three sites (Salzgitter, Valencia and St. Thomas), introduced the concept of the unified cell, founded a joint venture with Umicore to produce cathodes Daniela Cavallo and Oliver Blume and introduced activities to secure the supply of raw materials.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "PowerCo",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "July 2022",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Salzgitter",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Valencia",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "St. Thomas",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Umicore",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Daniela Cavallo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Oliver Blume",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "We are also taking on the task of expanding the charging infrastructure.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "By 2025, the Volkswagen Group wants to enable more than 40,000 fast-charging points in China, North America and Europe to be put into operation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "more than 40,000",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "North America",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Europe",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Table of Contents The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity and Compliance | Supply Chain and Human Rights About This Report German Commercial Code (Handelsgesetzbuch – HGB) secReport Structure tions 289b para.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Table of Contents The Group’s",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain and Human Rights About This Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "secReport Structure",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "289b",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The nonfinancial report is drawn up in accordance with HGB section 315c, in conThis 2023 Group Sustainability Report is based on internajunction with sections 289c through 289e.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "315c",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2023 Group Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "289c",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "289e",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In line with the tionally established frameworks and requirements, such as the German CSR Directive Implementation Act (CSR-RUG), this standards of the Global Reporting Initiative (GRI, see also nonfinancial report concentrates on the focus issues necessary following section), the German CSR Directive Implementation for an understanding of the Volkswagen Group’s business Act (CSR-Richtlinie-Umsetzungsgesetz – CSR-RUG), ESG development, overall performance and position as well as the sustainability ratings (Environmental, Social, Governance) Volkswagen Group’s impact on nonfinancial aspects.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "the Global Reporting Initiative",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "GRI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG development",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Environmental, Social, Governance)",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "We are and stakeholder expectations.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The report is supplemented again reporting on our climate protection activities in line by a detailed description of the sustainability activities of our with the requirements of the Task Force on Climate-related brands and regions and of the Volkswagen Group’s corpoFinancial Disclosures (TCFD).",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Task Force",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "corpoFinancial Disclosures",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "rate citizenship projects.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Further information, particularly information relevant to ESG Furthermore, the GRI Standards are used as the framework investors – for example, ESG KPIs – is available on the Group’s for drawing up the nonfinancial report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG Furthermore",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG KPIs",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In this Sustainability corporate website and is not part of this report.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Report, Volkswagen systematically uses the GRI Standards (with reference) as the underlying structure for reporting on www.volkswagen-group.com > management approaches and the specific standard disclosures.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "ESG-Performance & Reporting The GRI Content Index has been separated from the 2023 Sustainability Report and can be found as a separate document For reporting year 2023, Volkswagen AG is issuing a non- in the Group portal: financial statement at Company level and a nonfinancial Group declaration, which are being published together as a com- www.volkswagen-group.com >",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESG-Performance & Reporting",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the 2023 Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Reporting bined separate nonfinancial report within the meaning of Volkswagen Group Sustainability Communication 2023 SUSTAINABILITY WEBSITE ADDITIONAL REPORT COMMUNICIATION including www.volkswagen-group.com www.volkswagen-group.com > ESG-Performance & Reporting > Press Releases www.volkswagen-group.com 2023 Nonfinancial > Sustainability Statement\n\nTable of Contents",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group Sustainability Communication 2023 SUSTAINABILITY",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ESG-Performance & Reporting",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Statement\n\nTable of Contents",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity and Compliance | Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-2, 2-4, 2-5 As a member of the United Nations Global Compact, we also The KPIs presented in this report build on the indicators continuously report how we are putting the Ten Principles presented in previous years.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-2",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2-4",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2-5",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the United Nations Global Compact",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "previous years",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Any material changes to data into corporate practice.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Our current progress report can be collection or to measurement methods for our sustainability found on the UN Global Compact’s website: performance are explicitly disclosed by the respective KPIs.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the UN Global Compact’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "All figures shown in the report are rounded, so minor United Nations Global Compact discrepancies may arise from addition of these amounts.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "United Nations Global Compact",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The strategy chapter and the six following chapters on focus Report Auditing issues in the report each consist of a text section plus a consolidated KPI table at the end of each chapter.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "six",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Report Auditing",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "KPI",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "EY GmbH & Co. KG Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft conducted a voluntary, limited assurance engagement in accorReferences to disclosures outside the nonfinancial report dance with ISAE 3000 (Revised) on the combined separate are supplementary information and do not form part of this nonfinancial report prepared in accordance with HGB sections report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EY GmbH & Co.",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "KG Wirtschaftsprüfungsgesellschaft",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "ISAE 3000 (",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "HGB",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The following passages are also not part of the non- 289b para.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "289b",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "3 to verify that its disclosures financial report: comply with the relevant statutory requirements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "3",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Further information on the engagement can be found in the indepen• Volkswagen Group Sustainability Communication (pp.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group Sustainability Communication",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "3–4) dent practitioner’s report on a limited assurance engagement • Foreword (pp.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "•",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "6–8) on the nonfinancial reporting.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The German Corporate Governance Code – A Blueprint for Successful Corporate Governance (p. 15) Disclosures in Connection with the Annual • Further Information; The Volkswagen Value Chain (p. 16) Financial Statements • Making the Social and Environmental Impact of Our Actions Measurable (p. 24) No material special items in connection with the diesel issue were recognized in fiscal year 2023.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The German",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "15",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Connection",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "the Annual • Further Information",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Value Chain",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "16",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "the Social and Environmental Impact of Our Actions Measurable",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "24",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The information in this report relates to the Volkswagen Group as a whole.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Where information relates to individual Group di-",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "To hedge the currently known legal risks related to the diesel visions only, this is clearly indicated in the text.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Unless indi- issue, the provisions for litigation and legal risks as of Decated otherwise, any information provided for the Group also cember 31, 2023 include an amount of around €0.9 (1.4) billion, applies to Volkswagen AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decated",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "cember 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "around €0.9",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "1.4) billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In addition to Volkswagen AG, based on existing information and current assessments.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "the Group includes all major subsidiaries inside and out- I nsofar as these can be adequately measured at this stage, side Germany that are directly or indirectly controlled by contingent liabilities relating to the diesel issue were disVolkswagen AG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "disVolkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "closed in the notes to the consolidated financial statements in an aggregate amount of €4.0 (4.2) billion, whereby €3.8 In the financial data, our joint ventures in China are reported (3.6) billion of this amount results from lawsuits filed by inusing the equity accounting method.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "4.0",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "4.2) billion",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "3.8",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "3.6) billion",
        "MONEY"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "However, they are in- vestors in Germany.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The provisions recognized, the contingent cluded in full (100%) in volume-related data (sales, production liabilities disclosed, and the other latent legal risks in the and workforce) and in production-related environmentally context of the diesel issue are in part subject to substantial relevant data.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "100%",
        "PERCENT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The management approaches described in estimation risks given the complexity of the individual relevant this report (e.g., the environmental compliance management factors, the ongoing coordination with the authorities, and system) apply to all the Volkswagen Group’s controlled the fact that the fact-finding efforts have not yet been concompanies.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "With our non-controlled companies – i.e., com- cluded.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Should these legal or estimation risks materialize, panies that are not controlled by a company of the this could result in further substantial financial charges.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In Volkswagen Group as the majority owner – we work to the particular, adjustment of the provisions recognized in light of extent feasible and permitted by law toward implementation knowledge acquired or events occurring in the future cannot of the adjusted management approaches.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Chinese joint be ruled out.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "ventures are included in the information on the Volkswagen Group in the KPIs and the associated targets on the topics of The remaining provisions relate to a wide range of identifireduction of the environmental impact of production (UEP), able individual risks, price risks and contingent liabilities, the decarbonization index (DCI), the Opinion Survey, the di- which are factored in in the amount of their probable occurversity index, training hours per employee, accident indices rence.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "UEP",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "DCI",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Opinion Survey",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "hours",
        "TIME"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Depending on the jurisdiction concerned, risk provisions and accident figures.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The risks of the Chinese market are for any non-compliance with statutory emissions limits are assessed by Volkswagen China Investment Company Ltd. also included.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Chinese",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen China Investment Company Ltd.",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Their measurement takes into account,\n\nTable of Contents",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Table of Contents",
        "PRODUCT"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity and Compliance | Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-3 among other things, the respective sales volume and the Editorial Notes legally defined fee or the cost of acquiring emission rights from other manufacturers.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-3",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Advantage has been taken of Whenever this report uses the term Sustainability Report, synergies between individual brands of the Volkswagen this expression includes the nonfinancial report each time it Group by establishing emission pools where possible.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Addi- is mentioned, to the extent described on page 10.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "10",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "tional information on this matter and the valuation assumptions and bases can be found in the Annual Report in the Reporting Practices notes to the consolidated financial statements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Annual Report",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Reporting Practices",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The nonfinancial report is published annually.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "annually",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The last nonAdditional Reporting within the Group financial report was published on March 12, 2023.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "March 12",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In addition to information about the Group’s sustainability activities By referencing this combined separate nonfinancial report, in the 2023 fiscal year (January 1 to December 31, 2023), all Group companies that are required by national legislation this 2023 nonfinancial report also contains selected inforto disclose nonfinancial and diversity-related information mation from the 2024 fiscal year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the 2023 fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "January 1 to December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "inforto",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the 2024 fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "pursuant to Directive 2014/95/EU but do not issue their own nonfinancial statement are exempted from the obligation to About This Report submit their own nonfinancial reports.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2014/95",
        "MONEY"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The editorial deadline was February 14, 2024.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "February 14, 2024",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Group Terminology Relating to Climate Protection Sustainability Report is published in the first quarter of 2024 and is also available in the original German.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Group Terminology Relating",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Climate Protection Sustainability Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the first quarter of 2024",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In the event of The use of the term CO₂ emissions in this report includes the any discrepancies, the German authoritative version of the consideration and identification of additional climate-dam- document takes precedence over the English translation.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "English",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "aging greenhouse gases such as methane (CH₄) and laughing gas (N₂O) (CO₂ equivalents).",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "All figures in this report on CO₂ Legal Information emissions correspond to CO₂ equivalents, except for fleet emission figures.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "CO₂ Legal Information",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This sustainability report contains statements relating to the future business development of the Volkswagen Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Net carbon neutrality is achieved when anthropogenic CO₂ These statements are based on assumptions relating to the emissions are balanced worldwide through avoidance,",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "development of the economic, political and legal environduction and offsetting over a specific period of time.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "With ment in individual countries, economic regions and markets, regard to climate protection, in addition to CO₂ emissions, and in particular for the automotive industry, which we have Volkswagen also pays attention to other relevant greenhouse made on the basis of the information available to us and gases.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Avoidance and reduction have priority over offsetting which we consider to be realistic as of the time of going to for the Volkswagen Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "For offsetting measures, the Group press.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The estimates given involve a degree of risk, and the follows internationally established standards.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "actual developments may differ from those forecast.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Any changes in significant parameters relating to our key sales markets, or any significant shifts in exchange rates, energy and other commodities or the supply of parts relevant to the Volkswagen Group will have a corresponding impact on the development of our business.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In addition, there may be departures from our expected business development if the assessments of the factors influencing sustainable value enhancement, and of risks and opportunities, presented in this sustainability report develop in a way other than we expect at the time of publication, or if additional risks and opportunities or other factors that affect the development of our business emerge.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Sustainability in the Group’s DNA 13 Corporate Governance 17 NEW AUTO Group Strategy 22 ESG Performance Management and Materiality Analysis 25 Sustainability Management 27 Sustainability Impact of New Mobility Options 30 Stakeholder Management 33 Environmental Compliance Management 42 Risk Management 45 Corporate Citizenship\n\nTable of Contents The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity and Compliance | Supply Chain and Human Rights Corporate Governance GRI 2-1, 2-6 Outline of the Legal Structure of the Group www.volkswagen-group.com >",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "13",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "17",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "ESG Performance Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Materiality Analysis",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "25",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Sustainability Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "30",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "33",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "42",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "45",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain and Human Rights Corporate",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2-1",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Annual Financial Statements Volkswagen AG is the parent company of the Volkswagen Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Financial Statements Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "It develops vehicles and components for the Group Volkswagen AG is a vertically integrated energy supply brands, but also produces and sells vehicles, in particular pas- company as defined by section 3 no.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Group Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "section 3 no.",
        "LAW"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "38 of the German Energy senger cars and light commercial vehicles for the Volkswagen Industry Act (Energiewirtschaftsgesetz – EnWG)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "38",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "German Energy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Industry Act",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Energiewirtschaftsgesetz",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "and is Passenger Cars and Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Passenger Cars",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "therefore subject to the provisions of the EnWG.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "EnWG",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In the elecIn its capacity as parent company, Volkswagen AG holds direct tricity sector, Volkswagen AG generates, sells and distributes or indirect interests in AUDI AG, SEAT S.A., Škoda Auto a.s., electricity as a group together with its subsidiaries.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "AUDI AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SEAT S.A.",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "h.c. F. Porsche AG, TRATON SE, Volkswagen Financial Services AG, Volkswagen Bank GmbH and a large number The Volkswagen AG Board of Management has sole responof other companies in Germany and abroad.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "F. Porsche AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Financial Services AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Bank GmbH",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen AG Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "More detailed dis- sibility for managing the Company.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Supervisory Board closures are contained in the list of shareholdings in accor- appoints, monitors and advises the Board of Management; it is dance with sections 285 and 313 of the German Commercial consulted directly on decisions of fundamental significance Code (Handelsgesetzbuch – HGB), which can be accessed on for the Company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "285",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "313",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "the website and is part of the annual financial statements.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Volkswagen AG Shareholder Structure Employees by Market as of December 31, 2023, in % of voting capital as of December 31, 2023, in % German institutional Porsche Automobil Europe (excluding investors 2.2 Holding SE 31.9 South America 5 Germany)/ other markets29 State of Lower Saxony11.8 North America 7 Qatar Holding LLC 10.0 Asia-Pacific 16 Foreign institutional investors 20.0 Germany 44 Private shareholders/ others24.1 Organizational Structure of the Group Commercial Vehicles brand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Shareholder",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "December 31",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "German",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Porsche Automobil Europe",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2.2",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "31.9",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "South America",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "markets29 State of Lower Saxony11.8 North America 7",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "10.0",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "16",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "20.0 Germany",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "44",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Activities focus on the development of vehicles, engines and vehicle software, the production The Volkswagen Group is one of the leading multi-brand groups and sale of passenger cars and light commercial vehicles, and in the automotive industry.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Group’s business activities the genuine parts business.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The product portfolio ranges comprise the Automotive and Financial Services divisions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Financial Services",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "from compact cars to luxury vehicles and also includes Our core brands within the Automotive Division – with the motorcycles and is supplemented by mobility solutions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "exception of the Volkswagen Passenger Cars and Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles brands – are independent legal entities.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Commercial Vehicles Business Area primarily comprises the development, production and sale of trucks and buses, The Automotive Division comprises the Passenger Cars, the corresponding genuine parts business and related services.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Commercial Vehicles Business Area",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Automotive Division",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Commercial Vehicles and Power Engineering business areas.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Commercial Vehicles",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Power Engineering",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The commercial vehicles portfolio ranges from light vans to heavy trucks and buses.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The collaboration between the The Passenger Cars Business Area primarily consolidates the commercial vehicle brands is coordinated within TRATON SE.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the The Passenger Cars Business Area",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Volkswagen Group’s passenger car brands and the Volkswagen\n\nTable of Contents",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity and Compliance | Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-6 The Financial Services Division’s activities comprise dealer divisions are also represented on the committees.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-6 The Financial Services Division",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "We are and customer financing, leasing, direct banking and insurance continually revising and optimizing these and other top activities, fleet management and mobility services.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "management committees in the Group in order to verify that they still align with our corporate strategy and to further inWith its brands, the Volkswagen Group is present in all of crease the efficiency of their decision making.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This reduces the markets around the world that are relevant for the Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "complexity and reinforces governance within the Group.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The key sales markets currently include Western Europe, China, the USA, Brazil, Türkiye, Mexico, Poland and the As part of the “Group Steering Model” base initiative from the Czech Republic.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Western Europe",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "USA",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Brazil",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Türkiye",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Mexico",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Poland",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the “Group Steering Model",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Czech Republic",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "NEW AUTO Group strategy, a new leadership model for the Group was presented at the Capital Markets Day in June 2023 Volkswagen AG and the Volkswagen Group are managed by that will sharpen the focus on customer orientation, entrethe Volkswagen AG Board of Management in accordance preneurship and team spirit.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Capital Markets Day",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "June 2023",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "It follows the “value over volume” with the Volkswagen AG Articles of Association and the principle, prioritizing sustainable value creation over volume rules of procedure for Volkswagen AG’s Board of Management growth.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen AG Articles of Association",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG’s",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "As part of this, the brand groups will receive a new issued by the Supervisory Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In addition, the brand positioning and the product range are to be sharpened.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The realignment also inAccordingly, responsibilities in the Board of Management cluded a renaming of the brand groups: Volume has become are currently divided among ten Board functions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ten",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In addition Core, Premium is now called Progressive, Sport & Luxury to the “Chair of the Board of Management” function the other has been changed to Sport Luxury, and Truck & Bus to Trucks.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Core, Premium",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Progressive, Sport & Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sport Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Truck & Bus to Trucks",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Board functions are “Technology”, “Finance and Operations” (formerly “Finance”), “Human Resources and Trucks brand The Core brand group comprises the Volkswagen Passenger group” (formerly “Human Resources and Truck & Bus”), “In- Cars, Škoda, SEAT/CUPRA and Volkswagen Commercial tegrity and Legal Affairs”, “Progressive brand group” (formerly Vehicles brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Finance and Operations",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Core",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Passenger",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Škoda",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Legal Affairs",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Vehicles",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Progressive brand group comprises the “Premium”), “Sport Luxury brand group” (formerly “Sport & Audi, Lamborghini, Bentley and Ducati brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Progressive",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sport Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sport & Audi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Lamborghini",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Bentley",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ducati",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Sport Luxury”), “IT”, “China”, and “Core brand group” (formerly Luxury brand group consists of the Porsche brand.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Sport Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "China",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Porsche",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The Chair of the Board of Management is also re- pany responsible for this brand, Dr. Ing.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ing",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "F. Porsche AG sponsible for the “Sport Luxury brand group” Board function.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "F. Porsche AG",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the “Sport Luxury",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "(Porsche AG), has been listed on the stock market since the end of September 2022.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Porsche AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the end of September 2022",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In the Trucks brand group, TRATON SE Directly attached to the Board are a number of Group Man- acts as the umbrella for the Scania, MAN, Volkswagen Truck & agement functions that act as an extension to the Board Bus and Navistar commercial vehicles brands.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Trucks",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Scania",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Truck &",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board Bus",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Navistar",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "TRATON SE functions.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "These comprise the “Group Sales”, “Group Pro- is also a listed company.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the “Group Sales",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "duction”, “Group Procurement” and “Group Research and Development” functions.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group Procurement",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "Group Research and Development",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In addition to the strengthening of the brand groups, the reorganization and expansion of new units also enabled The allocation of responsibilities on the Board of Management substantial progress to be made with the “Architecture”, is based on the rules of procedure decided by the Supervisory “Software”, “Battery, Charging & Energy”, and “Volkswagen Board.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory “Software",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Board",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The way this is structured helps the Board of Manage- Group Mobility” technology platforms in the reporting year.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Manage- Group Mobility",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the reporting year",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "ment to focus on key tasks such as strategy, central deci- The structures and product processes at the software sions on the Company’s direction, capital allocation and fi- subsidiary CARIAD will be optimized further.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "nancial requirements.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The task of the extended board-level management functions is to leverage synergies in the Group",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "We are convinced that our corporate structure, which effiand to connect the brands and divisions.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "ciently connects not only the brand groups but also the technology platforms, will enable us to make better use of Board of Management committees exist at Group level for the existing expertise and economies of scale, leverage synergies following areas: products, technologies, investments, digital more systematically and accelerate decision making.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Clear transformation, integrity and compliance, risk management, responsibilities and a high degree of business responsibility human resources and management issues.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In addition to the in the brand groups and technology platforms will enable responsible members of the Board of Management, the rele- comprehensive implementation of the Group’s NEW AUTO vant central departments and the relevant functions of the strategy.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Table of Contents The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity and Compliance | Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-6 Each brand within the Volkswagen Group is managed by a Legal Factors Influencing Business brand board of management, which is responsible for the brand’s independent and self-contained development and Like other international companies, the business of Volkswagen business operations.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-6",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "a Legal Factors Influencing Business",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "To the extent permitted by law, the companies is affected by numerous laws in Germany and board adheres to the Group targets and requirements laid abroad.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Germany",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In particular, there are legal requirements relating to down by the Board of Management of Volkswagen AG, as services, development, products, production and distribuwell as with the agreements in the brand groups.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management of Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This allows tion, as well as supervisory, data protection, financial, comGroup-wide interests to be pursued, while at the same time pany, commercial, capital market, anti-trust and tax regulasafeguarding and reinforcing each brand’s specific charac- tions and regulations relating to labor, banking, stateaid, teristics.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "comGroup",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Matters that are of importance to the Group as a energy, environmental and insurance law.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "whole are submitted to the Volkswagen AG Board of Management to be agreed upon, to the extent permitted by law.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Volkswagen AG Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The German Corporate Governance Code – A The rights and obligations of the statutory bodies of the Blueprint for Successful Corporate Governance relevant brand company thereby remain unaffected.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The German",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Blueprint for Successful Corporate Governance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Corporate governance provides the regulatory framework The Volkswagen Group companies are managed solely by for corporate management and supervision.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This includes a their respective managements.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The management of each in- company’s organization and values and the principles and dividual company takes into account not only the interests guidelines for its business policy.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The German Corporate of its own company but also the interests of the Group, the Governance Code (the Code) contains principles, recommenrelevant brand group and the individual brands in accordance dations and suggestions for corporate management and with the framework laid down by law.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The German Corporate",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Governance Code",
        "LAW"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Its principles, recommendations and suggestions were prepared by a dedicated government commission on Material Changes in Equity Investments the basis of the material provisions and nationally and internationally accepted standards of sound, responsible corpoIn May 2023, the Volkswagen Group completed the sale of its rate governance.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "May 2023",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "In the interests of best practice, the governshares in OOO Volkswagen Group Rus (Volkswagen Group Rus), ment commission regularly reviews the Code’s relevance in Kaluga/Russia and its local subsidiaries (OOO Volkswagen light of current developments and updates it as necessary.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group Rus",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Code",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Kaluga/Russia",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Components and Services, Kaluga/Russia, OOO Scania The Board of Management and the Supervisory Board of Leasing, Moscow/Russia, OOO Scania Finance, Moscow/ Volkswagen AG base their work on the principles, recomRussia, OOO Scania Insurance, Moscow/Russia) to OOO mendations and suggestions of the Code.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Kaluga/Russia",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Scania The Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board of Leasing",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Moscow",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Scania Finance",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Moscow/ Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "recomRussia",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Scania Insurance",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Moscow",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "We consider ART- FINANCE, Moscow/Russia, which is supported by the good corporate governance to be a key prerequisite for Russian automotive dealer AO Avilon Automotive Group, achieving a lasting increase in the Company’s value.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Moscow",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "AO Avilon Automotive Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Company",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "It helps Moscow/Russia.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Moscow",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "On registration of the transaction – also in strengthen the trust of our shareholders, customers, employMay 2023 – ownership of the shares in Volkswagen Group ees, business partners and investors in our work and enables Rus was transferred from the seller to the buyer.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "employMay 2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Group ees",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "The trans- us to meet the steadily increasing demand for information action includes the production facilities in Kaluga, the im- from national and international interest groups.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Kaluga",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "porter structure of the Group brands Volkswagen Passenger Cars, Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles, Audi, Škoda, Bentley, The Group Corporate Governance Declaration is available in Lamborghini and Ducati for potential after-sales business the Annual Report and is permanently accessible on our and the warehousing activities as well as Scania financial website.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Passenger Cars",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen Commercial Vehicles",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Audi",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Škoda",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Bentley",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "The Group Corporate Governance Declaration",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Lamborghini",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ducati",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Annual Report",
        "LAW"
      ],
      [
        "Scania",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "services activities with all associated employees.",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "www.volkswagen-group.com >",
    "entities": [],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Declaration of Conformity\n\nTable of Contents The Group’s DNA | Decarbonization | Circular Economy | People in the Transformation | Diversity | Integrity and Compliance | Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-6, 207-4 Further Information The Volkswagen AG Group Board of Management has adopted an update of the tax strategy principles, which has been Explanations of the composition, working methods and diver- published on Volkswagen AG’s website.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Decarbonization | Circular Economy",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Supply Chain and Human Rights GRI 2-6",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "207",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG Group Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG’s",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "sity concept of the Board of Management and the Supervisory Board and information on voting rights are available in the Each year, Volkswagen AG sends the German Federal Central Corporate Governance chapter in the 2023 Annual Report.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Board of Management",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Each year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Volkswagen AG",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the German Federal Central Corporate Governance",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "Tax Office a country-by-country report, which includes information on tax payments and tax expenses/income by country.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Tax Office",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "2023 Annual Report > Corporate Governance The Volkswagen Group has the ambition of implementing its Extensive explanations of the remuneration system and the marketing and communication activities transparently and individual remuneration of the members of the Board of responsibly.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "The Volkswagen Group",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Board of responsibly",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
    "sentence": "This includes attentiveness toward our environManagement and Supervisory Board can be found in the Re- ment and requires us to treat all individuals with respect and muneration Report for fiscal year 2023, which forms part of honesty and as equals.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Supervisory Board",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "fiscal year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "label": "unlabeled"
  },
  {
    "company": "Volkswagen",
    "year": 2023,
